<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_leave">The servant girl mysteriously disappeared. There were rumours that she had been sold as a bed slave to an Eastern dignitary… but no one knew for sure. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_leave">The man and his taint continued to befoul the soil and the people of his province starved. Those who survived talked openly of your failure to help them.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_leave">After a series of refusals the traveller decided to take the griffin bones on tour. He travelled with the caravans and made a good living from the fantastical remains of the mythical beast. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_leave">Like a petulant child, the magistrate refused to buy any additional slaves. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_leave">As time went by the reports of the chariot maker's skill began to vary. Those who visited the man personally praised his work, whereas those who sent underlings in their stead found his work merely passable.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_leave">The general was displeased with your refusal to act on his behalf. In the end he took matters into his own hands and killed the gosan, in a rather inventive style…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_leave">The magistrate insisted his fears were not baseless. The number of runaway slaves increased, and there were even reports of slaves attacking their masters!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_leave">Romans love to gossip; some other harlot will come along and distract them in no time. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_leave">The man returned to Carthage and took up his post as the captain of the Carthaginian trade fleet. He spoke favourably of his treatment at the hands of the Romans and continued to spread the word of your honesty and virtue for many years. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_leave">The old woman and her books disappeared and were never seen again.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_leave">The trade of Nisean horses continued much as it always had. There was nothing more that required your attention.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_leave">After having her plots revealed to the entire court the concubine was ostracized. There were rumours that she had attempted to recruit people to her cause, but she had lost what little influence she once had.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_leave">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_leave">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_leave">As the man fled south through the forests he was crushed to death by a falling tree! The gods had their revenge.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_6_Slaver_leave">The slaver was insulted by your refusal to honour him with your patronage but their was little he could do about it.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_leave">The woman came to plead her son's case time and time again. After a while your guards grew weary and refused her entry. She was forced to plead her case to your courtyard fountain.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_leave">The drought continued for a time but, eventually, the rains came and the earth became fertile once more.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_leave">The people of the tribe were never going to let such an affront to the gods go unpunished. The man's body was found, riddled with stab wounds: the blood debt had been paid.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_leave">The land soon returned to normal, the gods were simply testing the magistrate and his people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_leave">The general paid the ransom himself and his wife was returned to him. Not long after she gave birth to a strong, healthy son. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Silk_leave">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_leave">The seas stayed becalmed for a short while, but soon good winds resumed and all returned to normal.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_2_Wine_leave">The people were outraged by your failure to act. Many believed good wine was their right as citizens, and they were not happy that they were forced to import wine from other provinces.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_leave">The people continued in their selfish pursuit of pleasure. The gods watched in disgust and the priests did all they could to restore our people to the gods... but it was no use.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_leave">On this occasion the astronomers had misread the signs. There was no flood.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_leave">Like a petulant child, the magistrate refused to buy any additional slaves. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Wine_leave">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_leave">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_leave">The lanista revealed all his dark and dirty secrets, but no one of importance listened to his words.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_leave">Word of the awful crime spread and the mob vowed vengeance for the murdered boy. They dragged the man from his home in the dead of night and made him pay for his crimes, repeatedly.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_leave">Sadly this promising young man was thrown from his horse and killed. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_leave">The slave girl and her stories were put on display for all to hear. The people walked by and enjoyed the spectacle, but few stopped to listen to her words. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_2_debt_own_leave">He's dead. Probably his creditors…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_7_Miner_leave">Word of the deposit spread quickly and soon the hills were swarming with people hoping to exploit the rich ore deposit. Many had no mining experience and the hastily dug and poorly maintained shafts soon collapsed, killing all those inside.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_leave">The rumours continued but there were no tangible signs that the woman was plotting anything. Life at court continued much as it always had.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_leave">The scum soon started fighting among themselves, splitting into two factions. The fighting was bloody and both sides lost heavily, leaving none with enough strength to hold the ports. The grain supply into Rome restarted.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_leave">Our people continued to honour the gods and all was well.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_leave">Word soon reached the governor and he quickly divorced the woman, leaving her destitute.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_leave">A younger, prettier hetaira became available and the old one was soon forgotten. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_leave">The gods have more pressing concerns, this woman is of no concern to them or us.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_leave">When the child was born it looked nothing like its supposed father, exposing the woman's slanderous lies.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_leave">The women were put on trial for all to see. This seemed to please Aphrodite, though their families were less pleased.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_leave">If we have incurred the wrath of the gods, there is little we can do now…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_leave">When the man heard you were unwilling to see him he disappeared and was never seen again.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_leave">The girl continued her dalliance with this Greek but, as time went by, he grew tired of her and moved on to another wayward girl.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leave">The tribe continued to honour their leader with words and songs. They told and retold the stories of his great deeds. His memory lived on in the hearts of his people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_general_cloaka_maxima_leave">The general soon realised that his grand plan would prove expensive and changed his mind about sailing down the Cloca Maxima.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_leave">The warriors rode out and returned safely with their game.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_leave">It is unwise to ignore the wishes of the grieving mob. Denied the opportunity to publicly mourn their hero, the people took to the streets. Public buildings were damaged and fighting broke out across Rome.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_family_member_vicious_wife_1_leave">Proud of his strong and virtuous wife, her husband showered her with gifts and all the other women of the family were mad with jealousy.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_leave">As the prophetic chickens predicted all was well, and our people remained favoured by the gods. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_leave">When the older brother called for support no one came. The younger man was the tribe's choice and all stood by him.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_leave">The general kept the fawn, and he and his men cared for it until it grew into a magnificent white stag. They took the creature everywhere and good luck walked with it.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_leave">On meeting the man it was obvious that he was not a legendary leader sent by the gods. When the tribe heard the truth he became a figure of fun. The people fashioned a wooden crown for him to wear on feast days.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_leave">The astrologers predictions were correct! The years that followed the alignment were incredibly prosperous for you and your people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_leave">It was too late for the young man. He was involved with some very unsavoury characters who did not appreciate his lack of money. He was found dead in his own home. His family never discovered the killer or the reason for their son's murder.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_leave">The people soon grew bored with this particular story and moved on to one about the girl born with the ears and tail of a pig.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_flavour_leave">The boy returned to his mother's tribe and went on to become a fine young warrior.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_leave">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_wrecking_leave">The fisherman continued to lure ships on to the rocks, growing bolder with every passing day. When your failure to act was discovered, other leaders were outraged that you were unwilling to hunt out criminals…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_leave">Her grief soon got the better of the poor woman and she fell ill. She was bedridden for months but, when she was well again, the madness and her desire for revenge  had abated.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_leave">His enemies came looking for him and were not happy that we had offered him sanctuary, but there was little they could do.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_leave">It took time, but the land did recover and crops grew anew in the once-barren soil.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_leave">The father accepted his son's story and the matter was laid to rest.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_leave">The man took your decision to do nothing as permission to do as he liked. He killed his wife, restoring his honour. Nothing further was said of the incident.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_the_hunt_leave">A sudden storm blew through the forest where the Hunt had been heard. The trees were damaged but nothing more serious happened.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_family_member_1_blessed_leave">Sadly the boy was killed by his beloved pet eagle, perhaps he failed to please the gods.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_leave">Someone must have been mistaken. Perhaps… it was merely shadows they saw, for there have been no further signs of the gods' displeasure.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_leave">The magistrate insisted his fears were not baseless. The number of runaway slaves increased, and there were even reports of slaves attacking their masters!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_leave">The gladiator graced the sands for several more years, but the day came when an opponent was just a little quicker. He died a valiant death on the sands.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_leave">The two men fought and the magistrate was injured. He soon recovered from his wounds and he, and the young general, continued to serve you loyally.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_leave">As time went by, the reports of the metalsmith's skill varied. Those who visited the man in person praised his work; those who sent their servants in their stead found his work merely passable.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_leave">The merchant decided that he had too much to lose and so doubled his guard. The caravan made it safely through your lands and trade continued much as it always had.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_family_member_6_surgeon_leave">The man continued to pursue his grisly hobby and the pile of bodies soon became a mountain. He was eventually found dead in his villa, having turned his experimental knife on himself.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_leave">The Vestal was released but her body was found a day later. There were no signs of injury or visible wounds. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_witchcraft_leave">The drought continued and the people of the tribe talked openly about your failure to act in this matter. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_family_member_6_pirates_leave">On hearing of your refusal to discuss terms for the boy's safe return the pirates decided that he held no value. He was never seen again.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_leave">After ignoring the dream a terrible sickness came to your lands. People died by the hundred, and the land itself became infected with the evil taint of the sickness.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_leave">A petulant child rather than a grown man, the magistrate refused to buy any additional slaves. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_leave">The beautiful woman remained at court for a short time but, when it became obvious that you were indifferent to her charms, she boarded a ship and returned to her homeland.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_religions_1_Dodona_leave">Nothing happened, as expected. We are the gods' faithful, so why would they punish us?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Spices_leave">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_leave">The magistrate continued to bleat on about his fears but nothing ever came of them.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_leave">Nothing happened. It seems the gods are satisfied.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_leave">People continued to flock to the province to see the dolphin and costs to entertain them continued to rise.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_leave">After couple of weeks the man disappeared, no doubt moving on to pastures new.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_leave">The madman wandered off of his own accord.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_leave">A successor was sent to replace the dead man, much to the annoyance of the widow. She assumed her lover would be given the position.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_leave">The child grew and it was obvious that the astrologers had been right: bad luck followed wherever he went and people feared to be near him.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_leave">The old man continued to forge his weapons but his reputation waxed and waned. Those who visited the man sang his praises but those who sent others found their purchased weapons were merely passable. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_leave">The Gaul continued to create exquisite work. But one night he slipped his chains and slit his master's throat before escaping.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_leave">A silent night and a concealed blade were the last thing this monster knew…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_5_Librarian_leave">Afraid of the power he sensed in the scrolls the librarian burned them. He claimed that he could hear them whispering to him late at night, telling him of a power that could be his. The man never really recovered from his discovery with these mysterious scrolls.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_leave">The boy returned to his mother's family and went on to become a fine young general.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_death_leave">The sentence was carried out and the man's vast wealth went to his family.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_leave">The High Priestess introduced her tax, prompting a great deal of grumbling from the people. However, as the voice of the gods on earth she was safe from reprisals. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_cult_1_leave">As expected, the gods exacted their revenge on the cultists. Their leader was struck down with a strange affliction that covered his body with painful red welts. Within days the entire cult had succumbed. A few days more and the gods took them all…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_leave">The general was angered by your lack of support and took a small group of warriors to steal his wife back. Much blood was shed, but the general did manage to retrieve his wife.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_1_Goldsmith_leave">The Gaul continued to create exquisite work. But one night he slipped his chains, and slit his master's throat, before escaping.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_leave">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_1_leave">Sadly the boy was gored by his beloved pet boar. Perhaps he failed to please the gods.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_roman_family_member_5_Child_mars_leave">Your daughter continued her decent into debauchery, and her exploits were the favoured topic of gossips for years to come.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_leave">Chalcon soon tired of your lack of hospitality and moved on to find a more hospitable host.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Nisean_leave">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_leave">The hag was never seen again and the gods allowed the people to continue on as normal. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_messages_optional_text_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_leave">The general continued to care for the fawn and it grew in to a mighty white stag. One day, the general and all his men simply disappeared. There were rumours that they had followed the stag into the Otherworld, where they would be honoured as champions for all eternity.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>