<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_pontic_chapter1_bonus_1_flavour">The leader of the Galatians. A frequent guest in your court, he seeks to secure agreement with Pontus.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_flavour">A merchant from the distant south brought incense and spices.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_flavour">Your astrologers warn that a child, recently born into your family, came into the world under baleful stars. This child's ill luck cannot be allowed to seep into the rest of the family.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_flavour">A young member of a rival family has found himself in serious debt. Perhaps we can use this to our advantage…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_family_member_5_Child_mars_flavour">Your daughter is with child. She swears she has never known the touch of a man and believes that the child is a gift from Mars, the god of war.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_chapther1_bonus2">Quintus Fabius Maximus Gurges</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_flavour">The astronomers warn of ill omens in the stars, omens that foretell of a terrible flood.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_flavour">A young boy baring an uncanny resemblance to a member of your family has appeared. He claims to be his son by the daughter of another tribal leader.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_wrecking_flavour">A local fisherman has been luring ships on to the rocks near his home and profiting from the wrecks.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_carthaginian_generic_priestess_flavour">Priestess of Kore. She begs the judges to remember what happened when our troops desecrated the temple of Kore in Sicily. We should build a suitable home for her.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_flavour">A member of your family is having an affair, with her Greek physician! Ohh the shame!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_flavour">A traveller from distant lands has appeared offering to sell you the bones of a griffin. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_historical_text_flavour_evolve_cicero_1">Desperate, angry, and frustrated, Cicero takes his crusade against you to new heights.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_1_Goldsmith_flavour">Word has reached us of a Gallic slave whose skills as a goldsmith are fast becoming legend.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_5_Librarian_flavour">Deep in an abandoned vault, a librarian has found a set of ancient scrolls, containing long forgotten knowledge.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_chapther1_bonus2_flavour">Quintus Fabius Maximus Gurges, son of Rullianus, a legendary general who fought and subdued the Etruscans. Beloved by Roman soldiers and citizens alike, he strongly opposes the idea of good relations with the treacherous Etruscans.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_flavour">Following the death of our beloved leader his youngest son was chosen to replace him. His oldest son is not happy about this and is threatening to rally men to his cause.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_flavour">Your general's wife has been kidnapped by the enemy. They have sent a note implying that they will trade the woman for gold and other treasures.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_flavour">A Roman soldier has been found looting offerings from our sacred lake! What should be done with him?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_flavour">On of your magistrates informs us that his lands are barren, the harvest has failed and the farmers worry the same will happen again next year if nothing is done.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_historical_name_cicero">Marcus Tullius Cicero</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_flavour">A member of your family has come to plead with you to reinstate her son. The boy disgraced himself and was banished from court, but his mother claims that he has learnt the error of his ways. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_flavour">Our lands are racked with drought, we must do something to appease the gods.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_flavour">A young boy in this province has befriended a dolphin. So great is their bond that the creature has allowed the boy to saddle it. The spectacle has drawn visitors from far and wide and the cost of entertaining them is taking its toll on the province's finances.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_flavour">In order to pay for the upkeep of the god's temples, the High Priestess intends to introduce a temple-tax.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_flavour">The pregnant wife of one of your generals has been captured by the enemy. They are offering to return her to her husband, for a price.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_flavour">In the depths of a forest an old blacksmith forges the finest spearheads and swords the world has ever seen. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_dummy">[DO NOT LOCALISE]</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_flavour">A metal smith is making rhyton of surpassing beauty, his skill is praised far and wide and only the rich and influential can hope to afford one of his pieces.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_pontic_chapter1_bonus_1">Lonnorius</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_flavour">A horse trader from Nisea, has arrived. He claims to be selling the best horses in the known world!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_flavour">A lame man cured in Epidaurus is walking the streets, rejoicing. The people are abandoning their homes and jobs to follow him on a pilgrimage to honour the gods.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_2_Wine_flavour">One of your magistrates is complaining about the deterioration in the quality of wine in his province. He claims he wouldn't expect barbarians to drink such swill.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_flavour">A guardian has poisoned his ward in order to inherit his lands. How would you like to punish him?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_flavour">Our Thracian slave girl has been captured by a political opponent. She has been a trusted member of our household for many years and knows everything about our family. These people will use this information to ruin us. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_makedonian_generic_envoy_flavour">All hail Great King Amtikini! Priya-darshi, Beloved of the Gods, and King of the Maurya wishes us to teach you the Path of Awakening.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_flavour">A chariot maker has opened a forge and if the rumours are true his work could rival that of the Smith!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_flavour">Birds have been seen flying in the senate! This is the worst possible omen, the gods are furious!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_parthian_chapter1_bonus2_flavour">Envoy from Andragoras. He demands that you reconcile with Seleucus, the rightful heir of Alexander. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_parthian_chapter1_bonus1_flavour">Envoy from Diodotus of Baktria. He seeks a strategic alliance against the usurper Seleucus.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_flavour">On of your magistrates is claiming his lands are barren, the harvest has failed and the farmers worry the same will happen again next year if nothing is done.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_flavour">A dust stained and travel worn stranger is seeking an audience with you. He claims to have knowledge of the whereabouts of a Djinn.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_egyptian_generic_scribe_flavour">Your faithful scribe presents his ledgers. It seems there are some anomalies in the yearly records; local magistrates are taking money for themselves and forging the records.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_flavour">This servant may prove invaluable in undermining the credibility of a rival family. She has been overheard discussing family secrets in the market, of all places.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_flavour">A trusted haruspey has come to us with troubling news. Whilst examining the innards of a boar it was found that the beast had no heart! The gods are displeased!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_egyptian_chapter1_bonus3_flavour">Theoxena, niece of Magas. Magas, our beloved half-brother, has betrayed us and now calls himself King of Cyrenaica.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_generic_senator_flavour_2">Ah, the dubious senator. We should have seen this coming. He tries to blackmail and work against us.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_generic_senator_flavour_3">Ah, our good friend. The co-operation  is fruitful to both of us.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_flavour">Our people are rejecting the old ways! They have become lustful and hedonistic, thinking only of life's pleasures and failing to give the gods the respect they deserve. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_flavour">A beautiful young woman has arrived at court, she is a gift from a foreign ruler seeking to gain your favour.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_flavour">There are rumours that a sacred sword has been pulled from its stone. The people whisper of a leader whose coming was foretold.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_flavour">The keeper of the auspice chickens informs us that the birds have eaten hearty, a sure sign that we are favoured by the gods!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_flavour">A member of your family has been unfaithful with one of her husband's shield-bearers. The man is furious and calls for the right to take his wife's life.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_flavour">One of your archons is concerned about the high number of slaves in his province, he thinks this might be dangerous.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_egyptian_chapter1_bonus3">Theoxena</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_flavour">A Vestal virgin has been found guilty of sexual misconduct. Her lover has already been flogged to death but what should be done with her?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_flavour">One of your magistrates is complaining about the lack of slaves in his province. He feels that more slaves would help to improve the productivity of his lands. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_flavour">A young boy baring an uncanny resemblance to a member of your family has appeared. He claims to be his son by the daughter of another patrician family.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_flavour">A merchant from distant lands has arrived, bringing silk with him.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_flavour">The leader of a vanquished tribe has arrived in your lands seeking protection from his enemies.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_flavour">A strange old woman has appeared offering to sell you nine books of prophecies. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_witchcraft_flavour">A woman in your family stands accused of witchcraft! Her recent arrival coincided with the arrival of famine and the people are looking for someone to blame.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_flavour">There are rumours at court that a favoured concubine is attempting to place her son on the throne. News of this intrigue has reached us from her fellow concubines, who were more than happy to have reveal her plans.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_death_flavour">A man has come to you begging you to over turn his death sentence handed down by an archon. He claims his crime does not warrant such a harsh sentence.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_flavour">If the rumours are to be believed, the head of an enemy warrior taken in battle has started talking to its owner. It repeatedly foretells of the doom of our people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_family_member_6_pirates_flavour">A member of your family has been captured by pirates! The brigands are offering to return the boy, in exchange for a substantial ransom.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_flavour">One of your governors has been found dead. All signs point towards poisoning, how should we proceed?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_general_cloaka_maxima_flavour">One of your generals is proposing to sail down the Cloca Maxima to display its impressive size to the people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_family_member_1_blessed_flavour">A distant member of the family is said to have a pet eagle. The bird came to the boy and perched on his right shoulder, a sure sign of greatness!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_flavour">One of your generals has a pet fawn, the creature is milk-white and follows him around like a loyal dog.  He claims it is a gift from the gods and whispers their secrets to him.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_flavour">Scorpus, the legendary charioteer, has been killed during a race. The people are heartbroken and are calling for this great man to be honoured.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_carthaginian_chapter1_bonus3_flavour">Philinus of Agrimentum. A learned man and historian.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_flavour">A member of your family is seeking vengeance for the murder of her husband. She is requesting your permission to hire a man to track her husband's murderer and bring him to justice.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_flavour">This magistrate is complaining because of the low number of slaves.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_flavour">Word is spreading that the wife of a governor has taken a slave for a lover! She flaunts the relationship in Rome while her husband toils in his province.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_flavour">Your general has taken a pet fawn, the creature is milk-white and follows him around like a loyal dog.  He claims the creature is a gift from Diana.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_flavour">A Carthaginian captain has been captured. One of your own captains was attempting to follow him but the Carthaginian ran his ship aground, causing his pursue to do the same. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_makedonian_chapter_1_bonus2_flavour">"Aristippus of Argos: 

My dearest king, Antigonus. Aristeas tries to deprive me of my rights in Argos and conspires with our mutual enemy Pyrrhus."</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_flavour">A concubine has been found guilty of plotting to kill your wife. The mad woman thought you would chose her to be your new wife. How would you like to proceed?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_flavour">A priestess has arrived from Bura. The dice of the Oracle have foretold good fortune for our people!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_flavour">A gosan has written a mocking poem about one of your generals. The man is outraged and is demand that something be done to repair the damage to his honour.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_flavour">A Lanista hoping to gain favour has performed a number of unsavoury tasks for a member of your family. The man is now attempting to blackmail him.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_makedonian_chapter_1_bonus2">Aristippus of Argos</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_flavour">A member of your family has been murdered by his own brother. The man is insisting that he had no choice, his brother chopped down a sacred tree and used it for firewood! </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_family_member_6_surgeon_flavour">A member of your family has been dabbling in surgery. The pile of bodies is becoming difficult to hide, what would you like to do?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_flavour">Your daughters indiscretions are the talk of Rome. Her behaviour is discussed in hushed whispers by all the women of standing and even the slaves know of her exploits!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Silk_flavour">A merchant from distant lands has arrived, he wishes to trade his strange shiny material with our people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_flavour">A group of warriors prepare to ride out for the hunt, we should make offerings for their safe return and the success of their venture.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_flavour">This man was once a slave, but as a slave driver he is cruel and heartless. His lack of compassion and the regular beatings are making the slaves rebellious.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_flavour">A gang has taken control of the ports in Rome and is attempting to monopolise the city's grain supply.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_surgeon_flavour">A Greek surgeon is gathering support for his heretical views</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_flavour">Word has reached us of a Gallic slave whose skills as a goldsmith are fast becoming legend.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_carthaginian_chapter1_bonus3">Philinus of Argimentum</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_flavour">A member of your family is concerned about a reoccurring dream she has been having. In her dream, a dark cloud descended on your lands and engulfs your people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Wine_flavour">A Greek trader has come to the tribe offering to trade the sweet wine they make in their homelands.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_generic_senator_flavour">A well-connected senator could help us to increase the popularity of our family. At a cost...</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_flavour">One of your magistrates has fallen prey to the evil eye. His bad luck is seeping into the soil of his lands and the people go hungry.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_flavour">Following the death of our mighty leader we must decide how best to honour his memory.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_historical_text_flavour_spawn_cicero">This senator opposes your authority in the Senate. His charismatic speeches undermine the popularity of your entire family.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_7_Miner_flavour">A miner has come across a rich deposit of ore in the hills not far from one of your mines.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_flavour">A distant member of the family is said to have a pet boar. The creature came to him during a hunt and bowed its head before him. It is said that the huge beast follows the boy everywhere.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_flavour">A merchant from distant lands has arrived in our lands. He has brought a strange new dye that creates a rich colour our people have never seen before.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Dodona_flavour">A traveller from Dodona brings word of ill omens from the Oracle. As the news spreads people begin to panic, fearing the wrath of the gods.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_flavour">A priestess from Dodona brings happy tidings! The rustling of the oak leaves have told her much and more of the future fortunes of our people. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_flavour">One of your magistrates is complaining about the number of slaves in his province. He fears they may soon outnumber his citizens and the gods only know what madness that may lead too.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Spices_flavour">A merchant from the distant south wishes to trade his incense and spices with our people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_flavour">This gladiator is known throughout the Roman territories, his prowess legendary.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_the_hunt_flavour">There are rumours that 'the hunt' has been heard, the people fear the wrath of the gods and look to you to appease them.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_flavour">A merchant from the east wishes to trade with our people. He has a regular supply of the strange material known as silk, a rare and sought after commodity. </string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_flavour">A hag has been spotted rising from the mists of a stream, the local people fear she may be a sign from the gods, a sign of terrible misfortune.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_flavour">Your astrologers have fantastic news! The stars are coming into an alignment that will bring great prosperity to you and your people.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Nisean_flavour">A trader from distant lands has come to our shores, he claims to be selling the finest horses known to man!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_flavour">A trader has come to you seeking additional protection for his caravan. Bandits have been targeting the trade routes around your lands and he fears an attack.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_flavour">A beggar priest has arrived from Delphoi. He speaks in riddles, uses divinations on the street and babbles of ill omens from the oracle. His words troubles the people…</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_6_Slaver_flavour">Slavers have arrived in your ports with a shipment of high quality slaves. But which of them catches your eye?</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_family_member_4_Vicious_words_flavour">One of our family members has been apprehend outside the Senate. She attacked a Senator who had spoken ill of her husband, stabbing him through the tongue with her hairpin.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_flavour">A distant member of the family shows signs of greatness. Despite his age it is said that the boy is a natural leader.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_pontic_generic_shaman_flavour">Your Agari. One of the famous Scythian shamans, he has much to teach you about poisons and immunity to them.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_flavour">The seas have been becalmed for quite sometime, if we are to trade and send warships against our enemies we must make an offering to Poseidon to regain his favour.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_flavour">The wife of one of your magistrates is claiming that a young general forced himself upon her. Her husband has come to you seeking your permission to kill the young man.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_flavour">A beautiful young hetaira has been stoned to death by local women, jealous of her beauty and talent.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_flavour">This woman is with child, she claims the father is a man of your blood and talks of it openly in the streets. A bastard from a hetaira can ruin a man's reputation.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_flavour">Phryne was seen dancing naked in the streets during a festival dedicated to Poseidon. This disgraceful act offends Poseidon and Athena!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_flavour">This hetaira has been the companion of your general for some time but now she  rejects his advances. The man is humiliating himself in his attempts to win her back.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_flavour">One of your archons is complaining about the lack of slaves in his province. Public works taken an age and some men don't even have bed slaves!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_flavour">One of your governors is complaining about the high number of slaves in his province. He fears they may soon outnumber true Romans and the gods only know what madness that may lead too.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_flavour">A member of your family has been caught hunting sacred hares. The people of the tribe are demanding blood!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_flavour">After hearing the riddle of Pythia of Delphoi, Chalcon and his wife have decided to pay you a visit.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_roman_cult_1_flavour">Members of a strange new cult have been caught desecrating a temple of the gods!</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_flavour">The horses of Nisea are the finest in the world. Your traders make an excellent living selling them to foreigners, yet, the more they sell the less prestigious these once fabled beasts become.</string>
<string name="campaign_subject_strings_string_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_2_debt_own_flavour">A member of our family has run up considerable debts. His actions have brought disgrace down upon him and our whole family.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>