<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_plague_starts">Pestilence grips the men. Its origins are unknown but it has spread throughout the ranks. Survivors work to collect the dead, and funeral pyres burn day and night... And the sickness spreads. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_D">The Horses from Across the Sea</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_A">The Horses from Across the Sea</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_C">The Horses from Across the Sea</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_B">The Horses from Across the Sea</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_1_i_B">The Dolphin Rider</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_1_i_C">The Dolphin Rider</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_1_i_A">The Dolphin Rider</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_greco_roman_description_of_greece">Description of Greece</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_followup_i_A">The woman was confined and died shortly. Some mutter that it was grief that killed her. Her son refused to fight for the person responsible for destroying his entire family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_followup_i_B">Thankful for your mercy. The woman's son offered his service in place of his father, and proved to be a promising general. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_claudia">Despite barbarian marauders stealing the hoard, nasty rumours speak of the Claudii having taken done it. Their influence with the people and the Senate has diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_i_A">Groups of angry citizens appeared at your door demanding to know who was going to pay them full value for the slaves they had lost.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_i_B">The executions calmed the mind of the magistrate, but set a fire in hearts of the remaining slaves. They were outraged that men and women had been put to death on the whim of one man.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_i_C">The magistrate insisted his fears were not baseless. The number of runaway slaves increased, and there were even reports of slaves attacking their masters!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_B">The offerings were made and the people waited to see if the gods approved of these strange foreign gifts. The gods were pleased, and blessed our people with good weather and a bountiful harvest.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_C">These new and exotic items brought traders from far and wide to our lands and trade flourished.  </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_A">People travelled from miles around to purchase incense and spices. As the only local source for these exotic items the tribe's wealth soared.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_D">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_earthquake">Earthquake</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_greco_roman_description_of_asia">Description of Asia</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_D">Nothing happened. It seems the gods are satisfied.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_B">We have given thanks to the gods and all is well.  </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_C">The cow was afflicted by gadfly! We have angered the Queen of the Gods!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_A">The celebrations lasted long into the night and both gods and men were pleased. People did not rush to their work next morning…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_bones_i_B">The Bones of Monsters</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_bones_i_C">The Bones of Monsters</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_bones_i_A">The Bones of Monsters</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_not_faction_leader_oracle_impress">The Oracle of Zeus Ammon</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_i_A">Tyrian Purple</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_i_C">Tyrian Purple</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_i_B">Tyrian Purple</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_i_A">The celebrations lasted long into the night. People with woozy heads struggled to return to their work the next morning!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_i_B">The offerings were made and the people rejoiced. As the astrologers promised, the following years saw bumper harvests and your people prospered.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_i_C">The astrologers predictions were correct! The years that followed the alignment were incredibly prosperous for you and your people.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_4_Vicious_words_i_A">After being publicly chastised she apologised, but that was not the end of it. Patrician women rallied to the woman's cause and openly mocked your family for what they saw as an act of cowardice.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_4_Vicious_words_i_B">Following your praise of the lady for a wanton act of violence, the Senate and the other patrician families began to think twice before crossing you and yours.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_4_Vicious_words_i_C">Proud of his strong and virtuous wife, her husband showered her with gifts and all the other women of the family were mad with jealousy.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_A">Bad Omen</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_C">Bad Omen</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_B">Bad Omen</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_D">Bad Omen</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_D">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_A">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_B">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_C">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_i_A">Displeased with her fat old husband your daughter quickly returned to her old ways, shaming both you and her new husband.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_i_C">Romans love to gossip; some other harlot will come along and distract them in no time. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_i_B">The gods welcomed her with open arms and gifted her with 'the sight.' Her visions are heard and respected by all Romans.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_3_faction_leader_loss_influence">Word of the kings' all-too-clear mortal status has reached the people. Some now openly say that he is no Alexander; others question his right to rule.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_A">The Slaver</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_B">The Slaver</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_C">The Slaver</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_D">The Slaver</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_i_B">The rich new colour produced by the merchant's dye became popular with the nobles of the tribe. Before long it was a symbol of importance, fetching higher prices than any other goods. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_i_C">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_5_tyrian_purple_i_A">The new colour was beautiful to behold and the people of the tribe looked in envy.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_plague_starts_foreign">Troubling news: informants speak of a plague gripping this foreign army. Contact should be avoided.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_C">They came in the dead of the night. The woman and her child were never seen again…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_B">The woman took the money and returned to her homeland. True to her word, both she and her brat were never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_A">The boy was adopted and raised by your family. As he grew it became more and more obvious that the woman had been truthful: the child was truly of your blood.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_D">The woman withdrew from court life to raise her child. As he grew the boy favoured his father. The people were in no doubt as to his lineage.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_i_C">Bandits</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_i_B">Bandits</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_i_A">Bandits</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_D">Nothing happened, as expected. We are the gods' faithful, so why would they punish us?</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_C">The gods are pleased by our noble sacrifice. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_B">The sky darkens and lightning rips the clouds. Our meagre sacrifice has angered the mighty gods.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_A">After being manhandled from the city the traveller cursed everyone. So? We have nothing to fear from a madman.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_D">The boys behaviour became too much for some members of your family to stomach. He disappeared from one of his haunts of depravity and was never heard from again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_C">The boy continued to shame the family with his acts of debauchery. His mother doted on him and convinced herself that he was now a good boy, but the rest of the family knew better and questioned your judgement.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_B">The boy was put to death and his mother wept for his loss. Afterwards, other young members of your family became strangely well behaved. The fate of the boy served as a lesson in poor conduct. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_followup_i_A">The boy returned to his home in exile and soon resumed his life of foul debauchery. His mother was mortified and never spoke her son's name again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_julia_appropriated_accusation">Somehow, somwhere, someone talked, and the the Julii's part in the disappearance of the gold of Tolosa is now known. Their influence with the people and the Senate is now greatly diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_junia_appropriated_accusation">Somehow, somwhere, someone talked, and the the Junii's part in the disappearance of the gold of Tolosa is now known. Their influence with the people and the Senate is now greatly diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_greco_roman_description_of_greece">Volumes describing the sights and customs of Hellas have emerged. These offer much to those who dream of travel in foreign lands.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_3_faction_leader_gain_influence">His new-minted divinity has helped the king's influence to grow. The people are inspired!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_i_A">Careless Sons</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_i_B">Careless Sons</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_i_C">Careless Sons</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_i_A">Deadly Rumours</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_i_B">Deadly Rumours</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_i_C">Deadly Rumours</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_7_Miner_i_B">Word of the deposit spread quickly and soon the hills were swarming with people hoping to exploit the rich ore deposit. Many had no mining experience and the hastily dug and poorly maintained shafts soon collapsed, killing all those inside.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_7_Miner_i_A">The expansion of the mines was costly but the new ore more than paid for the work. Miners claimed they had never seen anything like it and the further they dug, the more they found. This was surely a gift from the gods!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_i_A">The man was killed cleanly and laid to rest with all the honour due one in his position. Within days of his death the rains finally came and the crops grew once more.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_i_B">The magistrate was banished from his province. The land recovered and the people rejoiced. However, the lands where he walked soon fell victim to his taint, and their inhabitants were outraged that you had knowingly sent forth an accursed man.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_i_C">The man and his taint continued to befoul the soil and the people of his province starved. Those who survived talked openly of your failure to help them.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_snowstorm">Snow Storms</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_hannonid_appropriated">The attack on the convoy is complete. No one survived to speak of the gold of Tolosa ogoing to the Hannonid family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_i_A">Following her punishment the concubine left the court for a time. Shortly after, your wife was found dead in the gardens of your home, poisoned.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_i_C">After having her plots revealed to the entire court the concubine was ostracized. There were rumours that she had attempted to recruit people to her cause, but she had lost what little influence she once had.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_i_B">The woman was publically put to death. The number of plots and schemes in your court apparently decreased dramatically.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_followup_i_B">The pirates, angered by your refusal to pay, decided the boy was more trouble than he was worth. He was never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_followup_i_A">The fool boy was released and swaggered back into his family home boasting of the huge sum that had been paid to secure his release. After being properly chastised by his father he remembered his place and has brought no further trouble to the family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_i_C">The child grew and it was obvious that the astrologers had been right: bad luck followed wherever he went and people feared to be near him.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_i_B">After receiving your generous gift the astrologers re-examined the signs. They found that the planets had moved shortly before the child's birth, so he had not been born under the influence of baleful stars! Amazing!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_i_A">The baby and its mother were sent away and the people breathed a sigh of relief. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_bandit_stolen">Curses! A band of merciless raiders has taken everything and left none alive! Could the Volcae's curse be true?</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_greco_roman_description_of_egypt">Description of Egypt</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_i_B">The woman was put back on a ship and returned to her masters. Your refusal to accept their generous gift was taken as an insult and relations between you suffered. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_i_C">The beautiful woman remained at court for a short time but, when it became obvious that you were indifferent to her charms, she boarded a ship and returned to her homeland.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_i_A">The woman was beautiful and charming. Her masters were pleased that you had accepted her as a gift, as were all the men of your  court.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_hannonid">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_i_C">Mad as a March Hare</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_i_B">Mad as a March Hare</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_i_A">Mad as a March Hare</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_D">Ill Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_A">Ill Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_B">Ill Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_1_Oracle_i_C">Ill Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_followup_i_A">The women took their punishment and all was peaceful, for a time. They soon returned to their plots and intrigues. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_followup_i_C">The concubines continued to plot and scheme but, ultimately, they had no power and their plots were of little consequence.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_followup_i_B">Following the public execution of the poisonous schemers life at court became peaceful. The plotting came to an end as all knew you were not to be crossed.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_A">The Gift of Beauty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_A">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_B">The Gift of Beauty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_B">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_C">The Gift of Beauty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_C">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_followup_i_D">The Gift of Beauty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_D">Blood is Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_i_C">The boy trained tirelessly and studied under some of the greatest minds of the age. As he grew it became obvious that he would go on to achieve great things.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_i_B">The boy became a well respected priest, and the gods were thankful to our family for sending such a fine boy to the temple.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_i_A">For once the rumours were true. The boy sat a horse better than men twice his age and his swordsmanship was beautiful to behold. The family were proud to have him as one of their own.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_7_Miner_i_A">All that Glitters...</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_7_Miner_i_B">All that Glitters...</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_i_C">The seas stayed becalmed for a short while, but soon good winds resumed and all returned to normal.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_i_B">The winds returned in an instant and trade flourished once more. The child's mother has yet to recover, but her sacrifice was for the greater good.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_i_A">Poseidon was unmoved by your sacrifice. The seas remained flat calm and our trade suffered as a result.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_D">Fallen Vestal </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_B">Fallen Vestal </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_C">Fallen Vestal </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_A">Fallen Vestal </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_i_C">The two men fought and the magistrate was injured. He soon recovered from his wounds and he, and the young general, continued to serve you loyally.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_i_B">On further investigation it was found that the woman had tried to seduce the young general and been spurned. Upon learning the truth, her husband cast her out and apologised all concerned.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_i_A">The young man continued to profess his innocence right up until the moment of his death.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_D">Word of the awful crime spread and the mob vowed vengeance for the murdered boy. They dragged the man from his home in the dead of night and made him pay for his crimes, repeatedly.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_A">When his sentence was read out the man broke down and insisted that it was not right for a citizen of Rome to suffer the same fate as slaves and foreigners.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_C">The people were outraged that you allowed a crime of this magnitude go unpunished. Some took to the streets to denounce you and others whispered in the shadows. In the end, the mob left you a grisly message and justice was done.  </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_B">Crowds gathered to watch the murderer receive his just punishment. The cheer as he was hurled from the Tarpeian Rock was deafening.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_A">The Greek Affair</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_C">The Greek Affair</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_B">The Greek Affair</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_D">The Greek Affair</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_plague_starts_region_foreign">There is talk of a pestillence gripping nearby lands. Beware the spread of disease.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_C">She took the money and will never darkened our door again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_B">The payment was enough to see that the child and its mother were never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_A">The hetaira took the small fortune offered her and was never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_B">Athena is a proud goddess! She has been angered by your support of this harlot.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_C">Word soon spread of the woman's disappearance and it didn't take long for blame to land at our door, a stain on the family name.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_B">The woman was kidnapped and sold into slavery. News of her fate soon spread and people whispered that you were not to be crossed. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_A">Following the trial Phryne became an outcast. No self-respecting man would pay for her services and her own kind shunned her.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_C">The fool refuses to see the error of his ways and insists that she is the only woman for him.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_A">The bastard is born and bares an uncanny resemblance to his father. The integrity of our house is openly mocked by all.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_D">The woman soon attached herself to another, more powerful man, forcing the general to admit defeat.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_i_A">The women were put on trial for all to see. This seemed to please Aphrodite, though their families were less pleased.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_D">When the child was born it looked nothing like its supposed father, exposing the woman's slanderous lies.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_i_C">Aphrodite was outraged by your failure to act on behalf of the hetaira. A woman given beauty by the goddess should have been protected. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_D">The gods have more pressing concerns, this woman is of no concern to them or us.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_i_B">Aphrodite was pleased with your offerings. She decided not to punish you for your failure to protect the hetaira.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_i_A">A Promising Youth</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_i_B">A Promising Youth</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_3_promising_i_C">A Promising Youth</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_D">Oaken Whispers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_A">Oaken Whispers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_C">Oaken Whispers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_2_Dodona_i_B">Oaken Whispers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_i_A">A Heavy Price</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_i_B">A Heavy Price</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_i_C">A Heavy Price</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_earthquake">No one is safe from the vengeance of the gods. The ground trembles, buildings crumble and the dead litter the ground, crushed beneath the rubble. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_A">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_C">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_B">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_1_Spices_i_D">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_i_C">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_i_B">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_4_plenty_slaves_i_A">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_i_A">The Wife of the Magistrate</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_i_B">The Wife of the Magistrate</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_5_bad_wife_i_C">The Wife of the Magistrate</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_followup_i_B">A Heavy Price</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_4_Agamemnon_followup_i_A">A Heavy Price</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_caught_out_disrespect">Tomb Robbers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_D">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_B">The offspring of the magnificent stallions were the most impressive animals anyone had ever seen: strong, swift and beautiful.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_C">The arrival of this trader drew others to our lands and trade flourished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_2_Nisean_i_A">The horses were given to our finest warriors. They were in awe of the beasts. The rumour quickly spread that they were a blessed gift from the horse goddess, and the men treated them with the utmost respect.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_C">Lost Love</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_A">A Question of Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_B">Lost Love</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_A">Wrath of Athena</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_A">Lost Love</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_B">Wrath of Athena</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_C">A Question of Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_C">Wrath of Athena</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_B">A Question of Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_2_i_D">Wrath of Athena</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_i_B">Wrath of Aphrodite</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_3_i_D">A Question of Blood</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_i_C">Wrath of Aphrodite</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_1_i_D">Lost Love</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_hetaira_4_i_A">Wrath of Aphrodite</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_i_C">The Price of Loyalty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_i_B">The Price of Loyalty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_i_A">The Price of Loyalty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_sandstorm">Sand Storms</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_i_A">The Gift of Beauty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_i_C">The Gift of Beauty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_1_foreign_beauty_i_B">The Gift of Beauty</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_i_A">The gods demanded a slow death. The man was strangled, hit on the head, had his throat cut and was finally thrown into a bog. As his body sank below the surface a hare appeared, a sure sign that the gods had seen the sacrifice and were well satisfied with it.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_i_B">Punishment was not enough for the gods. Blood was what they expected. They showed their distain for your feeble efforts by sending torrential rains that destroyed crops and homes.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_7_hares_i_C">The people of the tribe were never going to let such an affront to the gods go unpunished. The man's body was found, riddled with stab wounds: the blood debt had been paid.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_C">The Egyptian quickly became the favourite of the thinkers in the family and the warriors favoured the Scythian. Both men had much to teach us and were happy to share their knowledge with their new masters. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_B">The Scythian proved to be a wise investment. He had much to teach the family about horsemanship, and the right way to raise and train horses.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_A">The Egyptian proved to be a wise investment. He was a great success at feasts, where he would recite poetry and plays in several languages for the amusement of the guests.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_profession_6_Slaver_i_D">The slaver was insulted by your refusal to honour him with your patronage but their was little he could do about it.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_magonid">Rumours has it that the Gold of Tolosa was not taken by bandits. It is supposedly now the property of Magonids! These foul rumours diminished our influence in the council. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_followup_i_B">Deadly Rumours</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_followup_i_C">Deadly Rumours</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_followup_i_A">Deadly Rumours</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_bandit_stolen">Jupiter's curses on our enemies! A band of raiders has plundered everything and killed everyone. Is the Volcae's curse coming to pass?</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_i_C">Good Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_i_B">Good Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_3_star_prosperity_i_A">Good Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_plague_starts_region">No one knows where the plague came from but it does not matter now. The dead are countless and it continues to spread. Those who survive live in dread, and the local economy has been devastated.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_D">Valuable Information</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_A">Valuable Information</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_B">Valuable Information</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_C">Valuable Information</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_D">Chalcon soon tired of your lack of hospitality and moved on to find a more hospitable host.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_C">Angered by your refusal to see him, Chalcon spread Pythia's prophesy far and wide. Seven years of famine are to come and the people blame your failure to heed prophesy!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_B">Pleased by your willingness to hear his words, Chalcon happily recounted to the people that Pythia had foretold rich years to come.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_A">After a long, exhausting audience it was revealed that the couple had nothing of import to report to you. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_D">The general kept the fawn, and he and his men cared for it until it grew into a magnificent white stag. They took the creature everywhere and good luck walked with it.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_C">The gods welcomed your sacrifice and honoured your lands with a glorious summer. However, the general and his men were saddened by the loss of their beloved mascot and mourned for some time. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_B">The general and his men were pleased that you were willing to honour their beloved mascot, and the gods were happy that their gift was appreciated.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_A">The men who fought under the general were angered by your decision. They believed in the powers of the fawn and respected their general.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_D">Our people continued to honour the gods and all was well.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_A">The celebrations lasted long into the night. Gods and men were pleased. Sore heads and aching limbs prevented many from returning to their work the next day! </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_B">The gods are pleased with our gifts, and continue to honour us with their favour. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_C">The goat had scabies! The Queen of the Gods was angered by our failure to honour her with a proper sacrifice.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_julia_appropriated">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_junia_appropriated">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_seastorm">Sea Storms</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_3_not_faction_leader_loss_influence">The Oracle of Zeus Ammon</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_civ_gold_tolosa_3_returned">After a long and dangerous journey, the Tolosa hoard has arrived in the capital. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_i_A">The Value of Silence</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_i_C">The Value of Silence</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_i_B">The Value of Silence</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_i_A">Groups of angry citizens appeared at your door demanding to know who was going to pay them full value for the slaves they had lost.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_i_C">The magistrate insisted his fears were not baseless. The number of runaway slaves increased, and there were even reports of slaves attacking their masters!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_i_B">The executions calmed the mind of the magistrate, but set a fire in hearts of the remaining slaves. They were outraged that men and women had been put to death on the whim of one man.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_bar_gold_tolosa_3_returned">The Volcae hoard has arrived safely in our homeland! Our people rejoice!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_barcid_appropriated">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_i_B">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_i_C">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_i_A">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_i_C">Word soon reached the governor and he quickly divorced the woman, leaving her destitute.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_i_B">The woman wept for the loss of her lover and the slaves grew more rebellious than ever. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_i_A">The people of Rome love a good scandal! As the woman was dragged through the streets, many gathered to enjoy the spectacle.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_i_B">The Smith Reborn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_i_C">The Smith Reborn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_i_A">The Smith Reborn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_i_B">Your man returned with the rhyton from the metalsmith, but it was no more impressive than any other in your collection.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_i_C">As time went by, the reports of the metalsmith's skill varied. Those who visited the man in person praised his work; those who sent their servants in their stead found his work merely passable.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_i_A">The metalsmith was honoured by your patronage and presented you with a gold rhyton in the likeness of a winged lion. The beast had ruby eyes and the metalwork was beyond compare.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_C">The gods welcomed your sacrifice, but the general and his men were saddened by the loss of their beloved mascot and mourned for some time. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_B">The general and his men were pleased that you were willing to honour their beloved mascot, and the gods were happy that their gift was appreciated.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_A">The men who fought under the general were angered by your decision. They believed in the powers of the fawn and respected their general.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_D">The general continued to care for the fawn and it grew in to a mighty white stag. One day, the general and all his men simply disappeared. There were rumours that they had followed the stag into the Otherworld, where they would be honoured as champions for all eternity.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_returned">The Gold of Tolosa has arrived safely, and is in the capital's strongrooms</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_followup_i_B">No Shame!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_followup_i_C">No Shame!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_followup_i_A">No Shame!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_plague_spreads_army">Rumours of sickness among the soldiers have gone unheeded. The plague has spread to the people. The death toll rises. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_B">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_C">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_A">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_D">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_popular_respect">Tomb Robbers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_i_A">Brotherly love</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_i_B">Brotherly love</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_i_C">Brotherly love</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_faction_leader_oracle_impress">The Oracle speaks! Our great ruler is divine and has been shown his path! </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_i_C">A petulant child rather than a grown man, the magistrate refused to buy any additional slaves. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_i_B">Under the lash, the slaves worked much harder and the local economy was boosted. However, it was only a matter of time until the unhappiness of the slaves boiled over into rebellion. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_i_A">The magistrate was pleased that you took the time to hear his request and were gracious enough to act upon it. He put the slaves to good use and the province prospered.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_i_A">The slaves were unwilling to talk at first, but they revealed that another man had been in the villa the night of their master's death. It might be wise to question him as well.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_i_A">The magistrate was pleased that you took the time to hear his request and were gracious enough to act upon it. He put the slaves to good use and the province prospered. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_i_C">A successor was sent to replace the dead man, much to the annoyance of the widow. She assumed her lover would be given the position.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_i_C">Like a petulant child, the magistrate refused to buy any additional slaves. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_i_B">The woman denied everything, but quickly suggested that her lover may be suitable for the recently vacated position of governor.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_3_Lack_slaves_i_B">Under the lash the slaves worked much harder and the local economy was boosted, but it was only a matter of time until the unhappiness of the slaves boiled over into rebellion.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_A">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_B">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_C">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_creature_1_white_faun_i_D">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_i_B">At first the people accused you of failing to properly honour the legendary charioteer. When the statue was revealed they were overjoyed!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_i_C">It is unwise to ignore the wishes of the grieving mob. Denied the opportunity to publicly mourn their hero, the people took to the streets. Public buildings were damaged and fighting broke out across Rome.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_i_A">The streets were packed with people wanting to honour the passing of Scorpus. His funeral pyre grew so large that there was a danger to nearby buildings. One grieving fan even threw himself onto the pyre! </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_popular_respect">The people speak of these investigations with approval and respect. Egyptians appreciate the work of Ptolemaic administration to preserve their land's heritage.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_magonid_appropriated">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_hellenic_resistance_to_hegemony">Hellas Hegemony</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_B">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_C">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_A">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_D">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_D">His captors questioned him a little too vigourously and the Captain never returned to Carthage.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_C">The man returned to Carthage and took up his post as the captain of the Carthaginian trade fleet. He spoke favourably of his treatment at the hands of the Romans and continued to spread the word of your honesty and virtue for many years. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_B">Despite days of torture the man refused to give up his secrets. Left alone, he managed to escape and find a ship back to Carthage. When news of his treatment became known the rulers of Carthage were outraged.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_Captain_i_A">The Carthaginian was surprisingly willing to share his secrets. He supplied information on a number of valuable trade routes and was granted his freedom in return. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_B">The Oracle foretold years of plenty for our people! The man is a liar.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_C">He quickly gets confused and contradicts himself. The people enjoy the spectacle and soon forget his silly talk of ill omens.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_A">It would seem that the beggar-priest is not mad after all. The Oracle spoke of freedom for all living things. Now the slaves are restless…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_D">The madman wandered off of his own accord.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_i_A">The Greek Affair</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_i_B">The Greek Affair</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_i_C">The Greek Affair</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_julia_appropriated">The attack on the convoy worked: the gold of Tolosa now rests in Julii coffers.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_junia_appropriated">The attack on the convoy worked: the gold of Tolosa now rests in Junii coffers.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_plague_spreads_army_foreign">Word has arrived from this nearby land. A deadly plague carried by sick troops is taking its toll on the local populace.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_faction_leader_oracle_disappoint">The high priest is indifferent to our king's requests for an audience. He simply states that the Oracle will not utter words the King wishes to hear.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_C">Romans love to gossip; some other harlot will come along and distract them in no time. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_B">Your daughter was never seen again. The gossips soon found another topic and life continued.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_A">The gods welcomed her with open arms and gifted her with 'the sight.' Her visions are heard and respected by all Romans.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_D">Your daughter was found murdered. It is impossible to trace the murderer, but it may well have been her husband.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_carthage_merchants_got_here_first">Pioneer Traders</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_i_A">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_i_C">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_i_B">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_general_1_cloca_maxima_i_C">The general soon realised that his grand plan would prove expensive and changed his mind about sailing down the Cloca Maxima.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_i_A">The Mystery of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_i_B">The Mystery of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_i_C">The Mystery of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_i_A">"The men you sent to kill the lanista were slain by his gladiators. Angered by your attempt to kill him, the lanista revealed all that he had done ""in your family's name""."</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_i_C">The lanista revealed all his dark and dirty secrets, but no one of importance listened to his words.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_i_B">The lanista took the money, although he was aggrieved that we were unwilling to offer him position because of his low birth.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_i_A">Parched Earth</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_i_B">Parched Earth</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_i_C">Parched Earth</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_A">The improved soil gave a bumper harvest the following year. The farmers praised your quick response to their concerns.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_B">Improving the land's irrigation systems helped greatly with the quality of the soil. The farmers brought in a bumper harvest that year. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_C">The magi consulted the stars and informed you that the rains would return soon enough. True to their predictions, the rains fell, the sun shone, and the farmers had a bumper harvest that year.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_D">It took time, but the land did recover and crops grew anew in the once-barren soil.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_i_A">After the offering was made the hag was seen next morning. The skies split with rain that lasted for days; rivers burst their banks and crops and homes were washed away. The gods and goddesses of the rivers were angered by our failure to honour them.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_5_cult_i_C">Cultists</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_5_cult_i_B">Cultists</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_i_C">The hag was never seen again and the gods allowed the people to continue on as normal. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_5_cult_i_A">Cultists</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_i_B">The offerings were cast into the stream and the people waited to see if the gods would drive the hag from the stream. She was never seen again and the people thanked the gods for delivering them from misfortune.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_all_gold_tolosa_2_find_not">Tolosa has been searched. There is no trace of the fabled treasure. Was it just a legend, or has someone else taken the Volcae hoard?</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_B">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_C">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_A">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_D">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_D">The scum soon started fighting among themselves, splitting into two factions. The fighting was bloody and both sides lost heavily, leaving none with enough strength to hold the ports. The grain supply into Rome restarted.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_A">The men seized the gang's stockpiled grain and drove them out. However, within a couple of days the gang was back, and the grain supply faltered again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_B">The man might have been more brutal than his predecessors but he was also clever: he took the money, and his gang left Rome the next day.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_C">The fires burnt for days and port buildings were damaged, but the gangs were driven out once and for all.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_D">The gladiator graced the sands for several more years, but the day came when an opponent was just a little quicker. He died a valiant death on the sands.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_A">The gladiator was presented with a rudius in front of a huge crowd. The people cheered and the slaves were given new hope that one day they might earn their freedom.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_C">As the gladiator hacked down the champions in every province he visited, his renown grew. The people awaited his arrival eagerly and cheered his name… and yours.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_B">Angered by his continued enslavement the gladiator broke free from his ludus, killed his lanista and freed all his fellow gladiators. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_A">The gods were pleased by your gift of the foreigner and his shiny clothes.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_C">The foreigner and his strange items brought new traders to our markets and with them came their ideas. Life continued much as normal, but some aspects of these strangers' ways were adopted by your people.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_B">The item may have been soft to the touch and a joy to wear, but your people frowned upon your decision to adopt it. No real warrior should be seen dead in such effeminate garb!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_D">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_i_B">The Poisoner's Art</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_i_C">The Poisoner's Art</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_i_A">The Poisoner's Art</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_5_Child_mars_i_A">The child was born and it quickly became obvious that he was no ordinary boy. Like the mighty Hercules, there was something special about him. He was a born leader of men. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_i_A">Poisoned Words</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_5_Child_mars_i_C">Your daughter continued her decent into debauchery, and her exploits were the favoured topic of gossips for years to come.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_i_C">Poisoned Words</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_5_Child_mars_i_B">Your daughter was spirited away and had the child in secret. It was adopted by a farmer and his wife. A small token of your appreciation brought their silence and no word of your daughter's folly ever reached Rome.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_i_B">Poisoned Words</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_all_trade_disruption">Despite repressive measures unrest is getting out of hand. Unless authority stamps on these people local trade revenue and production will be affected. Rebellion will follow.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_general_cloaka_maxima_i_A">As the general sailed down the Cloca Maxima people packed the banks, cheering and waving. The spectacle may have been costly but you cannot put a price on the benefit of a happy Roman mob. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_general_cloaka_maxima_i_B">"Angered by your refusal to back his plans, the general chose to fund the spectacle himself. The people gathered to watch and word quickly spread that you had refused to be a part of this great event. The people called you ""miser"" and praised the general for his generosity."</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_i_C">The Sacred Sword</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_i_B">The Sacred Sword</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_i_A">The Sacred Sword</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_i_B">Following the demotion of the slave driver the slaves' morale rose significantly and all thoughts of rebellion were put aside.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_i_C">The man continued to brutalise his charges and the slaves continued to hate him, but life continued as always…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_i_A">The man continued to work the slaves hard, so hard that some lost their lives through his lash. Those that survived talked of rebellion and the merciful end of their tormentor. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_returned">The gold of Tolosa has arrived Rome and has been put in the Senate's coffers.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_C">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_B">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_A">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_7_the_hunt_i_A">Once the sacrifices had been made the wind changed suddenly: great gusts blew through the forests, taking the Hunt with them.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_7_the_hunt_i_C">A sudden storm blew through the forest where the Hunt had been heard. The trees were damaged but nothing more serious happened.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_7_the_hunt_i_B">An offering of a bow and an arrow were made. The people listened for the telltale sounds of the Hunt. No such noises were heard and the people rejoiced.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_faction_leader_oracle_disappoint">The Oracle of Zeus Ammon</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_i_C">The girl continued her dalliance with this Greek but, as time went by, he grew tired of her and moved on to another wayward girl.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_i_B">The girl was sent far away and forbidden to make contact with her Greek lover. Her behaviour was a popular subject for gossip for some time, but she never shamed the family again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_i_A">Following her punishment, the girl pretended to have learned her lesson. But only for a time: it was obvious that she had understood nothing.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_1_i_A">Blessed by the gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_1_i_B">Blessed by the gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_1_i_C">Blessed by the gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_D">The tribe's trade continued much as it had before the arrival of the trader. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_C">The arrival of this trader drew others to our lands and trade flourished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_B">The gods were pleased with the gift of wine and blessed our people with their favours.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_A">"The wine's popularity brought people from far and wide to taste it. As demand for this ""nectar of the gods"" grew the tribe's wealth grew also."</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_i_A">Looters!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_i_C">Looters!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_i_B">Looters!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_i_A">The Shield-bearer</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_i_C">The Shield-bearer</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_i_B">The Shield-bearer</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_i_A">The warriors returned from the hunt telling tales of giant beasts. The tribe dismissed them as stories until the carcasses were displayed for all to see. These creatures were surely gifts from the gods!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_i_C">The warriors rode out and returned safely with their game.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_i_B">When the warriors returned from the hunt they were laiden down with game. The forests were filled with deer, boar and more! Every shot found its mark!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_followup_i_B">People were prevented from entering or leaving your lands until the magi said otherwise. Months passed and, when there was no sign of the illness, the magi allowed travellers and traders to come and go as they pleased.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_followup_i_C">Days passed and there was still no sign of the terrible illness. The magi met again to discuss the dream and decided that it had not been truly prophetic after all.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_followup_i_A">The offerings were made, but something was wrong. A traveller was taken ill  and soon all around him were struck down. Within weeks, half the population had been infected, and the spread of disease showed no sign of stopping.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_A">The men seized the gang's stockpiled grain and drove them out. However, within a couple of days the gang was back, and the grain supply faltered again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_C">Killing the leaders had an unfortunate side effect. Another man, more brutal and ambitious than the last, took control of the gang.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_B">The creatures took the money and cleared their men from the ports.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_1_i_D">The scum soon started fighting among themselves, splitting into two factions. The fighting was bloody and both sides lost heavily, leaving none with enough strength to hold the ports. The grain supply into Rome restarted.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_i_A">Younger Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_i_B">Younger Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_i_C">Younger Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_followup_i_A">The Poisoner's Art</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_followup_i_B">The Poisoner's Art</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_followup_i_C">The Poisoner's Art</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_lost">Far from home, in unknown lands, they have lost their way. A minor setback, perhaps, but a setback.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_A">The rich and powerful sent their agents to purchase bolt after bolt of silk. As the only source of this luxury item your profits soared.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_8_surgeon_i_A">The man was spirited out of the city to one of the family's villas. Guarded day and night, and with fewer potential victims around, his excesses were curbed.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_B">The silk attracted merchants from far and wide and trade flourished. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_8_surgeon_i_B">The man was dragged into the streets and his crimes were laid bare. Those who had lost slaves and even family members to his knife called for justice. It was quickly decided that he should be thrown from the Tarpeian Rock.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_trade_1_Silk_C">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_8_surgeon_i_C">The man continued to pursue his grisly hobby and the pile of bodies soon became a mountain. He was eventually found dead in his villa, having turned his experimental knife on himself.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_claudia_appropriated">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_roman_triumph_2">Triumph</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_roman_triumph_3">Triumph</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_roman_triumph_1">Triumph</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_subject_roman_generic_senator_i_B">Subject murdered!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_subject_roman_generic_senator_i_A">Subject murdered!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_D">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_A">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_B">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_creature_white_faun_1_i_C">The Pale Fawn</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_D">Talking Heads</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_B">Talking Heads</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_C">Talking Heads</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_A">Talking Heads</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_hannonid_appropriated_accusation">Word of our involvement in the theft of the Gold of Tolosa is spreading. Faith in our family wanes and our influence in council is diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_carthage_merchants_got_here_first">It is always a pleasant surprise when taking a place far from home to discover that Carthaginian merchants have a long-established and profitable presence.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_general_1_cloca_maxima_i_C">A Filthy Spectacle</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_fire">A great fire has broken out, devouring all in its path. Nothing can stop the flames and many have lost their lives. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_i_C">The father accepted his son's story and the matter was laid to rest.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_i_B">The man was telling the truth: he had killed his brother in the name of the gods. They were happy to see their champion honoured by his people.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_1_brotherly_love_i_A">The man was telling the truth: he had killed his brother in the name of the gods and their rage was terrifying to behold. The sky blackened, the winds rose and the rains lashed down in a seemingly endless torrent.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_followup_i_C">Word of the awful crime spread and the mob vowed vengeance for the murdered boy. They dragged the man from his home in the dead of night and made him pay for his crimes, repeatedly.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_followup_i_B">Crowds gathered to watch the murderer receive his just punishment. The cheer as he was hurled from the Tarpeian Rock was deafening.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_followup_i_A">The man was crucified but, to appease his fears of being mistaken for a foreigner or slave, his cross was painted white and placed higher than the others.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellennic_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_C">The Golden Gaul</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellennic_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_B">The Golden Gaul</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellennic_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_A">The Golden Gaul</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_i_B">The Hidden Forge</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_i_C">The Hidden Forge</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_i_A">The Hidden Forge</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_5_cult_i_A">The cultists were crucified outside the temple they had attempted to destroy. People gathered to pelt them with stones and rotten food and their deaths were slow and painful. Such was the will of the gods!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_5_cult_i_B">The cultists were entombed and left to the mercy of the gods. Those who went into the tomb to retrieve the bodies refused to speak of the horrors they saw. They would take the grisly memories to their graves…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_5_cult_i_C">As expected, the gods exacted their revenge on the cultists. Their leader was struck down with a strange affliction that covered his body with painful red welts. Within days the entire cult had succumbed. A few days more and the gods took them all…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_i_B">Grasping Lanista</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_i_C">Grasping Lanista</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_2_Lanista_i_A">Grasping Lanista</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_followup_i_A">The Mystery of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_followup_i_B">The Mystery of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_D">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_C">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_B">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_trade_aventine_gang_followup_i_A">Trouble on the Aventine</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_i_A">The Rython</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_i_C">The Rython</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_2_rhyton_i_B">The Rython</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_D">The Remembrance</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_A">The Remembrance</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_C">The Remembrance</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_B">The Remembrance</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_i_B">The general was pleased with your willingness to come to his defence. He sang your praises to his men and the members of the court.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_5_Child_mars_i_B">Child of Mars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_i_C">The general was displeased with your refusal to act on his behalf. In the end he took matters into his own hands and killed the gosan, in a rather inventive style…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_5_Child_mars_i_C">Child of Mars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_gosan_i_A">The gosan was publically flogged and told that never to recite the offending poem again. The general was pleased but felt that the gosan should have paid with his life for insulting his honour.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_5_Child_mars_i_A">Child of Mars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_barcid_appropriated">The attack on the convoy is complete. No one survived to speak of the gold of Tolosa ogoing to the Barcid family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_hannonid_appropriated_accusation">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_not_faction_leader_oracle_disappoint">The Oracle of Zeus Ammon</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_piracy">The seas are too vast even for the mightiest of navies to control. Piracy has escalated: commerce suffers as a result.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_profession_5_Librarian_i_A">Forbidden Knowledge</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_profession_5_Librarian_i_B">Forbidden Knowledge</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_profession_5_Librarian_i_C">Forbidden Knowledge</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_roman_triumph_1">This man has shown unfaltering devotion to Rome. He is a true Roman hero. We honour him and celebrate his glorious victories.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_roman_triumph_2">This man has shown unfaltering devotion to Rome. He is a true Roman hero. We honour him and celebrate his glorious victories.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_roman_triumph_3">This man has shown unfaltering devotion to Rome. He is a true Roman hero. We honour him and celebrate his glorious victories.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_claudia_appropriated">The attack on the convoy worked: the gold of Tolosa now rests in Claudii coffers.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_lost">Lost their Way</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_A">The Golden Gaul</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_B">The Golden Gaul</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_C">The Golden Gaul</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_i_B">Death of a Legend</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_i_C">Death of a Legend</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_4_Charioteer_i_A">Death of a Legend</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_roman_urban_migration">People leave the country for the city, seduced by the dream of a better life. There has been a drastic decline in farming, and the cities fill up with unemployed men. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_followup_i_B">When pushed harder on the matter the woman gave up one of her slaves as the murderer, claiming that her husband had used the woman badly. The slave had killed him as an act of vengeance. All of the household slaves were put to death, in accordance with Roman law.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_followup_i_C">A successor was sent to replace the dead man, much to the annoyance of the widow. She assumed her lover would be given the position.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_legate_1_Poisoner_followup_i_A">The man was quick to admit to his relationship with the governor's wife, and even quicker to blame her for the husband's death. The woman was put on trial and sentenced to death for the murder of her husband.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_plague_spreads">There were rumours of a terrible disease. Unheeded, it is now too late and the sickness has spread to the troops.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_D">The tribe continued to honour their leader with words and songs. They told and retold the stories of his great deeds. His memory lived on in the hearts of his people.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_C">Our leader was laid to rest in all his finery and with his weapons in his hands. The sight of his burial mound reminded the people of the strength of the tribe and the importance of honouring the dead. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_B">As his weapons were cast into the waters the clouds parted and sunlight shimmered on their surface. The gods welcomed our leader to their halls, as a brother and an equal. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_4_dead_leader_i_A">The tribe gathered together and feasted. For a day and a night the forest rang with singing and the sounds of drunken revelry. Despite the sore heads and aching limbs that followed, the people were happy to have honoured their dead lord.  </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_wrecking_i_B">The income gained from the wrecking continued to improve as the fisherman set his sights on bigger and bigger prizes. However, as more and more ships disappeared, foreign powers started asking questions and your involvement was revealed.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_i_B">Long Lost Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_wrecking_i_C">The fisherman continued to lure ships on to the rocks, growing bolder with every passing day. When your failure to act was discovered, other leaders were outraged that you were unwilling to hunt out criminals…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_i_C">Long Lost Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_wrecking_i_A">The man was a thief and was punished accordingly. With him gone, trade income improved and foreign ships once again felt safe in our waters.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_D">Child of Ill-repute</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_i_A">Long Lost Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_C">Child of Ill-repute</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_B">Child of Ill-repute</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_followup_i_A">Child of Ill-repute</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_i_B">As fewer Nisean stallions travelled west, the Nisean bloodline became weaker elsewhere. Once again your horses and cavalry became the envy of the world!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_i_C">The trade of Nisean horses continued much as it always had. There was nothing more that required your attention.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_i_A">The money from these impressive beasts continued to flow into your lands. However, as the Nisean bloodline thinned people no longer feared your cavalry. The legendary quality of the Nisean horses passed into memory.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_D">There must have been some misunderstanding! Although the beast had no heart there were no further signs that the gods were displeased.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_A">The second beast had no heart! The skies cracked with lightning, rain poured down for days, and the people were terrified.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_B">A single bull was not enough to restore us in the sight of gods. The people were angered by your meagre sacrifice.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_C">The gods were incredibly pleased with your sacrifice and the people honoured you as a true champion of the gods!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_D">Our failure to rein in the people angered the gods! Our lands were beset by drought and the people suffered.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_C">The people continued in their selfish pursuit of pleasure. The gods watched in disgust and the priests did all they could to restore our people to the gods... but it was no use.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_B">The people have continued with their shameful ways and the gods look down in disgust. The priests felt that only drastic measures could restore our wayward people to the loving arms of the gods.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_A">The people have renounced their lives of selfish pleasure and returned to the loving arms of the gods.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_D">The Stranger</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_B">The Stranger</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_i_A">Honoured by your visit, the blacksmith presented you with a set of fine weapons. The craftsmanship was unmatched and the blades were stronger than anything anyone had ever known.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_C">The Stranger</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_i_B">The old blacksmith sold your servant an impressive set of weapons, but they were not the finest in the world. As time went by, men who visited the blacksmith in person sang his praises, but those who sent others in their stead found they were disappointed with his work.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_2_Blacksmith_i_C">The old man continued to forge his weapons but his reputation waxed and waned. Those who visited the man sang his praises but those who sent others found their purchased weapons were merely passable. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_A">The Stranger</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellennic_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_A">Free to make items of his choosing his work improved tenfold and attracted buyers from all over the world.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellennic_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_C">The Gaul continued to create exquisite work. But one night he slipped his chains, and slit his master's throat, before escaping.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellennic_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_B">The slave's skill was without equal. His forge drew buyers from all over the world and the income gained from his work swelled our coffers.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_i_C">The man's body was found in the river. His creditors had taken his life as a final payment.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_i_B">No longer carrying the family name the man tried any means open to him to pay his debts. A life of debauchery soon took its toll and he was found face down in the river…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_magonid_appropriated_accusation">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_plague_spreads_foreign">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_i_A">The girl was snatched from the market and taken to a private place where she had a quiet conversation with a man and a sharp blade. She became very talkative, and the information gained from her was enough to ruin our rivals' reputations forever.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_i_C">The servant girl mysteriously disappeared. There were rumours that she had been sold as a bed slave to an Eastern dignitary… but no one knew for sure. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_1_secrets_i_B">The girl rightly pointed out that money was no use to her. Her masters would only wonder how she came by it and assume the worst. She could not be convinced to give up her secrets.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_D">Legend of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_C">Legend of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_B">Legend of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_3_Gladiator_i_A">Legend of the Sands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_i_A">The Nisean Legend</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_i_C">The Nisean Legend</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_trade_2_Nisean_i_B">The Nisean Legend</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_all_gold_tolosa_2_find_not">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_D">A Beast with no Heart</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_i_B">As the fire burned low the ashes were spread across our lands. That year, the harvest was plentiful and the people thanked the gods.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_C">A Beast with no Heart</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_i_C">The drought continued for a time but, eventually, the rains came and the earth became fertile once more.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_B">A Beast with no Heart</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_1_haruspay_i_A">A Beast with no Heart</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_3_drought_i_A">The blood of the mare soaked deep into the earth and, that year, the harvest was plentiful and the people thanked the gods.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_i_C">From the Mists</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_i_B">From the Mists</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_4_hag_i_A">From the Mists</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_B">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_C">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_A">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_5_Barren_land_i_D">Barren Lands</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_i_B">The stranger led you deep in to the desert and revealed that he was the djinn. As you had been willing to take the journey with him, he pledged to serve you until your dying day.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_i_C">When the man heard you were unwilling to see him he disappeared and was never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_i_A">The stranger led you deep in to the desert and revealed that he was the djinn. As you had been willing to take the journey with him, he pledged to serve you until your dying day.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_claudia_appropriated_accusation">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_roman_merchants_got_here_first">Roman merchants's ingenuity is without bounds. Even in this distant land they already have a profitable foothold.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_A">Favoured by the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_B">Favoured by the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_C">Favoured by the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_7_Bura_i_D">Favoured by the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_plague_spreads_foreign">Informants and travellers bring troubling news: disease has spread to this foreign army. Avoid contact at all costs.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_i_B">The tribe was pleased that you stood by their decision. Ridding them of the vain pretender was an added bonus.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_i_C">When the older brother called for support no one came. The younger man was the tribe's choice and all stood by him.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_2_younger_son_i_A">The boy's arrogance had no limits. No amount of talk could make him see that his younger brother was the tribe's rightful leader. He rallied a few young, headstrong warriors to his banner, and attempted to frighten others into joining his cause.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_followup_i_A">In the Dark of the Night</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_followup_i_B">In the Dark of the Night</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_followup_i_C">In the Dark of the Night</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_bribes_i_B">As the sentence was carried out the assembled crowd voiced a deafening cheer. The man had made many enemies, gathering his wealth at the expense of others. All were thrilled that he had finally received a fitting reward for his wickedness.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_bribes_i_C">The sentence was carried out and the man's vast wealth went to his family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_bribes_i_A">When the sentenced was overturned the crowd that had gathered to witness his end were outraged. He had to be spirited away to safety, but he paid you well for your help and for his life.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_D">The land soon returned to normal, the gods were simply testing the magistrate and his people.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_B">Improving the lands irrigation systems improved the quality of the soil and the farmers brought in a bumper harvest that year. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_C">The gods heard our prayers! The rains fell and the sun shone and the farmers had a bumper harvest that year. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_1_Barren_land_i_A">The improved soil provided a bumper harvest the following year and the farmers praised your quick response to their concerns.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_i_C">As the man fled south through the forests he was crushed to death by a falling tree! The gods had their revenge.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_i_B">The skies split and the rains fell, the gods were furious. Sickened by your cowardly lack of action they sent floods that destroyed crops and claimed the lives of many of your loyal people.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_1_looters_i_A">The looter was offered to the gods and the fire could be seen for miles around. Word reached Rome and their response left tribal leaders speechless. The Romans sent gifts: the man was a deserter and they thought he had escaped justice, so they were pleased by the manner of his passing.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_profession_5_Librarian_i_C">Afraid of the power he sensed in the scrolls the librarian burned them. He claimed that he could hear them whispering to him late at night, telling him of a power that could be his. The man never really recovered from his discovery with these mysterious scrolls.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_profession_5_Librarian_i_B">Only a few days after the discovery of the scrolls fires broke out around the abandoned vault. The librarian was found wandering in singed robes, speaking in a strange tongue. He claimed that the gods had told him that mortal eyes should ever look upon the scrolls and that he must destroy them. The fires spread, causing untold amounts of damage. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_profession_5_Librarian_i_A">The librarian returned the scrolls to their vault and had the whole place sealed up, with him inside. No one knew what madness gripped the man but some claimed they could hear his laughter coming from the vault in the dead of night…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_piracy">Rampant Piracy</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_1_i_B">The gods were pleased with the boy and he did well in training. Respected and loved by all, men came from miles around to hear his wisdom and see his fabled beast.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_1_i_C">Left to his own devices the boy became a great warrior and he, and his boar, became the stuff of legend.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_gaul_family_member_blessed_by_the_gods_1_i_A">The boy showed great promise. His skill-at-arms was unmatched and he even trained the boar to attack his enemies.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_i_C">The Horned Governor</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_i_B">The Horned Governor</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_2_Horned_i_A">The Horned Governor</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_C">The Gaul continued to create exquisite work. But one night he slipped his chains and slit his master's throat before escaping.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_B">The slave's skill was without equal. His forge drew buyers from all over the world and the income gained from his work swelled our coffers.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_1_Goldsmith_i_A">Free to make items of his choosing his work improved tenfold and attracted buyers from all over the world.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_i_B">The chariotmaker sold your man a handful of well-made chariots, but there was nothing particularly special about them.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_i_C">As time went by the reports of the chariot maker's skill began to vary. Those who visited the man personally praised his work, whereas those who sent underlings in their stead found his work merely passable.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_profession_1_chariot_i_A">Honoured by your visit the chariotmaker presented you with a gift: a chariot of unsurpassed beauty. Inlaid with precious stones and worked with gold, it was a gift worthy of the gods.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_returned">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_plague_spreads">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_followup_i_A">The body lay where it fell and was never found. The gods clearly approved of this man's death.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_followup_i_B">The woman and her husband were pleased with the trophy. However, when it was found that the man had been killed during an exchange, his people were less than pleased.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_roman_urban_migration">Urban Migration</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_followup_i_C">The woman had killed the man cleanly and, by rights, his head should have been hers to keep. Her husband and his men did not look kindly on this slight.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_subject_roman_generic_senator_i_B">At the end he was no-one. And no-one mourned him.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_subject_roman_generic_senator_i_A">The murder tracked back to us and cause quite an uproar in the senate.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_magonid_appropriated">The attack on the convoy is complete. No one survived to speak of the gold of Tolosa ogoing to the Magonid family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_roman_merchants_got_here_first">Pioneer Traders</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_A">The celebrations lasted long into the night and both gods and men were pleased. People with prodigious headaches struggled to return to their work the next morning... </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_B">We have given thanks to Jupiter and all is well.  </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_C">The bull was infested with gadfly! The goddess Juno was angered by our failure to honour her with proper sacrifice, and she has infested the entire herd to teach us a lesson!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_D">As the auspice chickens predicted all was well, and our people remained favoured by the gods. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_claudia_appropriated_accusation">Somehow, somwhere, someone talked, and the the Claudii's part in the disappearance of the gold of Tolosa is now known. Their influence with the people and the Senate is now greatly diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_B">The offerings were made and the head fell silent: the gods were properly appeased. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_C">As the head was burned it shrieked curses to the gods! The skies blackened and the rain put out the fire. The people ran screaming and news of this ill omen spread far and wide.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_D">The drought continued to plague the land for a time. The rains did come eventually, as they always will and always have done.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_A">There was no talking head! On visiting the source of the rumours all we found was a mad man clutching a turnip. He had carved a face into it and insisted that it had warned him of our doom!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_B">The offerings were made and the people waited with baited breath. When the rains came, they praised you for your quick thinking. All talk of the child and his starstruck ill luck was forgotten.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_C">The astrologers repeated the warnings they gave when the child was born. It was too late: the child's taint had already seeped into the land. Nothing could be done to reverse its terrible effects.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_2_talking_head_i_D">The people soon grew bored with this particular story and moved on to one about the girl born with the ears and tail of a pig.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_A">As the boy left your lands the people gathered to make sure that he was truly gone. Celebrations followed but the rains still refused to fall. The people remained afraid…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_not_capture">Tomb Robbers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_D">The magistrate continued to bleat on about his fears but nothing ever came of them.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_C">Selling a few of the slaves seemed to calm the magistrates nerves, and also provided a small boast to the local markets.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_B">The executions certainly thinned out the slaves but those that were left alive became intractable…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_A">As expected, slave owners were less than pleased with your decision to free their slaves. Your name was taken in vain by the great and good for some time.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_i_B">Ill Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_i_C">Ill Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_i_A">Ill Omens</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_8_surgeon_i_A">A Bloody Secret</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_8_surgeon_i_B">A Bloody Secret</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_8_surgeon_i_C">A Bloody Secret</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_barcid_appropriated_accusation">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_followup_i_C">Kidnapped</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_followup_i_B">Kidnapped</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_followup_i_A">Kidnapped</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_followup_i_A">The Djinn took you deeper and deeper into the desert. After days of walking it became obvious the djinn had deceived you and there was no treasure. News of your misadventure spread, and the people laughed and called you a fool.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_2_djinn_followup_i_B">The djinn was angered by your refusal to follow, but as your servant, he was unable to disobey. He led you home and the people rejoiced at your return.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_plague_spreads_army_foreign">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_A">Riddles and Divination</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_B">Riddles and Divination</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_C">Riddles and Divination</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_4_Delphoi_i_D">Riddles and Divination</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_i_C">When it became clear that we were unwilling to protect him he fled to another tribe. They turned him over to his enemies and he was put to death.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_i_B">As his enemies marched him away in chains the man swore bloody vengeance on our people. The gifts and gratitude left behind by his enemies more than made up for these empty threats.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_i_A">His enemies came looking for him and were not happy that we had offered him sanctuary, but there was little they could do.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_fire">Great Fire</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_bribes_i_A">The Price of Mercy</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_followup_i_C">Dark Deeds</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_followup_i_B">Dark Deeds</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_bribes_i_C">The Price of Mercy</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_guardian_1_followup_i_A">Dark Deeds</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_1_bribes_i_B">The Price of Mercy</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_hellenic_resistance_to_hegemony">One power ruling over the Hellenic states? This is an affront that must not continue! Tyrants must be brought down!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_bar_gold_tolosa_3_returned">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_i_C">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_i_B">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_legate_4_Plenty_slaves_i_A">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_civ_gold_tolosa_3_returned">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_D">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_A">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_C">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_4_Silk_i_B">The Silk Trade</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_all_trade_disruption">Disruption</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_3_not_faction_leader_loss_influence">Word of the commander's divine status has spread. The people begin to question the king's right to rule: surely the heir of Zeus should be master of all?</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_seastorm">Dark waves swell and lightning cracks the sky! Furious storms sweep the oceans. Ships are destroyed and men cast into the churning waves, lost to the gods and monsters of the deep.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_general_cloaka_maxima_i_A">A Filthy Spectacle</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_general_cloaka_maxima_i_B">A Filthy Spectacle</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_not_faction_leader_oracle_disappoint">The high priest is indifferent to our commander's requests for an audience. He simply states that the Oracle will not utter words the commander wishes to hear.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_i_A">Sanctuary</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_i_B">Sanctuary</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_vanquished_leader_i_C">Sanctuary</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_i_A">The magistrate was pleased that you took the time to hear his request and were gracious enough to act upon it. He put the slaves to good use and the province prospered. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_i_C">Like a petulant child, the magistrate refused to buy any additional slaves. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_3_lack_slaves_i_B">Under the lash the slaves worked much harder and the local economy was boosted, but it was only a matter of time until the unhappiness of the slaves boiled over into rebellion.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_D">Chalcon the Traveller</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_A">Chalcon the Traveller</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_C">Chalcon the Traveller</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_3_Chalcon_i_B">Chalcon the Traveller</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_D">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_B">The gods seemed indifferent to your gift. Perhaps they did not approve of the decadent, foreign stuff.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_C">The silk attracted traders from far and wide and trade flourished. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_1_Silk_i_A">The rich and powerful sent their agents to purchase bolt after bolt of silk. As the only source of this luxury item your profits soared.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_i_A">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_i_C">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_3_lack_slaves_i_B">A Lack of Slaves</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_C">Nectar of the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_B">Nectar of the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_A">Nectar of the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_trade_3_Wine_i_D">Nectar of the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_magonid_appropriated_accusation">Word of our involvement in the theft of the Gold of Tolosa is spreading. Faith in our family wanes and our influence in council is diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_i_B">Black Sheep</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_i_C">Black Sheep</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_faction_leader_oracle_impress">The Oracle of Zeus Ammon</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_i_A">With great pomp and ceremony the husband killed his wife before the whole tribe. He was grateful to you for allowing him to wash away his shame and all agreed that justice had been done.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_i_C">The man took your decision to do nothing as permission to do as he liked. He killed his wife, restoring his honour. Nothing further was said of the incident.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_6_unfaithful_woman_i_B">Angered by your refusal to give him justice the man sought out his wife's lover and challenged him to single combat. The two men fought for some time, but the young shield-bearer finally killed the husband. He then claimed the woman as his wife and no one disputed his right.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_i_A">A Bountiful Hunt</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_i_C">A Bountiful Hunt</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_5_the_hunt_i_B">A Bountiful Hunt</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_D">Another family took the old woman seriously and brought the remaining six books. Their priests identified them as the Sibylline Books, a gift from the gods!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_A">The Sibylline Books! These gifts from the gods contained much of our future. Before she disappeared into the night, the strange old woman warned that they must be carefully guarded.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_C">The old woman and her books disappeared and were never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_profession_1_Stranger_i_B">The priests quickly recognised the books for the divine gift they were, lamenting the loss of the other three. The old woman warned that they should be guarded carefully, and was never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_D">A Lust for Life</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_A">A Lust for Life</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_B">A Lust for Life</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_6_hedonistic_i_C">A Lust for Life</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_C">The Chickens have Spoken</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_B">The Chickens have Spoken</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_A">The Chickens have Spoken</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_religious_2_chickens_i_D">The Chickens have Spoken</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_plague_spreads_army">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_followup_i_A">He's dead. Probably his creditors…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_D">Baleful Stars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_followup_i_B">The man's body was found in the river. His creditors had taken his life as a final payment.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_debt_own_followup_i_C">Not even his mother mourned his passing. The funeral was a quiet affair, and the family never uttered his name again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_A">Baleful Stars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_C">Baleful Stars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_followup_i_B">Baleful Stars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_returned">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_i_B">Spare the Whip</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_i_C">Spare the Whip</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_3_slavedriver_i_A">Spare the Whip</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_i_C">As more men flocked to his banner the swordbearer began to panic: he had faked the whole thing and was no leader of men. Angered by his treachery the deceived warriors slit his throat and returned to their homes.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_i_B">As the blood of the man drenched the earth the gods rained down their displeasure. He had been chosen! We had no right to take his life. The people trembled with fear and whispered that their leaders were godless men.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_britons_sacred_sword_i_A">On meeting the man it was obvious that he was not a legendary leader sent by the gods. When the tribe heard the truth he became a figure of fun. The people fashioned a wooden crown for him to wear on feast days.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_not_capture">Catching a few pilferers has done little to stop the desecration of ancient graves…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_i_A">His mother eventually came forward and proved the truth of his words: the boy truly is a son of our house.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_wrecking_i_A">Wrecking Reputations</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_i_C">The boy soon disappeared and no more was said of the incident.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_wrecking_i_C">Wrecking Reputations</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_family_member_3_long_lost_i_B">His mother eventually came forward and proved the truth of his words: the boy truly is a son of our house. Angered by his dismissal he swore bloody vengeance on his sire's family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_profession_5_wrecking_i_B">Wrecking Reputations</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_D">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_A">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_B">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_2_plenty_slaves_i_C">Slaves, Slaves, Everywhere</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_i_A">All that could be done to protect your people was done and when the flood swept over your lands the overall damage was lessened as a result. Although crops were destroyed and lives lost, your people praised you for the lives you were able to save.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_i_C">On this occasion the astronomers had misread the signs, there was no flood.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_1_star_flood_i_B">The flood tore through your lands, destroying everything it touched. When the people heard that you had been warned of its coming they were outraged that you had failed to act.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_7_the_hunt_i_A">The Hunt</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_7_the_hunt_i_C">The Hunt</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_7_the_hunt_i_B">The Hunt</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_barcid_appropriated_accusation">Word of our involvement in the theft of the Gold of Tolosa is spreading. Faith in our family wanes and our influence in council is diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_i_C">Long Lost Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_i_B">Long Lost Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_i_A">Long Lost Son</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_caught_out_disrespect">The administration's involvement is known to the people. They are unhappy...</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_plague_spreads_region">Merchants and travellers warned of a plague sweeping the land. Their words were ignored and it is too late: nothing can stop the pestilence. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_piracy">Rampant Piracy</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_roman_gift_of_bacchus">Wine, the nectar of the gods, is Bacchus' gift to the people of Rome. Many honour his gift daily…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_i_A">On receiving the ransom the pirates made preparations to return the boy to his loving family.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_i_C">The fool! When the boy heard of the ransom you had paid he insisted he was worth more. The pirates are now demanding double!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_large_hoard">Tomb Robbers</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_i_B">On hearing of your refusal to discuss terms for the boy's safe return the pirates decided that he held no value. He was never seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_plague_starts_foreign">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_i_C">The merchant decided that he had too much to lose and so doubled his guard. The caravan made it safely through your lands and trade continued much as it always had.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_i_B">The merchant went on his way and was set upon by bandits. All his goods were stolen and many in his caravan lost their lives. After the attack, traders avoided routes through your lands and your income suffered. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_profession_3_caravans_i_A">The additional guards escorted the caravan safely through your lands, and the merchant was suitably grateful. When the bandits heard that you were providing guards to the caravans they went in search of easier targets.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_i_B">Vengeance</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_i_C">Vengeance</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_i_A">Vengeance</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_i_A">The boy paid in more ways than one. After giving us a considerable sum for our silence he was sadly unable to pay his less reputable creditors. When he attempted to reason with them they took his life in full payment of his debts.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_i_B">When the news began to spread the family attempted, and failed, to cover up the young man's indiscretions. The family name was ruined.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_family_member_1_debt_i_C">It was too late for the young man. He was involved with some very unsavoury characters who did not appreciate his lack of money. He was found dead in his own home. His family never discovered the killer or the reason for their son's murder.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_plague_spreads_region_foreign">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_i_A">Following her punishment the woman pleaded her innocence, claiming that her fellow concubines had invented the story in an attempt to be rid of her.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_i_B">After the concubine had been put to death it was revealed that there had never been a plot. Her fellows had concocted the whole matter to be rid of her.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_3_plots_i_C">The rumours continued but there were no tangible signs that the woman was plotting anything. Life at court continued much as it always had.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_snowstorm">The snow has fallen for days on end and shows no sign of ending. Equipment and supplies are ruined. Those who haven't frozen to death face a harrowing flight from winter's icy grip.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_i_A">The Evil Eye</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_i_B">The Evil Eye</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_archon_4_evil_eye_i_C">The Evil Eye</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_greek_gift_of_dionysos">Wine, the nectar of the gods, is Dionysus' gift to every Greek! Every Greek is thankful for this bounty!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_hannonid_appropriated">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_magonid">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_julia_appropriated_accusation">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_junia_appropriated_accusation">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_6_witch_i_C">The drought continued and the people of the tribe talked openly of your failure to act. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_6_witch_i_B">The woman was spirited away in the dead of night. When the news of her sudden disapperance spread it was quickly decided that she had used her dark arts to escape justice.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_religious_6_witch_i_A">The people gathered to witness the death of the witch. They watched in silence and when the woman was finally dead they looked to the sky expectantly, the rains still refused to fall. The witches taint clung to the land for sometime but the rains did return to wash it away eventually.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_D">The Price of Devotion</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_C">The Price of Devotion</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_B">The Price of Devotion</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_A">The Price of Devotion</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_flood">The rains destroy crops and livelihoods. Homes are gone, and loved ones disappear in the rushing waters, never to be seen again.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_D">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_A">As the only local source for these exotic items your profits soared.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_C">These new and exotic items brought traders from far and wide to our markets and trade flourished.  </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_B">Offerings of fragrant incense were burnt in every temple to ensure that each god received their fair share. The gods were pleased and blessed our people with good weather and a bountiful harvest. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_plague_spreads_region_foreign">Word has arrived from this nearby land. Disease has spread here from neighbouring regions, no doubt carried by merchants and travellers.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_B">Nisean Stallions</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_C">Nisean Stallions</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_A">Nisean Stallions</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_D">Nisean Stallions</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_6_witch_i_A">The Witchcraft</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_6_witch_i_B">The Witchcraft</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_religious_6_witch_i_C">The Witchcraft</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_setback_plague_starts">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_flood">Floods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_i_A">The magi interpreted the dream and warned that a terrible sickness would come to your lands if steps weren't taken to prevent it.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_i_B">After ignoring the dream a terrible sickness came to your lands. People died by the hundred, and the land itself became infected with the evil taint of the sickness.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_plague_spreads_region">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_i_A">His mother eventually came forward and proved the truth of her son's words. The boy truly is his father's son.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_i_B">His mother eventually came forward and proved the truth of her son's words. The boy truly is his father's son. Angered at the family's dismissal he swore bloody vengeance on his sire and his kin.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_5_long_lost_i_C">The boy soon disappeared and no more was said of the incident.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_roman_salarium">A local of high-standing, seeking to curry favour with the occupiers, has revealed the whereabouts of a vast salt hoard.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_D">Dark Deeds</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_C">Dark Deeds</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_B">Dark Deeds</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_7_guardian_i_A">Dark Deeds</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_C">The two lovers were put to death during a public spectacle that sent a clear message to all:  you would not tolerate disobedience!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_B">The girl was put to death quietly, but word spread. People whispered that your wrath was fearsome when provoked!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_A">The Greek physician was put to death before a partly-satisfied crowd, nearly all of which seemed to be his previous conquests and their angry husbands.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_3_greek_lover_followup_i_D">The girl continued her dalliance with this Greek but, as time went by, he grew tired of her and moved on to another wayward girl.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_D">The Vestal was released but her body was found a day later. There were no signs of injury or visible wounds. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_A">As the woman's sentence was carried out lightning struck the roof of the temple! All those involved in the Vestal's death were crushed by falling rubble.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_B">Entombed in a chamber underneath the temple, the Vestal was left to the mercy of the gods. The gods claimed her life, and her sisters saw that her body was properly honoured.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_4_vestal_i_C">Left to wander the streets with no money or food, the woman soon turned to the only profession open to her. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_roman_gift_of_bacchus">Gift of Bacchus</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_egypt_tomb_robbers_2_large_hoard">Those who say that nothing comes of crime have obviously never seen the riches in the Egyptian Royal Tombs!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_4_Vicious_words_i_A">Vicious Words</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_4_Vicious_words_i_B">Vicious Words</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_4_Vicious_words_i_C">Vicious Words</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_barcid">Rumours has it that the Gold of Tolosa was not taken by bandits. It is supposedly now the property of Barcids! These foul rumours diminished our influence in the council. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_gaul_gift_of_braciaca">Gift of Braciaca</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_2_Wine_i_B">Nectar of the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_2_Wine_i_A">Nectar of the Gods</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_A">The Nisean horses were given to the army and the men were in awe of the beasts. The rumour quickly spread that they were the distant relatives of Pegasus: the men treated them with the utmost respect.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_C">The arrival of Nisean horse traders drew other traders to our lands, improving our trade links and the income gained from them. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_B">The offspring of the Nisean stallions were some of the most impressive animals the breeders had ever seen, strong, swift and beautiful.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_3_Nisean_i_D">Trade continued much as it always had, the arrival of this trader and his goods had little effect. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_i_A">The Word of a Slave</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_i_C">The Word of a Slave</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_i_B">The Word of a Slave</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_julia">Despite barbarian marauders stealing the hoard, nasty rumours speak of the Julii having taken done it. Their influence with the people and the Senate has diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_junia">Despite barbarian marauders stealing the hoard, nasty rumours speak of the Junii having taken done it. Their influence with the people and the Senate has diminished.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_D">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_B">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_C">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_trade_2_Spices_i_A">Incense and Spice and all Things Nice</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_i_A">The kidnapper was a man acting alone and he agreed to make the trade somewhere private.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_i_C">Being the brave warrior she was, the general's wife escaped her captors and returned to her husband, no worse for her adventure. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_i_B">The general was angered by your lack of support and took a small group of warriors to steal his wife back. Much blood was shed, but the general did manage to retrieve his wife.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_i_C">Foul Plots</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_i_B">Foul Plots</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_concubine_2_killer_queen_i_A">Foul Plots</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_followup_i_A">Pirates!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_followup_i_B">Pirates!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_4_bandit_stolen">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_barcid">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_disaster_plague_starts_region_beseiged">Starved and cut off from the outside, people are dying. Disposing of the dead hasn't stopped the pestilence.  </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_plague_starts_region">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_i_C">The general paid the ransom himself and his wife was returned to him. Not long after she gave birth to a strong, healthy son. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_i_B">Angered by your refusal to provide the ransom for his wife's safe return, the general slandered you to anyone who would listen. A once loyal servant, he had lost all respect for you.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_4_kidnapped_i_A">The ransom was paid and the general's wife was safely returned to him. He was incredibly grateful and pledged the unborn child to your service.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_setback_sandstorm">Violent sandstorms in the burning wastes have slowed progress to a tortured crawl. The desert is merciless. Men die like flies; their bodies feed the vultures.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_3_faction_leader_gain_influence">The Oracle of Zeus Ammon</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_roman_salarium">Salarium</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_i_B">In the Dark of the Night</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_2_dark_dreams_i_A">In the Dark of the Night</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_B">Young Pilgrims</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_C">Young Pilgrims</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_A">Young Pilgrims</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_D">Young Pilgrims</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_bones_i_A">The griffin bones went on display and people flocked to see them. News of their discovery spread and thefts from mines reduced, as wrongdoers feared the wrath of griffins guarding treasures deep within the earth.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_bones_i_B">The traveller sold the griffin bones to someone who took his claims more seriously. People flocked to see them and thefts from nearby mines dropped as rumours spread that more griffins had been sighted.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_creature_1_griffin_bones_i_C">After a series of refusals the traveller decided to take the griffin bones on tour. He travelled with the caravans and made a good living from the fantastical remains of the mythical beast. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_2_not_faction_leader_oracle_impress">The Oracle speaks! Our great commander is divine and has been shown his path! </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_greco_roman_description_of_asia">The wonders of the far east have described in volumes that have found their way to our shores.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_D">The woman came to plead her son's case time and time again. After a while your guards grew weary and refused her entry. She was forced to plead her case to your courtyard fountain.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_A">The boy returned to court and was the model of propriety. His mother was incredibly grateful and did all she could to support you, even as others muttered that he did not deserve your forgiveness.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_B">"A small party of trusted men was sent to verify the mother's claims. When they returned all they would say was that the boy had been caught in ""a compromising position"". They felt it would be best for all involved if he stayed safely away from court."</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_2_debauched_i_C">The mother was devastated that you had denied her this simple boon, but everyone else agreed that the family was better off without the boy.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_plague_starts_region_beseiged">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_i_B">Pirates!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_i_C">Pirates!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_family_member_6_pirates_i_A">Pirates!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_claudia">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_i_C">Baleful Stars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_i_B">Baleful Stars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_eastern_religious_4_star_baby_i_A">Baleful Stars</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_piracy">Pirates have taken control of the oceans! No coastal settlement is safe! Only madmen take to the waves unarmed.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_car_gold_tolosa_4_bandit_stolen">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_greco_roman_description_of_egypt">The strange customs and beautiful sights of Egypt have come us in written by a diligent traveller. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_chain_car_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_hannonid">Rumours has it that the Gold of Tolosa was not taken by bandits. It is supposedly now the property of Hannonids! These foul rumours diminished our influence in the council. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_1_i_A">Charging to see the dolphin and his boy paid for the visitors' entertainment with a little money left over. However, the province's reputation suffered as people complained about having to pay to see a gift from the gods.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_1_i_B">Once the creature was gone there was no reason for visitors to go to the province and all returned to normal.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_creature_dolphin_1_i_C">People continued to flock to the province to see the dolphin and costs to entertain them continued to rise.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_A">Although we convinced the man to drop his claims to be a miracle some people followed him on a pilgrimage.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_C">The people and the gods were angered by your presumption. What right did you have to take away gifts given by the gods?</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_B">The people rejoiced and marvelled at the gifts the god had bestowed upon this lucky man.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_religious_5_Epidaurus_i_D">After couple of weeks the man disappeared, no doubt moving on to pastures new.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_D">The High Priestess introduced her tax, prompting a great deal of grumbling from the people. However, as the voice of the gods on earth she was safe from reprisals. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_A">The High Priestess was right. The new temple tax was the will of the gods. After speaking with you she returned to her temple to find that it had been struck by lightning, a sign of Zeus' displeasure, for she had failed.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_B">The profits from the new temple tax were pleasing, but the people were outraged. They felt that you were exploiting their love of the gods for your own ends.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_profession_4_Priestess_i_C">Within days of the collection of the new tax the people denounced the High Priestess and her exploitation of the gods. Many called for her to be replaced. Some requested much harsher measures…</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_incident_gaul_gift_of_braciaca">It is no secret that Celts are fond of drink, as shown by their many drinking halls! Braciaca, god of malt, has given the people the gift of beer. They could not have asked for more.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_2_Wine_i_A">With the introduction of the new standards, wine production slowed. However, the increase in quality meant merchants were able to charge more, and the province became renowned for its fine wines.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_magistrate_2_Wine_i_B">The people were outraged by your failure to act. Many believed good wine was their right as citizens, and they were not happy that they were forced to import wine from other provinces.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_successor_heir_of_zeus_3_faction_leader_loss_influence">The Oracle of Zeus Ammon</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_i_C">Child of Ill-repute</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_i_B">Child of Ill-repute</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_roman_family_member_2_harlot_i_A">Child of Ill-repute</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_disaster_plague_starts_region_foreign">Plague</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_i_B">A hired knife slipped into our rivals' house and silenced the girl once and for all. They still attempted to leak what they had learned but, without the source, their words were as the wind.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_i_C">The slave girl and her stories were put on display for all to hear. The people walked by and enjoyed the spectacle, but few stopped to listen to her words. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_hellenic_slaves_2_Thracian_i_A">After paying handsomely for the girl's safe return it was decided that she knew too much. She had to die. </string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_incident_greek_gift_of_dionysos">Gift of Dionysus</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_C">The augurs checked the signs again, and the gods were pleased with the sacrifice! The people rejoiced and all was well.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_B">The gods were pleased by the mighty sacrifice. Unfortunately, some good breeding stock was used and the quality of our livestock suffered as a result.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_A">The bull wasn't enough! The gods in their displeasure sent rains for weeks on end. Crops were ruined and the people hid in their homes, fearing the lightning that split the sky and the thunder that shook the ground they stood on!</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_roman_religious_3_augres_i_D">Someone must have been mistaken. Perhaps… it was merely shadows they saw, for there have been no further signs of the gods' displeasure.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_julia">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_chain_rom_gold_tolosa_5_bandit_stolen_accusation_junia">The Gold of Tolosa</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_i_A">An assassin was hired and it was only weeks before he tracked down the killer. He brought him before the grieving widow, and she watched the light leave his eyes and thereby found a measure of peace.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_i_C">Her grief soon got the better of the poor woman and she fell ill. She was bedridden for months but, when she was well again, the madness and her desire for revenge  had abated.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_description_rom_subject_eastern_family_member_1_revenge_i_B">Lost in her grief, the woman ignored your wishes and hired an assassin. He found his target quickly and returned to the widow with the murderer's head.</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_i_B">Kidnapped</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_i_C">Kidnapped</string>
<string name="incidents_localised_title_rom_subject_barb_family_member_3_kidnapped_i_A">Kidnapped</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>