<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_rome_cornelia">House of Cornelia</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_egypt_ptolemaic">One of Alexander the Great’s generals, Ptolemy, was father to the current Egyptian ruler. Under his reign Ptolemaic Egypt remains rich, powerful, and influential.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_iceni_council">By age and experience the elders in the council are the wisest men, and therefore the most qualified to rule and provide counsel when necessary.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_pontus_council">The Mithridatic court is a unique blend of coastal Greek culture and Iranian hinterland aristocracy, tracing its roots back to the Persian Empire.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_sparta_council">The Council of Elders in Sparta, the Gerousia, has 28 members, all aged 60 or older, as well as two kings. A loud voice is important, as decisions are made based on the loudest shouts, an idea that dates back to its founding by Lycurgus in the 7th century BC. </string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_egypt_ptolemaic">Ptolemaic Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_suebi_council">By age and experience the elders in the council are the wisest men, and therefore the most qualified to rule and provide counsel when necessary.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_egypt_council">Other Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_epirus_council">Other Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_athens_council">Five hundred citizens make up the Boule, or council, of Athens. Originally a council of nobles, the Boule now has hereditary  positions, some elected members and some chosen by lot to serve for a year.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_epirus_council">The Synedrion is a small governing and advisory council of the most eminent Greek nobles, picked by the king himself. Sometimes its membership is expanded by admitting city representatives as well.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_sparta_ruler">Royal Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_athens_council">The Oligarchs</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_rome_cornelia">The Cornelii clan is among the most illustrious of Roman families: more become consuls, generals and statesmen than any other family. Among them, the Scipios and the Sullas are especially notable. Sulla Felix, the famous dictator, was a member of this family.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_iceni_council">Other Chiefs</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_pontus_council">Other Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_epirus_ruler">Molossians</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_egypt_council">The Ptolemaic court is a complicated blend of imported Greek nobility and an increasingly-Hellenized, native Egyptian aristocracy.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_sparta_council">Other Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_suebi_council">Other Chiefs</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_athens_ruler">The Magistrates</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_arverni_ruler">Elder Chiefs</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_arverni_council">Other Chiefs</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_seleucid_council">The leading families of provinces benefit from the empire, and are united at court by a shared culture. The royal household serves as a crucible for the otherwise disparate nobility.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_pro_politics_rome_council">Other Houses</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_rome_council">Other Houses</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_arverni_council">By age and experience the elders in the council are the wisest men, and therefore the most qualified to rule and provide counsel when necessary.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_parthia_arsacid">Arsacid Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_parthia_arsacid">Arsaces, the leader of the Parni tribe, conquered Parthia in north-eastern Iran, then secured the satrapy of Parthava from the Seleucid Empire following a rebellion.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_parthia_council">Following the Persian tradition, Parthians accept local kings as quasi-autonomous vassals. Beyond the borders of Iran, the court appoints less-powerful satraps to rule.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_carthage_barcid">Barcid Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_carthage_council">This body serves as the elected senate of Carthage, drawn from among its citizens. They also served as a council of magistrates.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_macedon_council">Other Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_arverni_ruler">King Luernios rules over the most powerful of Gallic tribes from his stronghold in Gergovia. His word is law from the River Rhine to the Atlantic coast. Under him, the Arverni are reputed to play hard and fight hard. </string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_parthia_council">Other Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_carthage_barcid">"This notable family in Carthage is named after Barca or Barcas, meaning ""lightning bolt"". The family strongly opposed the threat from Roman expansionism."</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_macedon_council">The Synedrion is a small governing and advisory council of the most eminent Greek nobles, picked by the king himself. Sometimes its membership is expanded by admitting city representatives as well.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_carthage_magonid">The Magonids are an old and prominent Carthaginian family. Members of the Magonid family were responsible for Carthage's expansion into Lybia, Sardinia, and Sicily.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_rome_julia">Originally from Alba Longa, the Julii clan are an ancient patrician family, with a tradition of attaining high office dating back centuries. The most famous of the clan was Gaius Julius Caesar, who became life-long dictator.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_rome_junia">Perhaps blessed by the goddess Juno, for whom the month of June is named, the Junii are one of the most respectable families in Rome. This reputation rests on the labours of Lucius Junius Brutus, who drove out the last Roman king, Tarquinius Superbus.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_seleucid_seleucids">Seleucid Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_macedon_antigonid">Antigonid Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_rome_council">The Senate is the most important day-to-day political body of the Roman Republic. Composed of the most notable and experienced politicians, its main role is to direct domestic, foreign and military policy. The name senate comes from the Latin 'senex', literally meaning 'old men' - technically making it a 'Council of Elders'.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_pro_politics_rome_council">The Senate is the most important day-to-day political body of the Roman Republic. Composed of the most notable and experienced politicians, its main role is to direct domestic, foreign and military policy. The name senate comes from the Latin 'senex', literally meaning 'old men' - technically making it a 'Council of Elders'.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_seleucid_council">Other Families</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_carthage_magonid">Magonid Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_macedon_antigonid">The Macedonians can trace their heritage beyond Alexander the Great into the mists of antiquity. Who else has a history of such greatness, both mortal and divine? As a warlike nation, where every boy dreams of being a hero and becoming a legend, the Macedonians are a ferocious people and scornful of weakness. Their greatest minds are experts in military and civil arts, and can outwit almost any war leader. Having conquered the world under Alexander, who dares stop them doing so again?</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_carthage_council">Other Dynasties</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_seleucid_seleucids">In grabbing his share of Alexander's empire, Seleucus I Nicator carved out the largest of the Successor Kingdoms. The Seleucid Empire has a rather diverse composition, leading to much internal strife.</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_rome_julia">House of Julia</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_rome_junia">House of Junia</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_iceni_ruler">Elder Chiefs</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_iceni_ruler">The Iceni are a proud, fierce people from the flatlands of eastern Britannia, and among the toughest tribes of that mist-wreathed island. </string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_carthage_hannonid">Hannonid Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_pontus_mithridatic">Originally part of the Persian satrapy of Cappadocia, Mithridates remained ruler of the area after Alexander's conquest. After the partition of Alexander's empire his son fled from Antigonus, and successfully fought against Seleucus, re-establishing his dynasty in the process.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_athens_ruler">The magistrates of Athens have executive powers. Various checks and balances help maintain democracy, but there are times when the system falls under the influence of a single indvidual who secures total power for himself.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_epirus_ruler">Claiming descent from the mythical Molossus, the Molossians settled in Epirus following the sacking of Troy.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_suebi_ruler">Warriors of this German tribe are marked out by their hair, which is tied in a distinctive knot. This knot marks a man as a warrior, not a slave, and makes him taller, giving him a formidable appearance. Whilst the Suebi have a reputation as fickle and untrustworthy, enemies think them extremely belligerent!</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_suebi_ruler">Elder Chiefs</string>
<string name="political_parties_name_localised_rom_politics_pontus_mithridatic">Mithridatic Dynasty</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_sparta_ruler">The two hereditary kings of Sparta, from the Agiad and Eurypontid families, claim descent from Herakles. They are completely equal in authority and power.</string>
<string name="political_parties_description_localised_rom_politics_carthage_hannonid">Founded by Hanno the Great, the Hannonid, or Hannonian, dynasty ruled Carthage for 50 years during the 3rd century BC.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>