<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Amphitheatre_flavour">"

The word amphitheatre means “a theatre on both sides” and they developed from Greek circular theatres as venues for open air entertainment. Used for the richer members of the audience to show off to lesser folk, and to celebrate religious festivals, their main purpose was gladiatorial games. Blood became the staple entertainment of the Roman people. Every corner of the Empire from Britain to Syria had its amphitheatres. They ranged in size from small wooden structures to the great Colosseum in Rome. Here the plebeians could be entertained, and watch gladiators demonstrating the Roman virtues of courage and fortitude, and enjoy the bloodlust, spectacle and cruelty. They were also important to the social order: events were often free, paid for by patrician aristocrats, the wealthy, and emperors, all hoping for public support."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Port_flavour">"

Many ancient civilisations relied on naval power, both mercantile and military , to maintain their empires. At its height, the Seleucid Empire reached the Mediterranean, the Persian Gulf, and the Caspian Sea, and its trade influence spread into the Black Sea beyond. 

Closer to home, fish were a vital food resource for many cultures, supplementing farming especially in arid coastal regions. In comparison to the dangers of drought and flood that could destroy crops, fish were a resource that could be relied upon."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Fountains_flavour">"

Fountains and pools were often centrepieces in courtyards and gardens, a display of power and wealth in Carthage. Functional as well as decorative, they provided water and natural cooling in the desert heat. Fountains and cisterns also provided the water essential for ritual ablutions, necessary for the worship of the gods. 

Wells, springs and waterways would channel water to fill enclosed cisterns, which were designed to reduce water loss from evaporation, and these would then feed fountains by gravity."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Panhellenic_games_flavour">"

The Olympiad was a four year calendar cycle in Hellenistic culture marked by a series of four religious festivals. All the city-states and colonies came together to celebrate their culture, and engage in sporting contests. Foot and chariot races, javelin and discus throwing, wresling and boxing were included. The Olympics in Elis  were the biggest festival, and honoured Zeus, the king of the gods Zeus, as did the Nemean games. Other gods were honoured with their own games: Poseidon had the Isthmian games in Corinth, while Apollo was celebrated by the Pythian games at Delphi. Despite the bellicose relationships between some states peace was declared during the festivals. The victors were rewarded only with garlands and wreaths."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Farm_flavour">"

Farming in dry climes was and is a difficult endeavour. Water and its proper use are the crucial factors: rivers and flood plains good farm land, but floods can destroy crops and wash away good soil instead of renewing the land. Good land is often at a premium. 

In more arid areas, farmers are reliant on canals and qanats for irrigation, and water must be managed carefully. 

Farms would produce wheat, barley, olives and wine, as well as cattle, goats and sheep. Despite apparently unpromising land, many eastern states, including Seleucia and Parthia, had quite a strong agricultural base."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Shrine_of_astarte_flavour">"

Astarte was a complicated, warlike goddess and worshipped by soldiers and couples for her influence over war and love. She was most commonly depicted symbolically by a star within a circle representing the Evening Star, the planet Venus. Several creatures were also considered sacred to her, including the lion, horse and sphinx. In Carthage she was considered to have a separate role from Tanit but there was some overlap in their responsibilities. 

Astarte is most famously depicted as an alabaster figurine known as the “Lady of Galera”. This small statuette is seated on a throne and flanked by sphinxes. It holds a bowl that can be filled from liquid that pours out of her breasts. An ancient Ugarit goddess worshipped by the Phoenicians, Astarte was equated to Artemis and Aphrodite by the Greeks and to Venus by the Romans. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Slave_trader_flavour">"

Slavery was everywhere in the ancient world. Slaves were bought and traded in every town and city, their status the result of wars, kidnap, birth, poverty, or criminality. From fields to the mightiest of temples, slavery was the engine of everything. Interestingly, no group, nationality or tribe was considered to be automatically worth of enslavement. Misfortune could be visited with equally on almost anyone. 

Slaves were rarely used in battle on land or sea, and the image of slaves chained to the oars of warships is largely a product of Hollywood history. Rowing required skill, not just a strong back. And only the most desperate of masters would ever give their slaves weapons and permission to kill..."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shieldmaker_flavour">"

The shield was the most important piece of armour to a Greek infantryman. The hoplon not only gave the hoplites their name but also led to the creation of the phalanx, a supremely effective fighting formation. The concave, circular hoplon was made of bronze and wood with leather strapping for the hoplite's arm. It was of similar size to many previous designs but its unique grip allowed troops to stand close and cover the next man thus forming a solid, unyielding wall: the phalanx. The hoplon was used throughout the Hellenistic world. It was a terrible dishonour to lose a shield in battle as it was the hoplite’s talisman and symbol of being part of the greater army of his city-state."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Training_field_flavour">"

As warfare developed tactics became more organised and required disciplined training to carry out. The phalanx of hoplites was among the most intimidating battle formations: troops were trained to hold out their sarissae, or long spears, between their overlapping hoplon shields to create an impenetrable wall. The massed ranks behind the front line added weight to the attack. Hellenistic armies used this traditional Greek tactic to great effect. In time, the phalanx developed from a manoeuvrable formation to a massive unit that could overrun anything that stood in its way. 

Providing its its flanks were protected, and on flat ground, the phalanx was hugely effective. It could be used as the main line of attack or to lock the enemy in position while the cavalry swept round to attack the flanks and rear. In rough terrain or when the wings or rear of the phalanx were exposed, it proved somewhat unwieldy and vulnerable."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Loremasters_hut_flavour">"

Little is known for certain of the ways and practices of the ancient druids. Classical writers stated that these mysterious men refused to write their secrets down, preferring to pass their knowledge from generation to generation orally. The writer Diodorus Siculus was the first to discuss the idea that there were distinct roles within the druid system, and it was Strabo who divided these into three separate classes; those who studied moral philosophy were known as the ""druidai""; the diviners and specialists in the natural world were the ""o'vateis""; and the poets and singers were the ""bardoi"". The bardoi, or bards, were responsible for passing on history in poetry and song. History always included the brave deeds of warriors as well as knowledge of the gods and the natural world."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Bronze_workshop_flavour">"

Thanks to the tribal practice of making votive offerings to gods of rivers and waterways, many bronze artefacts have been discovered at the bottom of lakes and rivers all over Europe. The River Thames in London, England must have held particular significance to the local tribes as a number of bronze work pieces have been discovered on the bottom over the years. The Waterloo Helmet, a ceremonial piece with two horns, was discovered in 1868, and the Wandsworth and Battersea shields were also recovered from the river. and now reside in the British Museum. Like the helmet, the Battersea Shield is thought to be a ceremonial piece as there is no evidence of damage and no sign that it was ever attached to a wooden base, which would have given it the strength it required to be battle ready.  "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Heavy_horse_studs_flavour">"

Eastern cavalry had Hellenic and Persian influences, with the more easterly states favouring cataphract-style scale armour protecting both rider and horse in the Parthian fashion. The Seleucid kings maintained two 1000-man units of elite companion cavalry, the Hetairoi, modelled by Antiochus III on Parthian cataphracts. 

Following the Alexandrian and Parthian examples, heavy cavalry were a hammer in the tactical toolbox of eastern generals, driving off their opposite numbers before outflanking and exploiting the vulnerable flanks of phalanxes. This was helped by the use of a wedge formation, driving into the enemy."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_City_flavour">"

The cities of the ancient world were situated where resources were plentiful and could be defended. River crossings, ports and natural trade routes were ideal locations for large populations to arise. 

Cities developed over long periods of time, often incorporating the architecture of earlier civilizations. In 305BC, the city of Seleucia vastly expanded an existing town on the west bank of the Tigris River. In the centuries that followed it came to rival the great Hellenic cities in magnificence. Often planned expansion was limited to high-status quarters of the city: palaces, temples and public areas. Everyone else squeezed into the available space within the walls. This led to magnificent buildings being only a stone's throw from squalid slums."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Nobles_quarters_flavour">"

Elite infantry had a prominent role in the ancient world, often as noble companions and royal guards. Alexander’s successors had the agema and hypaspists, such as the Silver-Shields who served until they were almost too old to fight. The Seleucid Empire founded its own Silver-Shields, but these were an elite unit of phalangites. 

Over time, these elite units became professional and some, such as the nobles and mercenaries protecting the Parthian King of Kings, became royal guards living within the palace. Royal guards were not, however, always bound by tradition: the Seleucid ruler, Antiochus IV, retrained some 5000 Silver-Shields to fight in the ""Roman fashion"" as legionaries."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Water_canals_flavour">"

Canals and aqueducts were often used to supply the farms and communities with essential water. Whatever the source water often needed to be channelled and carried vast distances to sustain people, animals and farmlands. 

As a precious commodity in hot climates, water control was a matter of some sophistication and importance. Canals and aqueducts were carefully graded to manage flow. Reservoirs were used to store water for particularly dry times. Sluices directed the water onto surrounding farmlands."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_germanic_Grove_of_thunaraz_flavour">"

Literally meaning thunder, Thunaraz is one of the gods of the sky. He is very similar to the Norse god Thor and governed storms. He was best known for his incredible strength for wielding a heavy hammer in battle as a weapon as he rode his chariot across the heavens. He was not inclined to get involved with politics and the lives of men as Teiwaz and Wodanaz, but was seen as a great protector. He was the most popular god among the common German people and was especially worshipped by farmers and rural folk who depended on his gifts of rain for good harvests. These farmers were also the warriors of a barbarian army in times of war, and Thunaraz in his aggressive ways was a great inspiration to them. His power was seen in its purest form in lightning: a magical force that struck from the sky with great destructive power. Today his name lives on in English in the fifth day of the week, Thursday."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Blacksmith_flavour">"

If one worker built the ancient and modern worlds, it is the blacksmith. Tools of bronze and then iron allowed land to be cultivated, ships to be built, stone to be quarried, and wars to be fought with greater and more terrible savagery than ever before. Blacksmiths were ubiquitous: every village and town of note had a smithy turning out anything that the community needed. Smithing also encouraged trade, as the tin needed for bronze was not always a local resource. This is what led the Phoenicians to sail all the way to distant Britain: they were looking for a reliable, and plentiful, source of tin. 

It was the move from bronze to iron that gave warriors an edge in combat, often quite literally. In the hands of a strong man, an iron sword could cleave through bronze armour and weaponry with suitably unfortunate results for the target. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Spice_trader_flavour">"

Spices were highly valued commodities, both for local consumption and trade with other peoples. Trade along what would become the Silk and Spice Roads began almost at the start of civilization with the rise of farming and trade amongst Neolithic communities. It was not until Arab and Phoenician traders began trading spices and other luxury goods, such as gold, precious stones, silks and fine textiles, that fixed routes and markets began to appear. 

As well as spices to flavour foods, other items were traded including those considered essential for religious rites, such as frankincense. Traded for over 5,000 years, this tree resin gives off a strong aroma when burned. Myrrh was also highly valued for its uses as a medicine and for embalming mummies."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Fishing_Port_flavour">"

Seafood has always been important around the Mediterranean. The sea could be guaranteed to feed everyone even when crops failed. 

Fish was also important to the Romans for garum, a fish sauce that they added to many meals to give them extra pep and flavour. Garum, however, may not sound all that appetizing to many modern diners: it was made from the salted intestines of fish, left to ferment for many months. The exact flavour of a particular garum depended on the fish used, and the herbs added during fermentation and bottling in amphorae. The varied and flavoursome garum trade was actually quite widespread and important in the Roman world. Troops expected garum to be available to season their food, even if they were on duty in far Britannia! 

As well as being a tasty, if not essential, addition to Roman meals, garum was also used as a medicine for all kinds of problems although, given the chief ingredients, it was probably most use as a cure for constipation! Even so, garum was not universally liked: Seneca, the Roman stoic philosopher, hated the filthy stuff even though his family came from a garum-making region of Hispania."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Commons_flavour">"

Barbarian settlements were just as carefully laid out as any Roman or Greek city. They had clearly defined streets, areas for craftsmen to work, cattle pens and common land for use by the whole tribe. One of the best preserved examples of a Celtic village can be found In Chysauster in Cornwall, England. Here, the homesteads are built around an internal courtyard that has given them the name ""courtyard houses"". This particular style of homestead is only found on the Land's End peninsular and the Isles of Scilly. The eight remaining structures are clearly clustered along a street, and the paving stones survive to this day. As well as the houses, this settlement has an incredibly well preserved ""fogou"", or souterrain, an underground chamber used for food storage."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_tw2_rome_rome_Slums_flavour">%placeholder%</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Consecrated_Ground_flavour">"

Consecrated ground was dedicated to a religious purpose and given over to worship, prayer and often sacrifice. In fact, the Latin word “templum” actually refers not to a building but to a sacred outdoor space, where a religious structure might be constructed. 

Maintaining good relations with the gods was an essential part of everyday life for people who had a different god watching over them for every given circumstance. There were shrines in every home and community, and consecrated grounds such as springs and groves and temples were found everywhere. Up to a third of the official Roman year was dedicated to celebrating religious festivals and shrines were well-used spaces. To desecrate such a place was a sacrilege punishable by death."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_germanic_Grove_of_wodanaz_flavour">"

Meaning literally ""the Raging One"", Wodanaz is the chief of all the gods. Aligned with Odin in Norse mythology, he is the foremost of the Aesir and a complicated deity. Son of giants, he presides over wisdom, philosophy, art and poetry. He sacrificed himself to himself by hanging, dangling from the World Tree for nine days and nine nights. His reward was the learning of powerful songs and the twenty four runes of power. He also attained great knowledge by giving up one of his eyes in return for a drink from the Well of Wisdom. Wodanaz is seen as the creator of the German people and the lord of magic, death and prophetic power. Knowledge, wisdom and even berserker fury are given to those who pay homage to him."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Chieftains_hold_flavour">"

Many of the tribal leaders who fought the Romans are remembered as noble adversaries who stood against the Roman war machine but were ultimately crushed by it. There were those who chose to accept Roman rule in order to protect their people. Cartimandua, queen of the Briganti tribe in Britannia, chose to ally herself with Rome after witnessing the devastation of the southern British tribes. Fleeing for his life, the leader of the Catuvellauni tribe, Caratacus, sought refuge with Cartimuandua. Rather than break her alliance with Rome she gave up Caratacus to the Romans in chains. Her peace with Rome was eventually broken when her ex-husband rose up against her, plunging her people back into war with Rome."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Fishermans_huts_flavour">"

Over many years humans have developed a variety of fishing methods from the spear fishing of the Egyptians to the use of fish-cages in Greece. People developed methods that were appropriate to the waters they were fishing and the fish they hoped to catch. The Celtic tribes of Britain and Ireland developed a small river going vessel known as a coracle. This lightweight, oval boat had a framework of willow rods that were covered with animal skin. Its light weight meant it could be easily carried, allowing fishermen to carry their boats down to the river from their homes. The design of the coracle varied slightly depending on the river where it was to be used. Coracles for tidal rivers, like the Tywi in Wales, were round and deep, whereas those designed for use in rapidly flowing water had shallow, flat bottoms."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Grove_of_epona_flavour">"

Epona was the Celtic goddess of horses and fertility, and her name is thought to come from a Gaulish word meaning ""great horse"". She was often depicted as a woman riding a horse side saddle accompanied by a foal, which represents her role as a fertility goddess. She was adopted into the Roman pantheon and her cult spread quickly across Europe, thanks to the Roman cavalry who saw her as their protector. Her role eventually expanded to goddess of all those who worked with horses, as described in ""The Golden Ass"" by Apuleus. This text also hints that small shrines to Epona were erected in stables and barns to protect their equine occupants."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Shrine_of_melqart_flavour">"

The cult of Melqart spread across the Mediterranean from its Phoenician home city of Tyre, and shrines were eventually dedicated in cities as far away as Gades, or Cadiz, in Hispania. As Phoenician power waned, Melqart’s cult remained popular among the Carthaginians probably because of their reliance on trade. He was often invoked as a witness when a deal or bargain was struck. 

According to Livy, Hannibal was a devout follower and made a pilgrimage to Gades before beginning his invasion of Italy. His piety was apparently rewarded, and Melqart granted Hannibal visions of the destruction he would cause. The Greeks sometimes linked Melqart to their own semi-divine hero, Heracles."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_germanic_Grove_of_fraujaz_flavour">"

Fraujaz was the god of fertility, leadership, virility and prosperity. One of the Wenijiz family of earth gods descended from giants, ""the Lord""  was worshipped both as a god of peace and a warrior. As a handsome, manly figure he was called upon to make marriages fertile. Fraujaz rode in a chariot pulled by a boar, owned the fastest ship ever built and had a magical sword. Unfortunately, he is also a doomed figure, and destined to be struck down in the final battle of the gods. He is closely aligned to Freyr in later Norse mythology and to his female counterpart, Freya."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Wine_trader_flavour">"

The Greeks began making wine over 8000 years ago and eventually traded it all across the Mediterranean. Wine was a civilizing thing, promoting good conversation and bringing medical benefits. Retsina, still popular today, was a particular favourite across the Greek world. The Phoenicians spread viniculture along their trade routes from Canaan to North Africa, and from Carthage into Spain. Their winemaking techniques influenced both Greeks and Romans and they used amphorae to store wine. Around 600BC Greeks took winemaking to Massilia in southern Gaul, and helped establish a wine region that still exists today. Carthage produced good wines including a raisin wine that was loved by Romans. The ubiquitous use of wine, both domestically and ceremonially, along with the easy cultivation of grapes in hot climates all contributed to the spread of the this lucrative trade throughout the world."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Sacred_grove_flavour">"

Trees were considered sacred by many cultures, and in ancient Greece groves were believed to be populated by nymphs and other minor deities. They were places of calm, shade, and divine protection. Only initiates were allowed near the trees, and animals were not allowed to graze within. 

The most sacred grove in Greece was at Dodona, and dedicated to the Mother Goddess, the powerful earth goddess at the centre of nearly all ancient religions. According to Herodotus the site at Dodona had been used for thousands of years to foretell the future and seek advice. The initiated oracle would give answers to questions by watching the rustling leaves on the trees…"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Nomad_camp_flavour">"

With their herds of domestic animals, nomadic tribesmen travelled from camp to camp following the seasons and the grazing. They relied on their sheep and goats to provide meat, milk, hides and wool as the basis of their entire way of life. Despite lacking the supposed benefits of a settled community, nomads could prosper. With fearsome warriors among their numbers, they were not above ""foraging"" by raiding nearby settlements and farms!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shrine_of_hephaistos_flavour">"

Hephaistos, the god of fire, was also the master of smithing, sculpture and stone masonry, and therefore a good patron for mortal craftsmen of all kinds. Both volcanoes and forges were his responsibility, and the god was usually depicted with the humble tools of a blacksmith to hand. He was also depicted as being remarkably ugly and lame, but he had an arranged marriage to Aphrodite thanks to his father, Zeus, even though she strayed from the path of marital fidelity with monotonous regularity. The gods could be somewhat whimsical, at times. 

He was considered to be the Greek counterpart, or original, to the Roman god Vulcan, and was honoured by all sensible craft workers."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Fishing_port_flavour">"

Fish were a staple in ancient diets, and methods of fishing have changed relatively little over the centuries. Spearfishing, hook-and-line and nets date back to the Stone Age, and could support large communities. Cast nets were commonly used from coastal outcrops. These circular nets were weighted with stones around the edge, and had a drawstring that allowed the full net to be closed and hauled in. A complete contrast, in terms of effort expended,  was trapping: common types included woven baskets or nets for seafood, or fish weirs making use of tidal and river currents."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Subterrain_aqueduct_flavour">"

Subterranean tunnels were used to channel water from springs or rivers to settlements so that enemies could not tamper with the supply. Often with entrances and sources well concealed these aqueducts could not be blocked or poisoned, allowing Hellenic towns and cities to hold out for extended periods. 

Thanks to the way it was made, the Eupalinian aqueduct is famous: built in the 6th century BC, it connected the city of Samos to a hidden spring. It was just over 1km in length, and was dug from both ends at the same time, the digging teams meeting underground thanks to a superb grasp of geometry."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Villa_flavour">"

Land was a major commodity in the Roman world. The elite were quick to realise its value and began investing in farmland, hiring and exploiting slave labour to run their enterprises. New farms grew on the outskirts of Rome, with villas for landowners when they wished to visit. These villa “rustica” and their surrounding farmlands were the origins of the large agricultural estates or latifundium that came about when wealthy landowners took over peasant farms on a large scale. The idea of villa rustica also appealled to a Roman's idea of a simple, virtuous lifestyle. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Harbour_flavour">"

Any port needs a safe anchorage and a harbour where cargoes are manhandled onto ships. Greeks and Romans had different approaches: the Greeks adapted to the local environment, while Romans tended to bend nature to their wills. This is clear in their harbour designs. 

As the Roman Empire grew, harbours had to be built as disembarkation points, sometimes in areas where there was no natural inlet, bay or easy landing spot. In such cases Roman engineers set out to remake the coastline, and they created artificial harbours for their ships. Using wood, concrete and huge stone blocks, they built dams, piers, wharfs, sea walls and even artificial islands to protect harbours. Trajan’s extraordinary harbour at Centumcellae had a large basin dug into the shoreline of the River Tiber, all enclosed by huge walls. It was also connected by canal to Ostia further down the river."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Delicatessen_flavour">"

For a Roman, bread was a staple at every meal with some 50 varieties being noted by writers of the period. Breakfast was usually bread dipped in wine or oil with cheese, milk, eggs and olives. Meat was scarce and hardly ever eaten by the poor who relied more on fish complemented by radishes, pulses, turnips, leaks and porridge. 

Further up the social ladder, the richer citizens could enjoy a wide range of culinary delights. Spices from as far away as China found their way onto Roman tables and were used to flavour every kind of delicacy from peacock’s brains to stuffed dormice, flamingo tongues and parrot livers. Salads and fruits were widely consumed. 

Eating was at the heart of Roman social life, with dinner parties being a great way to show off to your friends. However, it became fashionable, not to say sensible, to employ a ""preagustator"" or food taster for meals with hosts you were not quite sure about..."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Farm_flavour">"

Outside of cities in the ancient world most people made a frugal living through agriculture. Major crops included cereals such as wheat and barley, fruits such as apples, plums, peaches, cherries and always olives wherever they could be grown. Most farms were family-owned businesses but as the cities grew so did demands on the available fertile land. 

Despite rising prices, it became difficult for small farmers to survive. Wealthy Romans bought up vast areas creating huge estates, or latifundia, to increase production. Slave labour was brought in and water was fed through irrigation ditches supplied by small reservoirs. The writer Pliny eventually complained that large-scale industrial farming ruined Italy and her provinces."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Light_horse_studs_flavour">"

Light cavalry was common in the armies of eastern states and steppe peoples. For all kinds of light horsemen, from the Aphraktoi to Scythian or Saka archers, speed was armour. They relied on the swiftness and stamina of their mounts, from majestic Persian horses to smaller and livelier Armenian breeds, and even dromedaries or Bactrian camels. Usually assigned to patrol trade routes and empty borderlands, and as scouts and flanking cavalry in times of war, such units were prized. 

In battle light cavalry was expected to harry the enemy with javelins or arrows, and withdraw quickly in the face of serious opposition. When their numbers were great enough, light cavalry could chase off opposing skirmishers, but would only closely engage other troops once they broke, driving them from the field and preventing them rallying."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Dockshed_flavour">"

Economic and military dominance relied not only land victories but also on control of the sea. An empire had to be able to outfit merchant vessels and warships, as well as keep contact with colonies and trading partners, if it was to thrive and grow. Warships, from patrolling biremes to colossal quinqueremes were vital in maintaining trade networks, and to moving and resupplying overseas expeditionary armies. 

In Carthage, following the Phoenician tradition, the docksheds of the fleet were improved by the construction of a great cothon. A protected harbour, the cothon was built to house and outfit 220 warships. It resembled a great wheel, with the slips facing inwards towards a central island housing the commander and administrative headquarters of the fleet, and it was a fine example of elegant and functional design."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Port_flavour">"

Ports were vital to the ever-growing Roman Empire. 

Rome's port of Ostia has been preserved for centuries; it was created in the 4th century BC as a military outpost to protect the mouth of the River Tiber. Later, the Emperor Claudius ingeniously developed it into the main landing for ships supplying the insatiable appetite of Rome. At its height, Ostia's 100,000 tradesmen, merchants and mariners kept Romans fed as reliably as the aqueducts gave them water. Warehouses, or horrea, stood full of grain arriving from Egypt, wine from Spain or spices from the east. There were even exotic animals destined for the arena. All had to be disembarked from the deep-hulled merchant ships, then transferred onto smaller lighters to be taken up the shallow Tiber and into Rome."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Muster_field_flavour">"

Drawing upon their citizens or subjects, supplemented by mercenaries, Hellenic states could quickly muster troops in times of war. Their generals were usually elected officials or chosen from amongst the nobility. In Athens, the military consisted of the ephebes undergoing training and the older male citizens, led by the ten elected strategoi, or war ministers. 

Originally these men would be hoplites but, following the pattern of Alexander the Great these developed into the hypaspists, phalangites and thureophoroi in the following centuries. This shift also saw a move to more professional and mercenary troops being used. Wealthier citizens, those able to afford horses, provided the hippeis, or light cavalry, while noble cavalry again followed the Alexandrian model. Mercenaries, such as the Thracians, the Scythian bow-armed police of Athens, or the Galatian royal guard of Cleopatra, would supplement these mustered forces."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Library_flavour">"

The Romans liked to think of themselves as less “bookish” than effete Greeks and Egyptians. However, their conquests of Greece, Macedonia, Asia Minor and other knowledgeable cultures did mean they were able to collect many texts to fill archives and private collections. This, along with their own scholarship, provided an invaluable source of research into history, culture, military tactics and technology. 

Books in a Roman library were mainly in Latin or Greek and, as in our modern libraries, covered all kinds of topics from politics and economics to agriculture and poetry. Books were extremely valuable in the ancient world due to their scarcity and because they were all hand copied, in the scriptoria of larger libraries. Statues of writers and decorative architecture often adorned the libraries making them memorial temples to wisdom and the written word."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Sacred_enclosure_flavour">"

The tribes of ancient Gaul, Britannia and Germania seldom constructed buildings to their gods, preferring to use natural boundaries like riverbanks, springs, lakes or tree groves to divide the everyday world from the spiritual realm. The oak was particularly sacred to the Celts, and oak groves were places of great importance where tribal matters were discussed and druids sought answers from the gods. The druids believed anything that grew on a sacred oak was a sign or gift from the gods and should be treated with great respect. Mistletoe was particularly considered powerful and was thought to be a cure for any known poison."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Harbour_flavour">"

Harbours were vital in the ancient world, offering a safe refuge from pirates and storms and a place for trade. Although most ships hugged the coastlines, loading and unloading goods needed a sheltered harbour. A natural bay would do, but the construction of docks and wharfs, and sheltering sea walls made sea-going life much easier. Harbours were colossal undertakings, but the long-term benefits far outweighed the labour and costs involved."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_City_flavour">"

Even in the ancient world, cities grew up in places where people had already been living for a long time because the sites were defensible, controlled river crossings, had natural resources nearby or were safe from floods and other natural disasters. 

Cities, despite their rulers’ best intentions, were rarely planned. There might be sections where public buildings stood by broad, open streets and temples were laid out in magnificent splendour, and patrician dwellings hid rich opulence behind bland frontages. But equally likely, if you walked a few paces in the wrong direction, you would be guaranteed to find a maze of twisty backstreets, cheek-by-jowl houses, and run-down slums, alehouses, whorehouses and slaughterhouses, all jostling for what little space there was within the walls. 

The city was the world in miniature, with all the wonder and squalor that implied. Romans and Greeks equally could take civic pride in their urbanity and sophistication, and at the same moment be a little disgusted by the dirt and tawdriness of the back streets only yards away."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Combat_posts_flavour">"

""I shall not bring dishonour on my sacred arms nor shall I abandon my comrade wherever I shall be stationed..."" And so begins the Ephebic oath sworn by all young male Athenians at their induction into the college that would forge them into citizens. Honour in battle was important to Hellenistic cultures and, as the gods watched, it was not whether you won but how you fought that marked you in the gods' sight. Excessive pride, or hubris, was a crime in many states, so boasting about good behaviour had its limits! 

The infantry was at the heart of any Greek-style army and fitness was part of basic military training. Having sworn their allegiance, soldiers had to be prepared to fight anywhere. Service in the army was an honour and great pride was taken in upholding Greek culture: ""I shall not leave my city any less when I die but greater than when I was born!"""</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Range_flavour">"

Although a proud people the Romans were never too arrogant to learn from others, particularly where war was concerned. After suffering devastating losses at the hands of expert foreign archers, particularly the Parthians, they decided to enlist large numbers of “sagittarii” as auxiliaries. 

In the east, they even borrowed the same design of composite bow, tipped with horn and bound with animal sinew, from their foreign rivals. Cretan, Syrian, Thracian and Balearic archers joined the infantry auxilia. A Doctor Saggitariorum, a Master of the Bow, was the title given to the chief trainer of recruits. Later, mounted archers were recruited from eastern provinces where the locals specialised in this deadly form of warfare."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Military_wharf_flavour">"

All states built their navies to safeguard their merchants' vital trade across the Mediterranean. 

The Carthaginians were the most daring seafarers of the ancient world, and preferred to hire mercenaries for their land battles while concentrating on commanding a huge fleet of ever-greater ships. As Carthaginian trade and the need to transport troops increased so did the importance of sea control. They built vast war galleys manned by citizen rowers. Alongside Greek-style triremes they built quinqueremes (""fives"") and septiremes (""sevens"") reinforced for ramming. Even so, the largest ship of the ancient world was the Syracusia designed by Archimedes and built in 240BC by King Hieron II. It used some 60 times the resources needed for an average trireme and took 300 skilled workmen over a year to build."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Sacred_Grove_flavour">"

The Romans had many words for woods but “lucus” was reserved for a sacred grove, a circular garden of trees used for prayer, worship, contemplation and remembrance. Trees were planted as a memorial to the dead or dedicated to a particular local deity. The grove was an outdoor temple and a connection between humans, nature and divinity. They were also sometimes home to statues, shrines and even the tombs of loved ones. Augustus, for example, planted a grove to commemorate the loss of his two grandchildren. Found throughout the Empire, groves were an important part of the religious landscape where rituals could be carried out. A famous grove of oak trees was used by the Vestal Virgins of Rome until it was burned to the ground in the Great Fire of 64AD."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Grove_of_andraste_flavour">"

Andraste was a warrior goddess and the patron of the Iceni tribe. Accounts written by Dio Cassius talk of a pre-battle ritual performed by the queen of the Iceni, Boudicca, during her war against the Roman occupation of Britannia. After encouraging her people to stand against the invaders, Boudicca released a hare from the folds of her dress. The crowd waited with bated breath to see the direction in which the animal ran, as it would predict the outcome of battle. On this occasion the omens were good, and Boudicca thanked the goddess Andraste for watching over her people in their time of need. The Romans eventually associated this powerful local deity with their goddess of victory, Victoria."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Hadast_flavour">"

A hadast or city was often established over centuries building on, or borrowing from, the remains of older cultures, and incorporating them into the new whole. They were often positioned to control, defend and exploit resources, fresh water, river crossings and natural ports, trade routes, or to take advantage of defensible hills or spurs of land. 

Rarely was an entirely new city founded: Carthage was the most famous and called ""Qart-hadast"" which means only ""new city"". Supposedly founded by Phoenician colonists led by the Queen Dido, Carthage rose to power following Tyre’s collapse and the end of Phoenician power. Its position on the Mediterranean coast, and proximity to Sicily, gave it powerful command of maritime trade."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Public_Forum_flavour">"

The forum was the beating heart of any Roman community. Originally an open market, the forum developed from selling spaces to become the theatre for all important civic business: oration, gladiatorial contests, games, trials, executions and triumphant processions by returning armies. They were even used for elections. 

The Roman Forum was built on drained marshland in one of the oldest sections of the city. It grew into a hive of bustling trade with several huge buildings surrounding the public square. Government offices stood alongside cattle markets as the whole of Roman society rubbed shoulders as they traded, debated and socialised. Everywhere the Romans went they built new forums as essential meeting places and centres of commerce."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Brick_maker_flavour">"

There were two main techniques of brick making in the ancient world. The old fashioned way was to make sun-dried moulded mud or clay bricks of various sizes. This was developed in Asia Minor around 7500BC and then used across Greece and Egypt. However drying in the sun caused problems with the final product. It was best done in spring and autumn, as during summer bricks would dry too quickly on the outside, but not the inside, giving little strength. Sun drying also took time; some preferred their bricks to be at least five years old before they were put to use. The more advanced method of kiln baking was developed later. Baked bricks, or testa, found in Greek and Egyptian lands are usually dated after the Roman conquest. In fact, prior to being conquered the Greeks maintained the use of stone for city walls and major buildings; brick was mainly only used for the houses of the poorer classes."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Shrine_of_zeus_ammon_flavour">"

Zeus Ammon was a joining together of three gods in one. Amun was originally a deity in Thebes, who was eventually seen as being one with the ancient sun-god Ra, the two becoming Amun-Ra. To the Greek colonists in Egypt, Amun-Ra was an aspect of Zeus, or “Zeus Ammon”. As such, he was worshipped across the Greek world, even as far away as Sparta and some Libyan colonies. 

Alexander the Great was seen as the liberator of Egypt, and was heralded as the “son of Amun” by the oracle of the Siwa oasis, thanks to his victory over the Achaemenids at the Battle of Issus in 333BC. He publicly acknowledged his own divine status and called Zeus Ammon his father, a useful bit of propaganda for any world conqueror. The tradition of divine descent was well established for Pharaohs, and Alexander’s Ptolemaic successors kept the claim as an aid to their own legitimacy."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Herding_ground_flavour">"

Animal husbandry was important in the Hellenic world, as both manufacturing and trade increased. Animals such as goats and sheep were the most common livestock, but cattle were reared where resources and land would permit. Cattle were prized not simply for their meat, but as beasts of burden and for their hides. 

 In contrast, horses were highly valued as mounts and their breeding was limited to the nobility and wealthy landowners that could afford to set aside land. Thessaly, with its ample plains, was well regarded for its horses; Thessalian cavalry had a proven reputation in Alexander the Great's army."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Shrine_of_eshmun_flavour">"

Principally worshipped as a healing deity, Eshmun was also a protector and the guardian of the Phoenician city of Sidon. He was also associated with spring and the renewal of life. Temples to Eshmun, such as the great complex near Sidon, had stone water channels and great basins to allow worshippers to carry out purifying ablutions before any rites. Votive offerings were left in the cisterns and pools as thanks for the gift of healing or in the hope of securing Eshmun’s favour. 

The story of Eshmun’s origin is a little gory, and gentlemen of a nervous disposition should look away now. 

Eshmun was originally a mortal man, and his beauty captivated and entranced the goddess Astarte. She pursued him relentlessly, determined to take him as a lover. In order to escape her advances, and in a rather permanent way, Eshmun castrated himself. With an axe. Unfortunately for all concerned, he died from the wound. The grief-stricken Astarte brought him back from the dead, and made him a god, so his axe work didn’t have the desired outcome after all."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Outskirts_flavour">"

With settled populations growing, and the demands for farmable land increasing, nomadic tribesmen were forced to abandon their wanderings. Staying in one place meant that farming and husbandry skills had to change and develop. Communities had to unite to build and maintain irrigation systems, allowing settled farmers to use their land, now their property, to the fullest even after the seasonal rains had gone. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Manipular_Barracks_flavour">"

The greatness of Rome's army lay in training, tactics and the spirit of the people. 

Before the Second Samnite War in 315BC the Romans fought as a phalanx. As the Romans suffered heavy defeats on difficult terrain a more maneuverable maniple system was adapted from the Samnites' tactics. Three divisions replaced the phalanx in battle: the young hastati in the front, the experienced principes as the main line and lastly the veteran triarii at the rear. 

This tactical system served Rome well until new enemies and new economic realities weakened it. Consul Gaius Marius made dramatic changes when he reformed the whole Roman army, creating what is now seen as the ""classic"" Roman Legion as the basic battle force. His system proved extremely effective and was adopted by successive generations of leaders. It was the Marian legions that went on to conquer the known world..."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Levy_camp_flavour">"

After the age of heroes, when fighting had been about individual valour and battles a brawl rather than a planned encounter, armies were organised into disciplined units. With conflicts between the city-states on the rise, and threats from the outside world, the Greeks created the first hoplites around 700BC. These were free citizens, fighting as infantry who provided their own armour and weapons. There was no standard equipment and these soldiers carried shields and armour emblazoned with family symbols handed down over generations. However, the name of hoplite derived from the one piece of equipment they did have in common: the hoplon shield. This circular shield was held so as to protect not only the bearer but also the man to his left. As a mass, hoplite then moved in the famous phalanx formation, marching towards the enemy as one solid wall."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Shrine_of_isis_flavour">"

Isis is a mother and wife goddess: wife to Osiris, ruler of the dead, and mother of Horus, the god of the sky and war. Hers is a tragic story, with her husband brutally murdered and dismembered by his brother Set, but ultimately triumphant as she brings her beloved Osiris mostly back from the dead. As an agent of rebirth and mother, she was a goddess of both fertility and protection; many revered her as a patron. 

Under the Ptolemaic dynasty and later, under Roman occupation, the cult of Isis thrived. This partly stemmed from the belief that it was her tears for the fallen Osiris that caused the Nile to rise with such reliable regularity. Her greatest temples were located in the Nile delta and at the island complex of Philae, although the cult later spread through the Roman Mediterranean. It is also possible to perceive a distant echo of Isis and her son Horus in some highly stylised portrayals of the Virgin Mary and baby Jesus. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shrine_of_zeus_flavour">"

After the Titan Cronus was overthrown by his children Zeus, Hades and Poseidon, the three usurpers drew lots to divide up the spoils of the universe. Poseidon was given mastery of the seas; Hades received the underworld; Zeus gained control of the sky and the air. The earth, Gaia, was to be shared but Zeus was made King of the Gods on Olympus. 

Much mortal effort was put into honouring Zeus, and he had more than 150 epithets to describe his powers and responsibilities. He was the Thunderer, for example, who controlled storms and lightning. It was a foolish man indeed who got on the wrong side of Zeus and risked destruction. 

On the other hand, many were desperate to claim a connection to him. Despite his marriage to Hera, Zeus fathered many children with other goddesses and mortals, the most famous being Herakles. It was quite the fashion for Hellenic ruling houses to claim partial divinity by descent from one of Zeus’ many bastards or, preferably, Herakles."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Recruiting_ground_flavour">"

In eastern Hellenistic states there was a limit to the number of Greek recruits available, and so local populations and mercenaries were used. After Alexander, leaders valued quantity over quality and some amassed huge armies of up to 70,000 men with only a small portion of Greek origin. Further west, Hellenistic states were caught up in conflicts that depleted numbers, making mercenaries essential to continued warfare. In 227BC Cleomenes III of Sparta made five thousand free men citizens and allowed some slaves to buy their freedom so that he had more potential recruits. When Philip V of Macedon suffered huge losses he chose to reorganise his kingdom. During peace, he redistributed the population and was able to leave a large army to his son, Perseus. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Wrestling_arena_flavour">"

Wrestling is a very old sport and popular in Persian, Indian and Hellenic cultures, although rules and styles do vary. Wrestling bouts could be held almost anywhere, but as the sport developed specialist arenas with earth or sand floors and galleries for spectators became popular. 

One of the earliest depictions of wrestling is a Neolithic cave painting from the Bayankhongor Province of Mongolia showing two naked men wrestling watched by onlookers. Centuries later, Greek wrestling became popular as part of the ancient Olympiad, and would eventually be absorbed into Roman culture, and taken across the ancient world by Alexander and his armies."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Hamlet_flavour">"

Based on agriculture, fishing, trade, or mining small communities supported the growth of Greek city-states and the later Hellenic empires, providing every raw material needed. Villages only happen where there is something worth exploiting, and the best placed ones soon grow into larger towns. 

In the Greek world, such settlements could be as varied as the hamlets of the Spartan perioikoi, who helped keep the helots slave inside the state and acted as intermediaries with the outside world, to the ""thousand golden cities"" of Bactria which thrived on agriculture and flourishing trade in Asia Minor."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Grove_of_gobannus_flavour">"

Gobannus was the Celtic god of smiths and held a high place in the Celtic pantheon. Smiths were thought to possess Otherworldly powers because of their work with fire and metal, so it is not surprising that their patron was also held in high regard. Depictions of Gobannus found in Britain show a bearded man wearing a belted tunic and conical cap, standing over his anvil with a pair of tongs in one hand and hammer in the other. Perhaps the most famous record of this smith god is also a testament to the skill of those who worshipped him. The Bern zinc tablet, found in Bern, Switzerland, was seen as a forgery for many years but it was eventually discovered that the tablet was in fact not zinc but an alloy of the metals which collected on the walls of furnaces."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Slave_trader_flavour">"

Slaves were an everyday, accepted part of Hellenistic society and were found everywhere. They did everything from backbreaking labour in fields and mines to managing treasury accounts. In the 5th century BC it is believed there was one slave for every free man in ""democratic"" Athens. Even free people on a modest living had at least one slave for menial tasks. 

Slaves were the lifeblood of the Hellenistic economy and the slave trade was seen as perfectly necessary and justified. Most slaves were taken in wartime while others were born into slavery, especially in Egypt. However, neither appearance or skin colour was the mark of a slave. Anyone could be a slave, even a fellow Greek from a different city. Many slaves were simply bought from traders who had acquired them in other distant countries. Prices varied enormously with young, healthy, and attractive slaves fetching up to twenty times more than older weaker ones."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Shrine_of_serapis_flavour">"

Serapis was an attempt to blend Egyptian and Greek culture under one joint deity, a deliberate act by Ptolemy I Soter. Serapis, a god of abundance and resurrection, was Greek in appearance but with a complete associated Egyptian symbology: the god had a modius, as his headdress, resembling a standard measuring basket of grain. It is possible that Serapis was a local god of Rhakotis, the settlement that became Alexandria, or the Babylonian Ea, as consulted by Alexander. 

Ptolemy III built the Serapeum of Alexandria, the greatest temple of Serapis in Egypt. The large complex even included part of the Library of Alexandria. The Serapeum was eventually destroyed during disturbances between Christians and pagans in 391AD."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Fire_alter_flavour">"

In the East, fire as well as water was a symbol of purity, and banished dark and chaotic forces from the world. Zoroastrianism, which greatly influenced later monotheistic faiths, had temples that housed atar, or holy fire. 

Even earlier, there had been a reverence for hearth fire as the source of warmth, light and food. Holy shrines and temples began as raised mounds on which fires were lit and offerings were made. In Zoroastrianism, Ahura Mazda, the force of wisdom and truth, was opposed by Angra Mainyu, the destructive spirit of chaos. Ahura Mazda's fire kept chaos at bay, and played a part in divination and oracular predictions. The priests would interpret the flames, or would burn a variety of spices and other substances, inhaling the smoke to make contact with the world beyond."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Royal_sanctuary_flavour">"

Veneration of ancestors and the worship of royalty, living and dead, were commonplace throughout the ancient world. The details varied, with ancestors being worshipped almost as household Gods, to temple complexes and great tombs being constructed in remembrance of powerful rulers. 

Interment of kings and rulers was common. In Persian traditions, bodies could be placed in stone monuments, such as the tomb of Cyrus the Great at Pasargadae. Rock monuments and tombs, which housed Achaemenid rulers such as Darius the Great, dominated their landscapes. The point of these great structures, however, was always the same: a clear and simple reminder to ordinary people that their rulers were powerful and had a history of being powerful. The dead were intended to be ""awe-full""."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Blacksmith_flavour">"

Smithing defines the arrival of the Bronze and Iron Ages, and blacksmiths could be found in almost every town and city, even in the developed world, until relatively recent times. Iron was beaten into shape for nails, knives, tools and, of course, weapons. 

A good blacksmith could turn his hand to anything, but as Rome's need for manufactured goods grew, there was a degree of specialisation in large-scale craft work. Lots of small-scale forges in the same place were able to turn out large amounts of reasonably standard iron goods. However, with slaves being so plentiful, the Romans never had the incentive to mechanize and use water-driven power tools, the first step towards an industrial revolution."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Blacksmith_flavour">"

Blacksmiths were held in high regard in Celtic society. They were considered to be the equal in status to the druids and other higher members of society. This was thanks to their ability to work magic with fire and metal. Each of the tribes of Europe had their own god of smiths, but all shared an association with fire and its power. Much like the Greek god Hephaestus, Gobannus, the Celtic patron of smiths is depicted as a powerful, bearded man who carries a hammer. In Irish myth the smith god appears in a trinity as, Goibhniu, Luchta and Credhne. Goibhniu was the smith, Luchta the wright and Credhne the metalworker; when their talents combined they produced powerful weapons and beautiful artefacts, the likes of which had never been seen by mortals."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Muster_Field_flavour">"

Serving in the Roman Legions was originally part of the duties of a property-owning citizen. Slaves, freedmen and criminals were never given arms. The Citizen Legions would be called up to serve for a campaign season. They were a militia who needed some training before battle. They were deployed as hoplites, fighting in Greek style as a phalanx. 

Over time, the military system evolved with the introduction of the manipular system and then the later Marian reforms. The end result was a professional force; by the 1st century BC citizens joined the legions as a job for life. The need to keep the army and its commanders busy and away from Roman politics must have influenced Rome's permanent interest in conquest and expansionism!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Farm_flavour">"

The cultivation of land in a hot climate around the Mediterranean was not always easy. Irrigation and crop rotation were used in Greece, especially where the soil fertility was poor and farmland uncommon. Terracing allowed for small fields to be created on the steep hillsides of islands and valleys. Olives, figs and grapes were grown everywhere. Honey was very important as a delicacy because it was seen as a connection with the gods. Bread was the staple of the diet with up to seventy different types known: it was made from wheat or barley. Barley was preferred because it was less demanding to grow and more productive than wheat. Animals were kept but meat was mainly only consumed at festival times. Greeks also associated meat eating with nomads and barbaric cultures, while civilised people tamed and then ate nature. Animals were also more useful alive: oxen were beasts of burden, and goats were kept for milk and cheese."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Port_flavour">"

For all those states bordering the Mediterranean it was vital to command the seas around their land. Any people wishing to expand looked to control trade routes and invade other countries by sea. It was far easier to sail 1000 km than march a tenth of the distance.  Good ports were the key and became the hub where shipbuilding yards were found cheek-by-jowl with markets, naval garrisons and countless sea-based trades. The port that served Athens, Piraeus, was described by Aristophanes as a hectic, bustling concoction of sailors clamouring for pay, rations being served out, men trafficking for corn, onions, leeks, figs, all to the sound of the hammering of the dock yards, and boatswains’ pipes and flutes. Carthage made its wealth and name through its two artificial harbours, and Alexandria in Egypt was one of the largest city ports of the ancient world."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Majore_field_flavour">"

Majore, was a sport similar in concept to rugby but using a solid wooden ball. It had been a popular game since the Bronze Age in Mesopotamia, and spread throughout the region over the following centuries. 

Games such as majore, along with boxing and wrestling, were accessible to all people, and these communal games were an important to society. They not only entertained people but also glorified the rulers and patron gods."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Tophet_flavour">"

This vast children's cemetery was a field of urns estimated to have been used for at least 20,000 interments. It was named by modern-day archaeologists in reference to the place when Canaanites sacrificed their children in the Valley of Hinnom, as mentioned in the Old Testament. There is no way of telling whether the Carthaginians followed the same rites; some Greek and Roman writers vilify the Carthaginians for practicing child sacrifice, but this may be propaganda. 

It is difficult to tell from the existing remains whether or not the children and youths died to natural causes or were sacrificed. According to the accounts that talk of human sacrifice, children were hurled into sacred fires as offering to Ba'al Hammon. Those sent to the flames included the children of the wealthy and powerful, for what was given up had to be valuable for the sacrifice to be valid."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Amphora_Maker_flavour">"

As with many other items, the Romans took the basic design of the amphora from the Greeks. Terracotta amphorae were vase-shaped containers usually lined with a resin to make them watertight and all had two handles attached to the neck. They were used to store and transport everything from wine and olive oil to cereals and salt, and made by the thousand. In fact, they were so plentiful that after their contents had been used they were usually smashed rather than kept or returned. Many different types of amphorae have been found, but the standard wine amphora held around forty litres. They were crucial to trade across the Empire and thousands have been found intact at the bottom of the Mediterranean thanks to shipwrecks and a watery end to their travels!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Combat_Posts_flavour">"

Combat training began with simple weapon exercises using wooden swords and spears against large posts driven into the ground. Recruits were also paired up, as in gladiator schools, and taught close-quarter fighting with weighted weapons. The legionary would take up a modern boxer’s stance and learn to thrust and jab forward while protecting himself with the shield. 

Once they had proved themselves with training weapons, legionaries were fully equipped and instructed in formation tactics. Drill halls, or basilica exertoria, were built so that training could continue during the winter months. Unlucky recruits, or those on punishment, would just have to train outside in all weathers!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Shrine_of_imhotep_flavour">"

The cult of Imhotep began some two thousand years after his death when he was deified as the patron of healing and medicine because of his legendary skill and wisdom. Originally from Memphis, the cult eventually merged with the worshippers of Thoth, the learning, medicine and architecture. In some places the two were treated as brother gods. 

During his lifetime, Imhotep rose from humble origins to be High Priest of Ra and chancellor to Netjerikhet, or Djoser, the founder of the Third Dynasty. He lived during the 27th century BC, a time that was impossibly remote, even in the time of the Ptolemaic pharaohs. He was the foremost architect, engineer, philosopher and physician of his age and, not surprisingly, one of the first of each in recorded history."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Horse_pens">"

Horses played an important role in Celtic society, both spiritually and practically. Many Roman writers freely admitted that the Celts were excellent horsemen, and they went as far as calling Celtic mercenaries the best cavalry in the Roman army. The Romans even adopted a Celtic deity in the hope that she would bestow the equine knowledge and skill of the Celts upon Rome. Epona is one of very few deities to be accepted into the Roman pantheon without change, although her role did develop over time. Eventually, she provided protection of all those who worked with horses and not just the animals themselves. She was a popular deity among the Roman cavalry, and her cult spread across Europe wherever the Romans had cavalry garrisons."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Levy_camp_flavour">"

Levies could be quickly mustered, outfitted and turned into an army whether the men were citizens or subjects. Usually commanded by nobles or local dignitaries, levies supplemented elite units such as the nobility and professional soldiers. Parthian armies, for example, were created by command of the King, who ordered his subordinates to muster troops and gather at an appointed time and place. These subordinates would then bring their noble households, attendant warriors, and hamspah, or levies. 

Over time there was a gradual move away from citizen and subject recruits to a professional standing army in the Hellenic world. These professionals and mercenaries were the same men as the earlier levies, but would see the army as a career rather than as a duty. In turn, this opened the way for promotion on merit rather than birth, creating armies loyal to generals rather than the old social order."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Brine_distiller_flavour">"

Salt was a valuable commodity that many tribes traded with the Greeks and Romans. Archaeologists are able to identify areas of high salt production by the presence of a refuse deposit known as briquetage. Ancient salt production started with pottery vessels; brine was added to these and allowed to dry out and form salt cakes. These pots were then smashed to release the salt cake, resulting in large quantities of pottery shards or ""briquetage"". A recent discovery at the Poiana Slatinei archaeological site, next to a salt spring in Lunca, Romania, suggest that the Neolithic inhabitants of the area were boiling the salt-laden spring water to extract the salt as far back as 6050BC, making it the oldest known salt works in the world."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Monument_of_leonidas_flavour">"

King Leonidas was the Spartan's Spartan. In 480 BC, he led 300 hoplites, his personal guard, north to the pass of Thermopylae, to fight a mighty Persian army under Xerxes. Leonidas could bring no more men, because a sacred festival would not allow the Spartans to go to war. Xerxes had, seemingly, brought everyone in the east against the Greeks. Although in his sixties, Leonidas personally led the defence of the narrow pass and held for two days before his force was betrayed and cut down from the rear. The Persians killed everyone and mutilated the body of Leonidas. His defence, however, bought time and that time gave the Greeks the eventual victory. Leonidas' heroics were the epitome of being Spartan, and 40 years later his remains were exhumed and the “Leonidaeum”, a monumental shrine, was built to inspire all those who looked upon it."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Enclosed_land_flavour">"

Enclosing land allowed farmers to keep a better watch on their herds and flocks. The construction of wooden fences and banks of earth also served to keep intruders and wild animals away from livestock. It is thought that some Celtic farmers valued their stock so highly they allowed them to sleep inside their homes at night to make doubly sure that no harm would come to them. More practically, this is also a good way of keeping warm. As Celtic society progressed and the population increased, large fortified settlements sprang up all over Europe. Many of these settlements had separate enclosures that historians have linked with the keeping of livestock. During times of war it is thought that the animals would have been driven between the inner and outer defences of a hill fort, protecting them from attackers while maintaining them as a fresh food source for the defenders."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Clay_pit_flavour">"

The tribes of ancient Europe kept very few written records, so much of what we know of their way of life comes from archaeological discoveries. For example, we know that the ancient Celts fired pots in kilns that allowed air, or rather oxygen, to be introduced, thus allowing the potter to control the colour of his work. It is clear from later finds that potters learnt that the introduction of liquid to the clay, before firing, could also affect its colour, and this led to new and more complicated patterns emerging. The differences in pattern design also reveals the differences between each of the tribes. Pottery discovered in Gaul and Briton tends to favour elaborate scenes of hunting, sports or deities compared to the more basic patterns found in other areas of Europe."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Grain_market_flavour">"

Grain was the most important crop for human and animal consumption. Wheat, millet and barley were the staple crops. The Greeks struggled with grain production because of their poor soil and limited land area for agriculture, so trade in grain was essential. In Piraeus, Athens' port, grain would arrive by boat and be held in the Deigma on the famous colonnaded Makra Stoa. Merchants could inspect samples, or deigmata, of the imported crops on stalls made of reeds. It was a hot and dusty place teeming with bustling activity from dawn until dusk."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Acropolis_flavour">"

Acropolis means “the top of the city”, and is used to describe a collection of important buildings on a hill or elevated land within the city walls. This was a common feature of many ancient cities, though now the Athens acropolis is the most famous. In Athens the site was used as early as the 14th century BC for the Mycenaean Royal Palace. Later it was converted into a place of sacred significance, and by the 6th century BC, it was dotted with temples and monuments. These were destroyed by the Persian invasion in 480BC. Under Perikles, some 30 years later, the Acropolis regained its majesty when the Parthenon was constructed."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Grove_of_cenunnos_flavour">"

Images of the god Cernunnos, or the ""Horned One"", have been found dating back to the 4th century BC.  Most commonly depicted as an antlered man sitting cross legged, some historians have argued that the antlers mark Cernunnos as an animal deity. His depiction on the famous Gundestrup Cauldron would certainly support this theory as he is shown surrounded by animals. Other historians, however, see him simply as a god of nature or a fertility symbol. He often appears wearing a torc around his neck, round his antlers or simply held in one hand. Torcs were a symbol of high status and this may possibly be traced back to their association with the immortal Cernunnos."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Woodworker_flavour">"

Although wood was the main building material for most of the tribes of Europe, each developed their own construction techniques depending on what was available. Some even developed techniques that allowed them to build in areas that should have been considered uninhabitable. The tribes of Ireland and Scotland built homes in rivers and lakes: manmade islands, or crannogs, provided their occupants with protection against attacks from men and beasts. The construction of the island involved wooden piles to create a sturdy base, in a circle to minimise erosion. They were often reached by wooden gangways and had traditional wooden roundhouses at their centre."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Shrine_of_hathor_and_maat_flavour">"

Hathor and Maat were widely worshipped under the Ptolemaic dynasty. Hathor was the goddess of birth, joy, love and motherhood and, for women, the promise of eternal life. She was often depicted with a cow’s head, but she was also a sky goddess and linked to the Milky Way of the night sky. Maat, on the other hand, dealt with the fate of the soul after death, as she weighed the hearts of the dead against the feather of truth in Duat, the Egyptian underworld. She was a personification of order: truth, law and justice were under her influence, and also the movement of the heavens and the seasons. 

The temple complex to Hathor and Maat on the West Bank at Thebes was extensively rebuilt by Ptolemy IV Philopator during his reign (221-205BC). Many depictions of the last pharaohs include emblems of Hathor and Maat to emphasise the justice and order they bring to the world. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Herding_ground_flavour">"

Agriculture and animal husbandry, alongside trade and manufacturing of goods and textiles, were vitally important to the Carthaginian economy. Herds of goats, sheep and oxen required large grazing areas and access to precious water. 

Mago, a Carthaginian writer, documented many of his people’s agricultural practices and, although his works no longer survive, they were taken back to Rome after the destruction of Carthage and translated into Greek and Latin. According to later commentators, his work deals with many farming practices including how to select bullocks and maintain the health of cattle, as well as how to collect bees from the carcass of a bull or ox."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Homestead_flavour">"

Most Greeks lived off the land, even in the ""city-states"". They lived and worked in largely self-sufficient homesteads growing barley, olives and figs, and herding sheep and goats. Life for a Greek farmer was harsh: good agricultural land was scarce, and rich landlords bought the best plots. The climate did not help much either: regular and rigorous ploughing was the only method of retaining the soil’s moisture following autumn's rains. This life bred hardy individuals, and freemen were often the best fighters in hoplite armies. Not only were they strong physical specimens, but they were well-motiviated to defend their farmlands!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Shrine_of_kore_flavour">"

The cult of Kore began in 396BC in Carthage, as a measure to appease the goddess. One of her temples had been sacked by a Carthaginian army in Sicily, and shortly afterwards a devastating plague had swept through the soldiers. The Carthaginians quickly realised that two and two did equal four, and began to honour the goddess themselves to turn aside her further wrath. 

Kore, or Persephone, was the daughter of Zeus and Demeter and was associated with the coming of spring and the renewal of growth. The Hellenic Persephone was supposed to spend six months of every year in the underworld as the consort of Hades. This brought about autumn and winter in the mortal world. Kore was similarly associated with Melqart, and so influenced the seasonal turning of the year. Her cult may also have adopted some of the rites of the Eleusinian mysteries but the exact details remain, as one would expect, suitably mysterious!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shrine_of_ares_flavour">"

Ares was a bloody god, a god of rage, brutality, and lust for battle. All of these were vital qualities for a warrior, but they were also dangerous and Ares, for all his status as one of the 12 Olympians, was a god of chaos, to be placated and feared as well as worshipped. His own divine parents, Zeus and Hera, were not fond of him and his destructive ways. Despite all his rough and rowdy qualities, Ares was accounted handsome, and Aphrodite, the goddess of love, fell for his charms. When she took a new lover, Adonis, as was inevitably going to be the case, Ares turned Adonis into a boar and slaughtered him in a jealous rage. Even his children, Phobos and Deimos, Fear and Terror, inherit his terrifying nature. 

For mortals, Ares is a bloody-handed god of fighting, where Athena is a goddess of strategic warfare. Both are necessary, and a wise man looked to both in times of danger. At the temple of Ares Enyalios Spartan youths sacrificed dogs to Ares in the hope of gaining his favour and courage."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Ludus_Magnus_flavour">"

The Ludus Magnus was the greatest of the four gladiatorial training schools in Rome. It included 130 cells and trained 20 different types of fighter as they learned combat skills and endured rigorous exercises. Here men could specialise in fighting with horse and sword, war chariot, lasso, net and spear as well as the standard sword and shield combinations. 

As well as learning how to fight, the gladiators had to learn how to die. Spectators expected a brave and honourable death. A gladiator could never show any sign of fear, not even in his final moments. As many as 3,000 adoring fans could watch gladiatorial matches from the stands, in much the same way as people visit football grounds today. A short walk along a tunnel from the Ludus Magnus brought fighters to the Colosseum next door where death and glory awaited."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Grove_of_tuotatis_flavour">"

Toutatis was a tribal protector, worshiped in Gaul and Britannia. He was one of the three Celtic deities that Lucan, the Roman writer, associated with human sacrifice. Lucan claimed that those sacrificed to Toutatis were drowned in a vat of liquid that might have been ale. Inscriptions to Toutatis have been found in Rome, Austria and Britain. Some historians even argue that a figure represented on the Gundestrup Cauldron could be a representation of Toutatis. A man is shown dipping a figure into a cauldron or vat, echoing the sacrificial offerings made to the god. However, it is also suggested that this image could just as easily represent the cauldron of regeneration, into which dead warriors would be thrown to be reborn as mutes."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Grove_of_rosmerta_flavour">"

Rosmerta or ""The Great Provider"" was a Celtic goddess of fertility and plenty. She was represented holding fruit or a cornucopia, clear symbols of her aspect as a goddess of plenty. Images of Rosmerta have been found in France, Germany and Luxembourg, and many show her beside the Roman god Mercury or even wearing his winged helm suggesting that she was seen as his consort by the Romans. A relief found in Wasserbillig, Luxembourg also hints that Rosmerta may have had a healing aspect, as an offering to her carries an inscription relating to the opening of a hospital."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Cloaca_Maxima_flavour">"The Cloaca Maxima was the large central sewer in Rome. Even today, parts of the Cloaca Maxima are used to drain rainwater from the modern city. 

Originally an open canal built by the Etruscans in the 6th century BC, the Romans built over the waterway as the population grew. Water came into Rome via the aqueducts and then passed through the fountains, palaces, baths and latrines down into several tributary drains. These emptied into the Cloaca Maxima before all the waste of Rome went into the River Tiber and finally out to sea. Private houses had their own sewage systems in chamber pots and cess pits! This highly sophisticated drainage scheme had its own deity to watch over it: the goddess Cloacina ensured a clean city above."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Polo_pitch_flavour">"

Although its exact origins are lost, polo was one of the dominant sports of antiquity in the east. Popular in Arabic, Byzantine, Persian and Chinese cultures, it was seen as a means to practice and demonstrate horsemanship and many battle skills. 

A game only needed a flat field, but over time permanent pitches developed where teams could train and play. Little is known about the early rules of the game except that points were scored by taking the ball from one end of the field to the other. This fits with the game's association with battle; riders may well have been allowed to strike or unhorse their opponents without penalty."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Brickmaker_flavour">"

After the Romans came, saw and conquered they generally built. Having developed brick production in Italy, they tended to build in the style of their home towns. Romans used brickwork in every public and private building, putting fine stone cladding only on the outside. It was a huge step forward from using wood and thatch, wattle and daub or massive stonework. Construction was quick and relatively easy. Above all, the bricks used for walls and the tiles used for roofing were strong and durable. 

The Roman army was largely responsible for spreading the use of brickwork throughout the Empire with their kilns, often stamping the bricks with a legion’s mark. The skill was passed on to local peoples and so became the standard building method in many lands for centuries."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Horse_Corral_flavour">"

Horses enjoyed a respected position in Roman society. Bred and kept for the great sport of racing, religious sacrifice and noble military service, they were less of the working animal they became in later cultures if only because of their cost. Horses were rarely used on farms other than when their sacrificial blood was given to purify other livestock or their heads were nailed to a farm wall in hope of a harvest blessing! 

It was claimed that Romulus himself had a personal guard of 300 horsemen. Roman cavalry was, at first, made up of the richer classes, the equestrians or ""riding class"", who could pay for their own mounts. Later, the sense of being an elite was maintained as the upper classes were favoured, and they were paid three times as much as foot soldiers. As the Empire grew, Gallic, Numidian, Spanish and Thracian horsemen were added to the ranks. The cavalry was used to scout, carry messages and, in battle, to charge, flank an enemy quickly and gain advantage at critical moments."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Slave_Trader_flavour">"

At the height of the Roman Empire, slaves were a quarter of Italy’s six million population; in Rome every third person was a slave. The slave trade was essential to Roman society as human muscle power did everything from quarrying and mining to farming and building. Slavery was a huge business and criminals, POWs and those simply abducted from their homelands were sold for their labour. Once enslaved, the unlucky individual had no rights under Roman law. 

The biggest market was the Graecostadium in Rome, originally specialising in the trade of Greek prisoners. Domestic servants, field hands, quarrymen, gladiators and harlots were all traded flesh from as far afield as Britain, Parthia, Carthage and Egypt. In fact, such exotic origins meant a premium price!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Field_flavour">"

Not only did the Celts develop a field system that made it possible to clearly define the boundaries between farms, they also made machinery that was far more advanced than that used by the Romans or the Greeks. The Celtic plough had a coulter, a sharp blade that turned the soil over on itself, and this allowed farmers to work land that had previously been inaccessible to arable farming. A wide variety of crops were grown by the Celtic people, depending on the climate and soils. For example, the Picts of Scotland were unable to grow olives and grape vines like the tribes of the Po Valley in southern Gaul; they relied instead on the raising of sheep for their wool."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Oracle_of_dondona_flavour">"

Situated at the foot of Mount Tomaros, Dodona was the home of the oldest Greek oracle. Myth has it that a single black dove perched on a great oak tree at Dodona and spoke. It declared that the will of Zeus would be heard from the oak, and that the site should be a place of worship. After such a miraculous beginning, prophecy was delivered through the rustling of leaves and the songs of the doves. The oracle would interpret these sounds, and record answers to questions on lead tablets. By the 4th century BC, walls enclosed the oak tree, and a stone temple was built. A century later, a fortified refuge was built, and other temples. Although destroyed by the Aetolians in 219BC, the Dodona was rebuilt and then finally destroyed by the Romans in 168 BC."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Craftmans_quarter_flavour">"

Cities and towns would often have entire quarters devoted to specific trades, with workshops and markets clustered close together. The trades could be as varied as stoneworking and sculpture by masons, pottery, or the construction of artillery and siege equipment. While many siege artillery pieces would be made from local materials, specialised parts had to be made beforehand, and field artillery would always be made to march with the army. Equipment included various types of ballistae and onagers to sophisticated fire-raisers and the polybolos. 

Such city quarters became a hubs of industry, needing all kinds of resources and support workshops to function. A ballista would require the efforts of blacksmiths, carpenters, butchers and even tanners. The last two may seem a little odd, but the weapon's power came from animal sinews. Masons or potters might also be employed to shape stone shot or make pots to carry chemical mixtures."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Cattle_Trader_flavour">"

Meat was an expensive commodity in the ancient world. Cattle trading was big business across the Roman Empire; the size of a herd was an old measure of wealth from before coinage became standardised. Most common people would only have eaten meat during religious festivals; after an animal was sacrificed, its meat was often divided up between the worshippers. Even so, demand could be high, and even the Circus Maximus was used as a holding area for beasts ""on the hoof"" between religious festivals. 

The Forum Boarium was the biggest cattle and meat market in the city. It was still being used in the 19th century to graze cattle."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Water_Tank_flavour">"

Water tanks were a basic but essential part of life in Roman cities. Growing populations needed a constant supply of water. A reserve could be held, in case of fire or drought, in tanks placed along the aqueducts. 

Fire was a common threat in the ancient world with many buildings being poorly made, and watches were organised to prevent them. The Vigiles Urbani of Rome were a force made up of armed citizens. They were equipped both to fight fires and patrol urban areas. They were not always successful: the great fire of 64AD was not stopped for six days and destroyed a large part of Rome. As well as firewatching, the Vigiles were also used at night to keep civil order and stop sabotage or criminal activity."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Fishing_port_flavour">"

Fish has always been a staple of the Mediterranean diet. Watchmen were often posted on cliffs to look out for shoals of fish and signal to fishermen below. However, fishermen were a low social class and many high-status Greeks were picky about the fish on their plates. Homer described the ways of line and hook, net, spear and harpoon that are still used today. Lack of refrigeration meant fish had to be either eaten quickly, or dried, salted or pickled. Fishing ports were bustling places: mule driven carts or trading boats were used to transport fish to where it was needed. Anchovies and spat were for the poorer classes while the wealthy ate bass,  tuna and red mullet. Shellfish, octopus, squid, swordfish were also common while sturgeon was considered to be among the greatest delicacies. The Greeks cooked their fish with wine, vinegar, olive oil and capers in much the same way as is still done today."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Hippodrome_flavour">"

A hippodrome is a sports arena used for horse and chariot racing, with the name coming from the words ""hippos"" meaning horse, and ""dromos"" or course. This circus had a wide track for ten chariots to race at one time, making for exciting and dangerous races. In the hopes of even more drama the Greeks placed an altar to Taraxippus, the horse disturber, at each corner. This spirit supposedly frightened the horses at the most dangerous part of the track, causing crashes! 

Some hippodromes were also used for footraces. The Lykaion hippodrome shows evidence that athletes took part in races during the same festivals as the chariots. Pentathlons, boxing, wrestling and other contests also took place."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Shrine_of_tanit_flavour">"

A mother goddess of fertility and war, Tanit was not just the consort of Ba’al Hammon but his equal and counterpart. Tanit was associated with the ancient Ugarit gods, like Ba’al, and particularly the war goddess Anat, who is often depicted as a headhunter in battle, wading knee-deep through blood. This imagery persisted in Carthage, but she was also revered as the mother of her people and as the patron of nursing. 

Kerkouane, a Carthaginian settlement abandoned sometime during the First Punic War, had a sanctuary dedicated to Tanit. It featured a courtyard, surrounded by a series of columns, and mosaic floors bearing her symbol. Associated with, or serving, the sanctuary, there are rooms and houses with stone baths, with sculpted seats and arm rests for bathers."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Water_tank_flavour">"

Used to store water and supply fountains, water tanks were an essential component of Hellenic cities. A reliable and steady source of water, stone tanks could be filled using mechanical devices such as Archimedes’ screw or by siphons, which were used in Pergamon's citadel. 

 Many Greek inventions and innovations stemmed the harnessing of water, including the clepsydra, a type of clock known as a water thief. Although water clocks had been used for centuries to mark time with a controlled flow, it was Ctesibius, an Alexandrian inventor, who is supposed to have improved the design. He is also responsible for the ""hydraulis"", or water organ."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Range_flavour">"

The use of any missile weapon requires practice and discipline, particularly if the enemy are firing or fighting back. Slings, javelins and bows were common weapons, and many troops were highly skilled in their use. The Parthian shot was a famed tactic of shooting while galloping away from the enemy, hopefully encouraging the more foolish among the targets to pursue, be cut off, and be cut to shreds. Skirmishers were trained to harass, delay and annoy the enemy before the battle was joined, and to keep enemies from doing the same to their own side. 

In the east, the compound or recurve bow was in common use: unlike the self bow which is a single piece of wood, it was made from many different layers that each added to its strength. Sinew, horn and wood were glued together to make a strong, springy whole. The dry climate helped, because compound bows need to be kept free from damp, otherwise the animal glues used to build them start to decay. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Fountain_flavour">"

Most commonly fed from subterranean aqueducts, springs or rivers, fountains date to as early as the 6th century BC, providing accessible drinking water for the communities they served. 

Often carved from marble, fountains consisted of a great basin fed by bronze piping, usually with a stylised, mask-like waterspout. Animals, mythic beasts, and the gods were common designs. 

Both Athens and Corinth were known for their fountains: Athens had the grand Enneacrounos of the Agora and Corinth the famous spring dedicated to the nymph Pirene."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Agora_flavour">"

Meaning ""gathering place"", the agora was at the heart of Hellenic cities, acting as the artistic, political and spiritual centre of city life. As early as the 10th century BC, these open spaces were used as the assembly ground for hoplite armies, and for the citizens to hear the decisions of their courts and proclamations of their kings. The space eventually included market stalls, gatherings for games, and the public platforms for democracy and public speaking. 

In Athens, the agora was situated to the northwest of the Acropolis on the Panathenaic Way, and featured fountains, temples dedicated to Zeus, Apollo and Hephaestus, shrines and altars to other gods, and the Strategeion. This last  was dedicated to the cult of Strategos and was where the ten Strategoi, or Athenian generals, would discuss politics and military policy. 

""Agoraphobia"", the modern term for a fear of open spaces, has its roots in this concept of an open, public space. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Qanat_flavour">"

Qanats are a series of shafts connected by sloping tunnels that channel water underground over great distances. Dug deep into hills and mountains to take advantage of a higher water table, these passages then send water out into distribution canals. Being underground, little water is lost due to evaporation and the qanats provide a clean water supply that is relatively safe from natural disaster and sabotage. 

Originating in the early First Millennium BC qanats spread rapidly across Africa and Asia. They required skilled artisans to locate potential water sources, plan routes and dig the passageways to the right gradient and then keep them clear. A steep qanat would let the water flow too fast, draining the source and eroding the tunnel; if it were too shallow the water would not flow at all."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shipwright_flavour">"

Shipbuilding, maintenance and having a safe harbour were obviously crucial to the trade and expansion of any Mediterranean people. From 500BC, the Greek trireme was the backbone of Hellenistic navies. Up to 40m long, and powered by a crew of 170 highly trained, professional rowers, the trireme was narrow and light if a little unstable. Rowers were expected to throw javelins and sling stones while seated so as not to rock the boat! In Piraeus, the port of Athens, up to 750 triremes could be sheltered in nearly 500 neosokoi, or covered hangars, when not in use. The Carthaginians constructed an artificial harbour or cothon to protect their ships from the sea. It is believed that other cothons could be drained to act as dry docks, allowing for ship maintenance."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Goldsmith_flavour">"

The skilled metalworkers of barbarian Europe had already perfected casting, sheet working and hammer working by the beginning of the Iron Age. The horse harnesses and vehicle fittings found just south of Gussage All Saints in southern England exemplify the casting method known as ""cire perdue"", or the lost wax method. The item to be cast is first modelled out of beeswax. Once this model is completed it is then covered in clay, leaving at least two vents. The clay is then heated to melt the wax and bake the clay hard. The wax is poured out of the hardened mould, and then molten gold is poured through one of the vents to fill it. When the metal had cooled the mould would be broken to reveal the cast piece which could then be finished and polished by hand."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Slave_trader_flavour">"

Prisoners of war in the ancient world were often sold into slavery. Those captured by barbarians were just as unlucky. Many of the Celtic words for slave have their roots in the Latin word ""captus"" or captive, and this may be an indication that the custom of taking slaves was introduced to the tribes by either the Romans or the Greeks. These civilisations held very different views on slavery. In Greece a slave, be he born into servitude or captured as a prisoner of war, could never become a Greek citizen. The Romans on the other hand, gave their slaves complete freedom after manumission, as well as political freedom and the opportunity to run for public office."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Horse_pens_flavour">"

The scarcity of horses in some states, climate, and the tradition of infantry fighting meant many Hellenistic rulers used a limited number of horsemen in their armies. Although the various states undoubtedly organised their forces differently, Greek military manuals point to both heavily armoured and lighter skirmishing cavalry. The ""hippeis"" were the high ranking citizens who could afford to buy and keep horses, and they often served as a royal guard. Unlike their foot counterparts they continued to drill and practice in peacetime and took part in major processions and festivals. 

The cavalry of the Aeotolian League was regarded as the best cavalry of the Hellenistic world, while the Achaean League’s horsemen were thought of as largely ineffectual. Generals would supplement their own cavalry forces with the more experienced and better skilled mercenary riders, along with horsemen from conquered states."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_germanic_Grove_of_austro_flavour">"

Austro's name is related to the Germanic words for ""shining"" and ""east"". She is a goddess of springtime and new beginnings, and celebrated as the goddess of youth and purity. She is connected to the pagan Anglo-Saxon goddess Eostre; much of Autro's symbolism, such as eggs and hares, or bunnies, at the spring equinox is still used in European Easter celebrations. Austro was said to have lights, carried by rabbits, before her. She brought the dawn as new beginning, and spring renewal after the dark of winter. It is easy to see why she is a joyous goddess."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Theatre_of_pompey">"

Built by the celebrated general Gnaeus Pompeius Magnus as a means of gaining political favour, the Theatre of Pompey was Rome’s first permanent theatre. It boasted beautiful gardens filled with ornate fountains, covered walkways where patrons could admire Pompey’s art collection, and a curia where political meetings could be held. It is said that Julius Caesar met his grisly end as he left Theatre's curia. When the mob heard of Caesar’s murder they burnt the curia to the ground; the theatre survived, but the curia itself was never reopened. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Port_flavour">"

While tribal societies were not great seafarers across the deeps, the opportunities for trading and raiding with ships were appreciated: coastal trade was certainly possible. As the Mediterranean powers began to sail in the Atlantic, trade from areas such as Cornwall and Brittany proved profitable. Tin, in particular, a much sought after resource as it was needed to make bronze. As great traders, the Carthaginians established the sea-trade, but it showed the locals where there were riches to be had. The Gallic Veneti tribe, for example, became renowned for their skill as shipwrights. Their use of oak and iron in the construction of their vessels made them incredibly strong, as the Romans discovered when Caesar’s fleet met sturdy Veneti ships in 56BC. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Recruiting_Ground_flavour">"

Rome expected her people to fight for their city and country in times of need. The army was originally a citizen militia and nearly all men provided their own weapons and equipment. 

As Rome’s power increased, more troops were needed to defend the Empire and so auxiliary soldiers were recruited from non-Romans to fill the rank and file. The enlisting of auxiliary troops was begun by Augustus and drew on provincial non-citizens, allies and conquered nations. Service was for 25 years, after which an auxiliary and his heirs were granted Roman citizenship, an important superior legal status. 

The army included many cultures and nationalities, often speaking their own languages and fighting in their own traditional styles. By the second century AD half the army's total strength and almost all the cavalry consisted of auxiliaries."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_germanic_Grove_of_teiwaz_flavour">"

Teiwaz or Tyr was the god of war, and the original sky-father deity until Wodanaz discovered the runes of power. Married to Zisa, Teiwaz was the only god brave enough to try and tie down the huge wolf, Fenrir. He bound the wolf with Gleipnir, the Fooler, an unbreakable rope crafted by dwarves but had his sword hand bitten off in the struggle. He is destined to fall at Ragnarok, the last great battle of the gods, killed by the hound of Hellheim, Garm. He demanded courage and honour from his followers, and warriors would swear their allegiance to leaders by Teiwaz. The Germans believed he held so much sway over the outcome of battles that they sacrificed many spoils to him, including prisoners. Arguments would be put to him to be decided in trials by combat. The Hermunduri tribe are known to have made human sacrifice to him. Tuesday is a distant echo of his name..."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shrine_of_poseidon_flavour">"

One of the three major gods of Greece, Poseidon had dominion over the sea and lesser waters. He was crucial to sailors and traders, and could not be ignored by anyone in Greece. He was also the master of earthquakes, and could bring ruin in an instant. Given the number of earthquakes in Greece and the surrounding islands, Poseidon was a god to respect and to placate as often as possible. He was, however, an unforgiving god as is shown by his hounding of Odysseus after the hero blinded Polyphemus, the Cyclops son of Poseidon during his voyage home after the Trojan War. 

Alexander cast a four-horse chariot into the sea before the Battle of Issus to honour Poseidon and obtain his favour. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_City_flavour">"

As barbarian society developed, the need for larger settlements to house more people increased. This gave rise to fortified settlements, which tended to be built on areas with natural defences such as hilltops, cliffs or river banks. These were fortified with stone or wooden defences, setting them apart from the smaller settlements of the tribes. Some historians argue that the addition of fortifications was not a defensive decision but was, in fact, a matter of prestige. A tribe could have more than one of these fortified settlements and their sizes varied significantly. Julius Caesar made a study of the Gauls and named their fortified settlements ""oppidum"", noting that the differing sizes seemed to show the hierarchy within each tribe."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Great_harbour">"

Egypt’s great costal harbours were a solution to the problem posed by the Nile to seafaring ships. Although the river is navigable, the delta silts up, and its waterways change course sometimes annually. Although ships could navigate the deeper water courses, this constant change made siting ports near the delta impossible.

 The greatest of the harbours on the coast was undoubtedly at Alexandria. Following Alexander the Great’s orders, his architect Dinocrat had the silted-up port of Rhakotis cleared, and two great harbours constructed, one military, the other for merchant vessels by the island of Pharos to the mainland. This land bridge was 1km long and 200m wide. It also allowed the construction of the Pharos, the Lighthouse of Alexandria, one of the Seven Wonders of the World, between 280-247BC."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Artisans_lodgings_flavour">"

Many Roman writers attempted to reduce the Celts to a crude people who lived for war and little else. When describing the Celts of the Po Valley, Polybius commented that “their lives are very simple, and they had no knowledge whatsoever of art or science.” Thanks to archaeological finds we know this to be an oversimplification of a very complex society, and beautiful examples of Celtic art found all over Europe tell a very different story. Items like the Gundestrup Cauldron and the Desborough Mirror show that the Celts had excellent metalworking skills, an artistic eye and the ability to tell stories through their art. The intricate detail on the cauldron was preserved by the peat bog in which it was discovered. The glass used in the figures' eyes gives us some idea of the excellent artistic and craft abilities of the men who made the Cauldron."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Boat_yard_flavour">"

The Celtic Otherworld was a paradise to which the Celts believed they travelled to after death. Many myths and legends describe it as an island, and the idea that the dead passed beyond the horizon is in many tales. The Byzantine philosopher Procopius of Caesarea recorded the beliefs of the tribes of Gaul and stated that they believed the Otherworld to be West of Britannia, modern-day Great Britain. According to Procopius, the Gauls believed that when a person died their soul would travel to the coast. Once there, they would bang on the doors of fishermen’s homes and beg passage across the seas. The fishermen would then ferry the souls to their destination and return home, never revealing the exact location of the Otherworld."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Range_flavour">"

Although Hellenistic armies used archers more than earlier Greek ones, they still relied on close-combat infantry. In early times archers had only been used to defend city walls or to cover the hoplites in battle;  they were never the main attack force. Bowmen were only about 10% of the Greek army in the Peloponnesian War. 

The Greeks learned from their battles with the Persians and, by the time of Alexander, some mounted archers had been introduced. They also often used skilled Cretan or Scythian mercenary bowmen who used the more powerful ""three-fingered grip"" rather than just the thumb and forefinger to pull the string back. Other missile troops included peltasts: lightly armed, skirmishing troops with a brace of javelins; and slingers who could hurl a stone beyond arrow range with pin point accuracy."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Consecrated_ground_flavour">"

The Greeks had hundreds of gods and spirits that governed nearly every aspect of life. For centuries the people had been paying them homage and consecrating spaces and buildings in their honour. The mythologies that told the stories of the gods, such as Homer’s The Iliad, were particularly important to the Hellenistic cultures and were treated as sacred texts. Numerous festivals would be held all year round so that the gods would bless the land and people. With so many gods, cults were established to focus beliefs on one particular deity or another. 

Like other peoples, belief in an afterlife was a given, so that mortal life did have consequences. For the Greeks, they might suffer in Tartarus, abide in Hades or go to the noble, beautiful fields of Elysium, depending on their path through life. Indeed, if strict funeral rites were not observed the dead might be condemned to wander as lost souls."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Military_pier_flavour">"

For most civilizations, military dominance has always included mastery of the sea. It was always far easier to move men and material by sea than march them overland. Suppressing pirates and protecting trade was merely an extra benefit. Construction of good military vessels was therefore vital, with all kinds of ships from patrol biremes to colossal battle quinqueremes needed for a balanced force. 

Mastery of the sea prevented invasions too, and could even be a tool of diplomacy. By the Apamea treaty in 188BC, Rome limited the power of the Seleucid Empire by dictating the number of warships the Seleucids were allowed. When Antiochus V Eupator broke the treaty, the Romans sent delegations to Syrian cities, charged with sinking the excess warships."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_germanic_Grove_of_frijjo_flavour">"

Frijjo is the original domestic goddess. The highest ranking female of the Aesir, wife of Wodanaz and stepmother to Teiwaz and Thunaraz, Frijjo governed over everything female in the world, from the crafts of weaving, sewing, spinning and cooking to all the mysteries of fertility and birth. As queen to Wodanaz she is his match in wisdom and majesty. The Germans would make offerings to her to keep social order and bless their marriages and children. As she weaved the cosmic order, so she kept peace at home: mothers would pray to her to keep their sons safe in battle as they sewed protective garments for them. She was also believed to be a seeress who knew the future but rarely revealed it. Friday is named after her."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Amphitheatron_flavour">"

The amphitheatron had a circular or oval plan, with a sloping gallery of seats looking over a central arena. Plays were a form of worship of the god Dionysus, and drama festivals such as the Dionysia in springtime were religious celebrations as well as entertaining. Officially performances in the amphitheatron were only for men, but records show that some women did attend. 

Theatre changed during the Hellenistic period and, instead of the earlier grand tragedies, audiences wanted plays that were about their own lives rather than the gods and myth. This new style was a comedy of manners, and the extant fragments of Menander's plays show that they were far more sophisticated than the farcical works of Aristophanes and others. This ""New Comedy"" went on to influence the playwrights of Rome."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Grove_of_nodens_flavour">"

As a god of healing Nodens was often associated with water; the ancient Celts saw water as a purifier and worshiped it for its healing powers. A large temple complex, built by the Romans, alongside the River Severn in England was dedicated to Nodens and featured dormitories, suggesting that it may have been a place of pilgrimage for the ill and infirm. The site of this temple may also have been chosen as it offered an excellent view over the river and would have been ideal for viewing the Severn Bore, a large wave which sweeps up river against the current. This natural spectacle can occur throughout the year but the largest bores tend to rise in the spring. The largest bore ever recorded reached a height of 2.8 metres."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Circus_Maximus_flavour">"

At the height of its popularity the Circus Maximus seated over 150,000 spectators but even this wasn't enough for every Roman to attend. Entertainment here was on a massive scale. Situated in a natural valley, the Circus has became synonymous with chariot racing but it was used for all kinds of elaborate ""ludi"" or games, often celebrating religious festivals. Rather like the modern Olympics, these games were paid for by rich sponsors and all tried to outdo previous events in grandeur and pageantry. As well as chariot races, boxing, wrestling, gladiator contests, athletics, plays, recitals and even elephant fighting featured as events! The Circus Maximus itself was rebuilt several times, to make it grander, safer for spectators, and then more dangerous and exciting again: Julius Caser ordered a moat to protect the crowd, but Nero then had it filled in so that everyone could be closer to the action!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Meeting_hall_flavour">"

Much of what we know of barbarian tribes comes from accounts set down by Roman and Greek writers, and they are often extremely critical. However, Gaius Cornelius Tacitus in the book ‘Germania’ writes about the Germanic tribes with great respect. He described a people who were very open and hospitable, who loved nothing more than feasting and celebrating great deeds. He was also impressed that they resolved all tribal issues at a council where the voice of every man could be heard. He also remarked on the fidelity shown in the marriages of the Germanic people, and yet there was one aspect of their lives that he found deplorable and barbaric. He thoroughly disapproved of “their habitual drunkenness”. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Blacksmith_flavour">"

Smithing was an essential trade in the ancient world. Since the Bronze Age fires had been used to smelt metal, and the skill of the smith forged swords and spear heads. With the arrival of iron blacksmiths sprang up in every town and city of Greece. Ploughs, axes, and tools of every kind, and even jewellery, were created. 

 Yet even though smiths were skilled and necessary, theirs was a lowly trade, and never attained the status of armourers and masons. Hephaestus, the crippled son of Zeus, was the patron god of smithing. Like the trade itself, he was considered ugly and unglamorous."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Adobe_maker_flavour">"

Adobe has been used as a versatile and durable building material for thousands of years. It is formed from clay, sand and water, with some fibrous, organic binding matter such as straw or manure. It can be made on site as a continuous structure, or turned into bricks by using wooden frames. Adobe has several useful properties, and slowly absorbs and releasese heat; adobe buildings stay cool in the day, and warm at night in arid, desert conditions. 

Traditionally, adobe was allowed to dry naturally in the sun, but adobe bricks and tiles can also be fired in kilns. Because of the ingredients, adobe makers could easily construct temporary adobe works next to large building sites. In large cities, where space was at a premium, areas could be given over to adobe production."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Hamlet_flavour">"

Wherever the Romans went they not only conquered but also settled and built communities. The Romans used stone and brick to plant colonies meant to last. Colonial towns developed from small hamlets and villages, some of which already existed. They became centres of regional administration and commerce. The planned provincial towns or “civitates” were built in a square grid pattern with stone periphery walls for protection. The smaller “vici” were less formal, often growing up outside Roman army camps in order to supply soldiers with the comforts and pleasures of home. 

Many indigenous villages were left as they had always been: simple collections of wooden houses and small workshops. Rome itself had grown from the village settlement of the Latin tribe upon the Palatine Hill some three or four hundred years before the Republic."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Infantry_tents_flavour">"

Mustering a force required careful planning. Levies were often expected to provide their own arms, such as spear and shield, or javelins and even bows. If this were not done, they would have to be outfitted at the expense of the state treasury. This took time, and the easiest way to get everyone organised and equipped was in temporary camps. 

Dependent on circumstances and population, permanent quarters or barracks for levies would be built. Barrack-based troops could be used to supplement town watches or to patrol borders and guard trade routes. Even so, conscript levies were usually poorly trained, and more lightly equipped than noble, professional or mercenary soldiers."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Field_engineers_workshop_flavour">"

As empires expanded so technologies developed to enable attacks on defensive positions and lay siege to large cities. Field engineers became adept in the arts of using whatever resources were to hand to construct catapults, siege towers and battering rams to break down the enemy’s defences. The scorpion, a crossbow-like spear-thrower, the fire-raiser, a burning cauldron attached to a long beam on wheels, and the sambuca, a type of covered troop ladder, were early innovations in siege engineering. Philip V of Macedon used catapults along with defensive field works in his defence of the Aous Valley in 198BC where the Romans lost many men. 

Towering, literally, above all these were the huge siege towers needed to assault high walls. The Helepolis was used against Rhodes in 304BC, stood some 40m high and required 3000 men to operate it!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Great_library_flavour">"

The most famous of all ancient libraries was founded in 288BC as part of the Alexandrian Museum by Demetrius of Phaleron. Originally based on the library of Athens, it housed mainly Greek scrolls but was open to poets, scientists, scholars and philosophers from all peoples. It was the vision of Alexander, as Aristotle’s pupil, to bring together all the knowledge in the known world under one roof, and some 70,000 scrolls were held. Much medical, scientific and scholarly work was undertaken, including the first star atlas. Aristarchus, a scholar using the library, worked out that the world revolved around the sun nearly 2000 years before Copernicus, and it was here that the Old Testament was first translated into Greek. For six centuries the Great Library embodied academic research and study. It declined after the Roman occupation and was destroyed by fire in 272AD."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Odeon_flavour">"

An odeon was a small, intimate theatre that was ideal for musical concerts and smaller works. While plays were performed, the acoustics favoured musical concerts, as shown by the name which means ""singing place"". Poets competed for prizes and many perfomances of epic classics such as the Illiad and Odyssey were given to sophisticated audiences. 

The oldest known odeon was built in Skias in Sparta around 600BC. One of the largest and most impressive remaining examples is the one built in 161AD by Herodes of Atticus, a rich Athenian magnate. Its beamed roof was made of cedar and it was decorated with works of art. It stands by the Acropolis and seated up to 5000 for musical concerts."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Shrine_of_horus_flavour">"

Horus was commonly depicted as a falcon-headed man or just as a falcon but he had many aspects and responsibilities. During the time of the Ptolemaic dynasty and under the Romans he was worshipped as the son of Osiris and Isis, and as the god of the sky. He was also a god of war and a divine vengeance taker, thanks to his war against Set to avenge Osiris’ death. In another aspect, Horus the Elder was worshipped as the patron of pharaohs, a giver of great wisdom. 

Many temples, such as the Temple of Horus the Elder at Kom Ombo were rebuilt by the Ptolemaic pharaohs. Ptolemy VI Philometor is the earliest ruler named in any inscriptions at the complex; construction probably began under him, but certainly finished after his reign. Ptolemy VI Philometor was, of course, Greek but was wise enough to follow local traditions."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Hamlet_flavour">"

Roman and Greek historians often described the barbarian tribes as a wandering people who lived for the hunt and knew little of farming and construction. Nothing could be further from the truth. A number of structures have been discovered that show that ""barbarians"" had a firm grasp of building techniques and were able to construct homes and defences that survived for thousands of years. Brochs, dry stone buildings found in Scotland, have survived harsh Scottish weather and provide interesting information about the people who built them. Many were multi-storey dwellings and historians still debate their original use: some believe they were defensive structures; others argue they may have been prestige buildings, symbols of wealth and power."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Ptolemaic_temple_complex_flavour">"

Great temple complexes and monuments were built and rebuilt throughout Egypt by all the Ptolemaic pharaohs as a sign of their right to rule and continued dominance. By celebrating heaven the Ptolemies could claim divine sanction for their continued rule, and give public respect to the beliefs of common Egyptians. 

With many Greek colonists entering Egypt, the new temples also helped bring the two peoples together as one nation. Temples to Isis and Horus were deliberately placed next to those to Hellenized gods such as Zeus Ammon and Serapis, and connections between both pantheons were clearly made for worshippers. Alexandria featured the greatest of these new complexes but other sites, such as the Philae or Thebes, were also rebuilt to suit the political and religious needs of the Ptolemies."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Wine_Trader_flavour">"

Romans loved wine and drank it every day. The wine trade grew alongside the Empire and became a huge business. Merchants took wine from Italy, Spain, Greece, Gaul and elsewhere to all parts of the Empire using amphorae stacked in ships. Sea transport was key as it could cost less to import wine from Spain by sea than to move it by road from home-grown vineyards. 

At the height of the trade, up to 40,000 amphorae of wine were exported annually from Italy to Gaul and it is estimated that 500,000 litres were drunk every day in Rome alone! 

The Forum Vinarium was, effectively, the biggest wine shop of the ancient world. Wine was grown using slave labour in both the Italian countryside and conquered lands. It has to be noted that the Romans were, for much of the Empire's lifespan, favoured with a warm climate that allowed viniculture in many northern lands."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Reservoir_flavour">"

Water was sacred to the ancient Celts. Rivers, wells and springs were all thought to have both medical and magical properties and they were often the sites of great sanctuaries. Perhaps the most famous of these can be found in the English town of Bath. The ancient Celts worshipped at the hot springs found in this area and attributed them to the goddess Sulis. After the invasion, the Romans developed the springs into baths and built a new temple to Sulis, who they equated to their own goddess Minerva. Over 130 lead curse tablets have been discovered within the springs, and it would seem that thefts were common while men and women were taking the water: many of the tablets curse unknown thieves."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Practice_camp_flavour">"

Training areas were a common feature in Greek settlements where every citizen was expected to play a part in warfare. These camps, forts and stratopedon prepared citizens, professional soldiers and mercenaries for the realities of the battlefield. It taught them how to follow orders, form up, and move as a phalanx, and to defend themselves and each other as a cohesive unit. 

Details of training varied across the Hellenic world. Spartan warriors, by virtue of being a dedicated army supported by their helot slaves, could devote their entire lives to military training. In contrast, Athens required its citizens to spend two years learning the military arts, with 18 year old conscripts having instruction in weapons, and drilled in tactics and siegecraft for attack and defence."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Shrine_of_Mars_flavour">"

Mars was the second-most potent god in the Roman pantheon after his father, Jupiter. War was at the heart of Roman imperialism and its governing deity Mars was crucial to the state’s expansionist ideals. He was rightly greatly revered and worshipped. A whole month, March, was put aside for his festivals, marking the beginning of the Roman year. 

Father of Romulus and Remus, Mars was associated with the very birth of Rome and thus Romans saw themselves as his children. Octavius built a temple to Mars, rather than Jupiter, on the Capitol in Rome to celebrate the overthrowing of Julius Caesar’s murderers. The Roman army believed Mars marched before them, so homage had to be paid to ensure success in battle."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Peripatetic_school_flavour">"

Around 335BC Aristotle founded his school of philosophy. The name derived from the words for ""colonnade"", and ""to wander"". Students would gather outside the Lyceum and Aristotle would lecture as they followed him on his walk. Many of the greatest minds in Greece came to hear him, and the school’s philosophy had a great impact on Hellenic culture. Aristotle, himself a student of Plato, was reputed to wander, in spirit at least, along the colonnade after his death. The school fell into decline in the 3rd century BC, but revived after the Roman occupation. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_egypt_Royal_sanctuary_flavour">"

Veneration of ancestors and the worship of divine royalty were common in the ancient world. Ancestors were commonly worshipped even in the meanest houses, while temples and great tombs were constructed to remember dead rulers. In Egypt the Ptolemaic rulers followed this useful tradition after the death of Alexander the Great. All great tombs and temples were a memorial to the greatness of the rulers who built them. 

Alexander was first entombed in Memphis on the order of the first Ptolemy, after his mummified remains were diverted from Babylon. His body was then taken to Alexandria and put in two tombs, the second one having members of the Ptolemaic dynasty alongside as a statement of status. Julius Caesar and Octavian both visited Alexander’s tomb to pay their respects, as such a pious display was a good way of demonstrating their own claims to greatness."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Quartermaster_flavour">"

Armies have always been more than just the men in the ranks. Provision of weapons, armour, supplies and camp materials was essential. Almost any workshop could make axes, javelins and spears, arrows and lead sling bullets, or simple leather armour, but making supplies in sufficient quantity needed central organisation. More complex equipment often required skilled blacksmiths working in better shops. A good sword needed time and skill to make, as did high-quality armour. 

Siege equipment could be constructed on site, but there was always a need for specialised parts. It was relatively easy to find timber, but the ironwork and sinew “springs” needed might be harder to find on campaign. These pieces would be created in advance in specialised central workshops."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Farmers_market_flavour">"

Long before the Romans began their advance northwards the tribes of Gaul, Germania and Britannia were trading goods with the Mediterranean world. The Roman writer Strabo commented that trade with far-off Britannia was far more profitable than the revenue that could be collected should the place ever become a Roman province. The complex timber trackways discovered all over Europe also hint at trade links between tribes. As well as land transport many tribes developed river vessels and used the Danube, Rhine, Rhones, Seine, Loire and Po rivers to transport their goods. It is also known that there were trade links between the tribes of Britannia and those of Northern Gaul, so they must have possessed ocean-going vessels, though remains of these have yet to be discovered."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Shrine_of_Minerva_flavour">"

Poetry, art, science, medicine, weaving and crafts all came under the auspices of the goddess Minerva. Her temples were meeting places for craftsmen, poets and actors. Above all she was known as the goddess of wisdom and, as such, had influence on every aspect of Roman life. 

Daughter of Jupiter, born not from a mother but from his head, Minerva was a major deity and governed thinking, calculating and the assessment of any situation. She was very important both in peace and war and many leaders asked her for cunning in battle. This was often repaid by war booty being given to her temples after victory. Statues of her show a brave maiden with helmet, shield and a coat of mail. 

As with many of the Roman gods, other cultures were seen as having their own local counterparts of Minerva. In Britain, for example, she was aligned with Sulis. The only surviving temple to Minerva is in Chester, England."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Shrine_of_baal_hammon_flavour">"

Ba’al Hammon was first among the Carthaginian gods. Depicted as a bearded man with curling ram horns, he was a sky god, responsible for storms and weather. His sphere of influence therefore was directly linked to seafaring and farming, both of which were important to a sea-going empire and a nation on the edge of a desert. 

His temples were always open to the sky. In Carthage itself the main sanctuary was Jebel Bu Kornein, a great hill overlooking the bay. Here incense and sacrifices were offered to Ba’al. Stories of children being sacrificed in his flames were probably wildly exaggerated by Roman writers, although Carthaginians were conscious of the need for sacrifice to be sincere. Ba’al may well have a connection to fire, as “Hammon” may well refer to the Phoenician word for brazier."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Military_Wharf_flavour">"

Rome is seen by most people as a military power not a naval one. The navy, though, was a key part of Roman power, acting in support of the army and carrying it to war. The Roman Navy was in action all over the Empire, even on major rivers like the Danube and the Rhine, and had facilities nearly everywhere as ships needed constant care to keep them ready for action. Dry docks had been built in the ancient world as far back as 200BC, and the Romans had many of them to build, repair and maintain their fleet or “classis” across the Empire. 

Roman citizens didn't have to work as oarsmen, and auxiliaries serving as such were given citizenship after 26 years of service. The Romans could be excellent fighting sailors, as demonstrated by Octavian's fleet at the Battle of Actium in 31BC. Unfortunately, the enemy were other Romans under Mark Antony. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Animal_breeder_flavour">"

Prized as commodities, animals were trapped, tamed and bred. Ownership and husbandry of exotic breeds cost money and time, and was a pursuit of the wealthy and the noble. War horses, swift racers, beasts of burden, or exotic war elephants, signs of an owner's conspicuous wealth. 

Horses were essential to eastern armies before the Greco-Persian Wars, replacing the functions of light chariots. Ancient cavalry could be roughly divided into two types: light skirmishers to harry the enemy at a distance, or heavy, armoured troops to engage other cavalry, outflank and then exploit the weak points of enemy formations. 

As well as horses, camels, dogs and elephants were conditioned and trained for war, providing shock elements for eastern generals. Camels were prized because of their ability to terrify horses by their unfamiliar smell alone!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Colosseum_flavour">"

With four massive tiers of seating, this gladiatorial arena was the grandest the world had ever seen, allowing 80,000 to watch the games. The building dominated the city. Lavishly decorated with marble, the Colosseum allowed Romans to see everything and everyone they had conquered. Built by Emperor Vespasian and his son Titus this huge symbol of Rome’s might and riches took less than a decade to build. The ruins of today are only the concrete core, stripped of marble over the centuries. Forty-two emperors saw an estimated 700,000 deaths in the Colosseum, watching everything from Christians to mass battles to elaborate executions. And all this was done in the name of entertainment! 

Elaborate staging allowed adventurous showmanship: sea battles were re-enacted by flooding the arena; exotic beasts such as giraffes, crocodiles and tigers were regularly hunted; and some 36 trapdoors meant a huge variety of surprises for the gladiators battling on the sand."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Windcatcher_flavour">"

Providing cooling breezes into the heart of a building, windcatchers could take a variety of forms. Typically, they consist of a capped tower with one open face directed towards the prevailing wind. This directs wind down the tower, providing natural airflow and a cooling effect throughout the building. Other types had shutters on each side to take advantage of any breeze. 

Underground shabestans used qanats to provide better cooling: opening a windcatcher so that it faces away from the wind creates low pressure to draws air up the tower, pulling cool air through a building from a water-cooled qanat below. Shabestans were often used in homes and schools, but could also be used for storage of certain goods and produce. In contrast, the above ground yakhchals, large-domed evaporative coolers, were used purely for storage and could be cool enough for ice even in summer heat."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Cattle_pens_flavour">"

In Celtic society a man’s wealth was measured by the size of his herd, making cattle an important symbolic part of everyday life. Large herds provided milk, meat and strong bulls to pull ploughs and act as sacrifices to the gods. In ancient Ireland the freshly flayed skin of a bull was worn to induce a sacred sleep that allowed druids to have visions of their future king. The breed of cow farmed by the majority of ancient Celts is thought to be the now-extinct Celtic Shorthorn. Archaeologists studying Danebury hill fort in England have looked at the animal remains found within the fort and concluded that two thirds of the meat eaten there was probably Celtic Shorthorn beef."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Shrine_of_Mercury_flavour">"

Mercury was the God of Travel and Trade and therefore considered important to the success of the Empire. Son of Jupiter from an illicit relationship with Maia, Goddess of the Clouds, Mercury watched over ""proper"" merchants and ""less formal merchants"" in the shape of thieves! Both groups prayed to him for favourable outcomes in their commercial transactions. 

Mercury was closely identified with the Greek god Hermes. The planet Mercury was believed to be the fastest moving by Roman astrologers. There was a temple to Mercury in the Circus Maximus because of his association with speed, and charioteers would pay homage before races. 

Worshipped across the Empire, he later became popular with Celtic and Germanic tribes. As the messenger of the Gods, Mercury is still associated with communication and news and many modern newspapers use his name. Today he is still distantly recalled in the name of “Mesurii dies” (Wednesday), the day dedicated to him: ""Mercredi"" in French and ""Miercoles"" in Spanish. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Shrine_flavour">"

Deeply held religious beliefs were, and are, at the heart of many communities. These were not just customs or duties requiring only lip service. Gods and ancestral spirits were real and were important in daily life. 

Veneration could take many forms, such as offerings to household Gods and ancestors through to public festivals and rites. 

Belief and practice varied from worship of the Greek or Persian Gods to Zoroastrianism and included monotheistic beliefs such as Judaism. The common thread was a desire for people to come together and express faith in the divine. Shrines and temples, tombs and mausoleums, were constructed to appease and glorify the relevant heavenly forces."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Shieldmaker_flavour">"

The shieldmaker and armourer of Rome were highly skilled workers and crucial to military success. The protection used by the Roman army developed over many centuries of campaigning as tactics and formations changed. Early Roman troops had to pay for their own war gear, and what a man could afford determined his position in the battle line. 

The classic armour of the legionary only developed after the reforms of Gaius Marius, and was largely standardised for many centuries. Body armour was made in one of four types: lorica squamata, or scale armour; lorica segmentata made up of metal strips; lorica hamata made of chain mail; and lorica plumata, expensive mail armour usually reserved for leaders. However, production was by hand so many variations occurred and often different types of armour would be used on the battlefield as families and legions would ""make do and mend""."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Shrine_of_baal_zephon">"

It is easy to see how ancient civilisations came to attribute the power of storms to the wrath of the gods. As lord of storms, Ba'al Zephon was revered for his control of the howling winds, churning seas and driving rain. It was his control of the rains that saw him linked to agriculture and cultivation. Torrential rain could destroy crops but, if Ba'al Zephon was appeased, the rains would fall as gentle showers, allowing the people to grow the crops they needed. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Pantheon_flavour">"

Nearly two millennia after it was built the Pantheon in Rome is still the largest unreinforced concrete dome in the world! An incredible feat of architecture, the dome and its large opening (or oculus) at the top represent the heavens. This stunning temple, originally built by Marcus Agrippa and rebuilt after fire by Hadrian, allowed the Roman people to come and pay homage to all of the immortals at once. 

Romans believed in many different gods and goddesses, and this was a temple to all the gods of Rome, where they could all be honoured properly. Many of the Roman gods came from the early Italian tribes, and some adopted very different heavenly duties: Mars was God of Spring originally but became the God of War."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Wells_flavour">"

Water was a precious resource in Carthage. The people needed it, agriculture needed it, and the city's famous dyeing, tanning and textile industries needed it.

Carthage, as well as its colonies and farms, made extensive use of wells and cisterns dug deep into the ground to draw and store water. Enclosed cisterns, covered to reduce the loss of water due from evaporation, were essential for regulating water supply, creating reserves for use in dry spells that would otherwise devastate crops and livestock. These were assisted by the use of underground water systems, like qanats, and the networks created by the Garamantes to ""mine"" water."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Hieron_ton_megalon_theon_flavour">"

The Sanctuary of the Great Gods was a sacred site from the 7th century BC. The most important religious retreat for the Hellenic peoples was on Samothrace in the northern Aegean. The old gods celebrated there were so mysterious and deliberately enigmatic that their names were never written down and were known only to cult initiates. The Great Mother, who embodied the concepts of fertility and the Earth, was central to the rites; she would later be personified as Gaia.  Prayer and animal sacrifice were the usual forms of worship. 

Among the initiates who took vows were the historian Herodotus, Lysander of Sparta, and Philip V of Macedon, the father of Alexander the Great. The Hieron itself was the largest unsupported room in the ancient world. Later, the site would include other temples, shrines, and a theatre."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Travellers_lodge_flavour">"

Extensive diplomatic and trade networks in the Hellenic and Mediterranean world meant travel was common amongst the merchant classes. Inns, or ""pandocheion"", often in or close by the agora, developed to meet the needs of well-heeled travellers, offering places to stay while on business. Travellers brought wealth into the cities and, as artistic, learning and philosophical tastes were shared and spread, contributed much to the Hellenisation of the Mediterranean coast. 

The philosopher Strabo, born around 64BC, was a typical Greek traveller. His extensive wanderings, the basis for his 17-volume Geographica, took him from his native Pontus, across Egypt and into the Kingdom of Kush, before he settled eventually in Rome."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Shrine_of_Jupiter_flavour">"

The temple to Jupiter Optimus Maximus, Jupiter the Best and Greatest, was central to public religion in the city of Rome. Sacrifices were made there on many state occasions, and magistrates drew at least part of their authority from Jupiter. 

The god was an embodiment of much that was Roman, but he also was worshipped during the time of the Roman Kings. This made Romans a little uneasy about his power during the Republican period, for they always had a suspicion of anything connected with kingship, even in something as Roman as their chief god. However, no Roman who wanted high office risked alienating or insulting Jupiter, at least in public. In a patriarchal society like Rome, where the power of the state was modelled on the power of a man as the head of household, it did not do at all to go against, or doubt portents from, the head of the divine household. If Jupiter threw a thunderbolt, all wise men paid attention!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Field_Engineer's_Workshop_flavour">"

An army on the move must be able to take on any challenge. When marching in enemy territory it was vital that the Roman army had specialised engineers with them to construct everything from bridges and fortifications to siege engines and roads. The establishment of a road network was crucial if the army was to be supplied quickly and efficiently. 

Every legionary carried digging tools, but engineers brought expertise to the work party. Examples of extraordinary military engineering during campaigns include Julius Caesar’s bridge to cross the Rhine in 55BC and the wall and massive assault ramp built during the siege of Masada in 73AD. The army also took part in ostensibly civilian projects such as building construction, brickmaking and harbour building."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Clay_tablet_archive_flavour">"

Writing and record keeping on clay tablets, and later papyrus or paper, were essential to administration in the ancient world. Originally developed to record taxes, writing quickly developed to include historical accounts, philosophies, religion and ideas. Cuniform writing on clay tablets was used for thousands of years. Tablets were fired if a permanent record was needed. Over the centuries, tax records and administrative archives would give way to the great libraries and eventually academies, or danesgah, in  later cultures."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Shrine_of_Vulcan_flavour">"

As a young god Vulcan came between his parents, Jupiter and Juno, as they argued. Jupiter picked Vulcan up and threw him from the heavens. He crashed to the ground, leaving his leg badly deformed. After that, Vulcan shunned the company of the other gods and lived in the volcanic depths of Mount Etna. There he worked with the giant one-eyed Cyclopes forging weapons for gods and heroes alike. 

If Vulcan was not honoured he was given to stoking his forge too much, making Etna erupt! He was worshipped as the God of Fire in both its destructive and useful forms. Those who wished to avoid harmful fires and those who used fire for work venerated the blacksmith of the gods. In August, the most dangerous month for fires in and around Rome, live fish were thrown on fires lit along the River Tiber as part of the Vulcanalia. This was done to assuage Vulcan and protect the city. Often his fire temples were built outside the city because of his dangerous nature!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_City_centre_flavour">"

Palaces, administrative ministries, markets and traders are at the heart of any ancient city, all jostling for attention alongside great monuments and temples. Here, business is done and civic duties performed, while the masses are entertained and overawed by rituals, sports and spectacles. 

Although cities were sometimes laid out according to one vision, such as Antioch's grid system of the architect Xenarius, most cities developed over time to meet the immeidate needs of their people. The results could be predicatably messy and very human: with space at premium, new buildings were often constructed on top of older ones, adapting and changing their purpose."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Library_flavour">"

The Lykeion, or Lyceum, in Athens was a meeting place named for Apollo Lyceus, patron god of the grove in which it was built. It was best known as a place of learning thanks to Aristotle’s Peripatetic School that debated there. The great philosopher kept a large collection of scrolls which formed the basis of this early library. Aristotle also taught the pharaohs in Egypt how to organise their libraries. 

 Public libraries were rare as most books were in the private collections of wealthy men. The first purpose-built public library was at Alexandria and it held some 750,000 scrolls. The library in Pergamum ""only"" had some 200,000 scrolls in its stacks."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_celts_Nemeton_flavour">"

Trees were incredibly important to the tribal peoples of Europe: they provided building materials, fuel and sites of worship. The Celts use of tree groves as sacred spaces was well documented, and a little sensationalised, by Roman writers like Pliny and Lucan. They were described as mystical places where animals dared not tread, where the silence was all consuming and where every tree was stained with sacrificial blood. The Irminsul of the Germanic tribes is less well known, though it is thought to have been a tree trunk erected by the tribes in honour of their gods. Historians have related them to the ‘Pillars of Hercules’ discussed by Tacitus in his work ""Germania"". Unfortunately these ""pillars"" were never seen by Roman eyes and have never been explained or described since."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Shrine_of_Neptune_flavour">"

Neptune was not only a god of the seas, but of water generally. It was a foolish sailor who did not at least honour Neptune a little before embarking. The Mediterranean could be a treacherous sea, and ships could easily be carried away by currents and dashed to pieces on hidden shoals. Neptune, the brother of Jupiter, was quite definitely the King of the Sea and therefore important to any maritime Roman ambitions. 

While it is tempting to see the Romans as a land power, much of their influence and success was based on naval strength in the Mediterranean world. The chief festival of Neptune, the Neptunalia, took place in the heat of summer at a time when the rivers in central Italy must have been at their lowest after winter and the spring thaw. This must have seemed an excellent time to celebrate Neptune’s bounty, if only to ensure more water in future months! 

Neptune was also the god of horse racing, which partly explains why dolphin-shaped markers showed the number of laps run in races at the Circus Maximus."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_carthage_Gardens_flavour">"

Carthage’s wealth and sophisticated water management allowed its people to grow and maintain exquisite gardens. These ranged from the purely decorative courtyards where the elite could take their ease to more functional spaces growing herbs or fruits. It is possible that, as early as the 4th century BC, grapes were grown within the city. 

Much like their Phoenician forebears and their Persian counterparts, Carthaginians saw gardens as a symbol of power and prestige. A seemingly-impossible garden in an arid environment demonstrated great wealth and good taste."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_barbarian_Storage_pit_flavour">"

Storing food for the winter months or for use during sieges was of vital importance. The tribes of Gaul, Germania and Britannia employed a number of techniques to keep people fed beyond harvest time. Storage pits were common to many of the tribes. Examples have been found in settlements all over Europe and have actually helped archaeologists to piece together the diets of the people who ate from them. Another common find is the souterrain, also known as a fogou in Cornwall. Most souterrains have timber roofs but the Carn Euny fogou has a roof made of heavy stone slabs. Alongside the Halliggye fogou it is one of the largest stores from the period ever discovered and runs for 65 metres underground."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Workshop_flavour">"

Workshops were used from ancient times by many craftsmen. Skills were perfected and guilds were set up to teach and protect the profits of those with skill against outside competition. Blacksmithing, pottery and weapon-making were all skills handed down from father to son. All the skills needed by a city would be found in small workshops alongside homes and other businesses. 

Some trades and skills, however, were less than pleasant for the workers and their neighbours: in a fuller’s workshop the art of whitening the Roman togas of the elite was done with urine collected in receptacles in the streets. The fuller spent his day treading the urine into the cloth with his bare feet. The clothes were then rinsed and sulphur was applied to rid them of any lasting stains. Finally they would be dried and then be ready to be returned to the owners as good as new."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Governors_palace_flavour">"

Varying in style, but not in purpose, palaces of local governors, satraps and royalty were power made manifest in stone. Whether based on earlier Persian designs, such as the administrative buildings and royal palace complex at Persepolis at the heart of the Achaemenid Empire, or constructed in Hellenic fashion by Alexander’s successors, such as the Seleucid palaces at Antioch, all these buildings were design to awe. 

The palaces were also hives of activity, from which the day-to-day running of cities, provinces and kingdoms was orchestrated, and diplomacy, politics and wars were conducted and planned."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shrine_of_hermes_flavour">"

Hermes, the herald and messenger of the gods, was often depicted as a handsome young man wearing winged sandals and carrying the herald’s staff, the kerykeion, with two serpents wrapped around it. Of all the gods, Hermes was the one who moved most easily between the mortal world and Olympus, home of the immortal gods. Perhaps this accounted for his work escorting the souls of the dead to the afterlife. He was also the god of travellers, merchants and, because he was fond of trickery and cunning, thieves. Perhaps, again, because hard bargaining and haggling in the marketplace were almost an art form, it was difficult to tell merchants and chiselling tricksters apart! 

More honestly, Hermes was also the patron of athletes, and was the inventor of the foot race. The Romans considered him to be the same as Mercury."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Hamlet_flavour">"

Small farming settlements were the backbone of ancient civilizations in the East, feeding the great cities such as Antioch and Seleucia. Situated to exploit good land, fishing, mining or quarrying, defence was often too expensive to be more than a secondary consideration. 

As the populations of the great cities increased, surplus food from these farming communities became essential. As small military garrisons were positioned to protect valuable resources and trade routes, there was a slow growth of many hamlets into towns, as people and trade passed."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Fountains_flavour">"

To Romans fountains were much more than mere civic decorations. As part of the most complex water distribution system in the ancient world they were a mark of Roman civilization and technical superiority. After the excavation of Pompeii, destroyed by the explosion of Mount Vesuvius in 79 AD, many fountains were found preserved by ash. They were placed throughout the city, enjoyed by citizens and slaves alike. 

In Rome, the writings of consul Sextus Julius Frontius mention that there were 30 grand fountains throughout Rome by 98 AD and nearly 600 public basins. Pressure to drive the water up and out was achieved through the clever use of gravity and different sizes of lead piping. Pliny the Younger describes one household where the fountains sprayed their water only when the guests sat down to dinner on their ingeniously designed seats!"</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Exotic_animals_flavour">"

Exotic animals were prized for display and sport and for their pelts and skins. Some, such as camels, dogs and elephants, were trained for battle. With careful handling, dogs and elephants could cause panic in undisciplined enemies; handled badly they could wreak havoc on friends too! Seleucus Nicator, the Victor, and the founder of the Seleucid Empire, gained 500 war elephants from a peace treaty with Emperor Chandragupta of Maurya. They proved decisive in Seleucus Nicator’s victory at the Battle of Ipsus in 301 BC. 

The animal trade was highly lucrative. As the games held at Roman amphitheatres reached their peak, the arenas had an almost insatiable appetite for animal flesh. Some animal populations, even from beyond Rome’s boundaries, were driven to the edge of extinction to feed the spectacles. Eastern merchants were quite happy to take Roman coin."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_greek_Shrine_of_athena_flavour">"

Athena, goddess of wisdom, has one of the strangest origins among the gods, a group not known for conventional behaviour. Her mother, Metis, was swallowed whole by Zeus, who suffered terrible headaches afterwards. Hephaistos, the god of smiths and Zeus’ son, split open his father’s skull and Athena sprang from the wound, a fully-grown woman. 

She is the patron of wisdom, intelligence, courage as well as the arts, civilised living and just warfare. Athena often features in Greek myths as the protector and helper of heroes, in particular Odysseus, Perseus and Heracles, especially when they used cunning rather than strength. She was therefore seen as goddess of military strategy and generalship. Despite her liking for heroes she remained chaste."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Latrines_flavour">"

For Romans relieving oneself was a communal activity. The seats in a public latrine could number as many as thirty built in a square formation. There was no segregation according to class either. If an aristocrat was caught short far from home and his body-slave had forgotten the chamber pot then he would sit alongside equestrian or plebeian in the same latrine. 

In any one of the 114 latrines found in Rome people would read, chat away and ""network"" with each other. The poet Martial ridicules one man for hanging around in public toilets waiting for a dinner invitation! 

Continuing this sense of camaraderie the Romans also shared a communal sponge to clean up afterwards. The latrines were towards the bottom end of the extraordinary water system created by the Romans. After a latrine, water and its effluent contents went into the sewers.  "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Market_flavour">"

If shrines and temples are the soul of a human settlement, then its markets, bazaars and caravanserai are its stomach and heart. Commerce is essential to town and urban life, as well as continued prosperity and growth. Trade in goods and services makes all who take part richer, as long as it is honest. 

Purpose-built caravanserai show the importance of trade and the flow of goods and money. Great courtyards, surrounded by identical alcove-like stalls, they were designed to accommodate travelling merchants and trade caravans. They acted as waypoints along routes like the Silk Road and the Royal Road, re-established by Darius the Great in Asia Minor. They provided shelter, water and fodder for pack animals, and secure places to conduct business."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Training_Field_flavour">"

As well as teaching combat skills, Roman army instructors focused on fitness, discipline and moral strength. Running, athletics, swimming and forced marches increased their fitness and mental toughness until a foot soldier was capable of travelling 20 Roman miles with a full pack in under five hours. Learning to march also prepared them for keeping formation under pressure on the battlefield. 

According to the historian Vegetius, marching was the most important part of a legionary’s training. To march at great speed in a disciplined fashion while keeping formation allowed the army to cover enormous distances and instilled qualities of teamwork and endurance. All of this, however, needed practice, practice and more practice under the watchful eye of the centurions."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Practice_Castrum_flavour">"

For any Roman legionary on the march in foreign parts the day did not end when their commander decided they had marched long enough. No matter how far they had come, when the legionaries reached their destination they then had to knuckle down and build a “castrum” or camp. 

As befits Romans, these marching camps were not casual affairs. A suitable spot would be chosen and measured out to create an enclosed area of four Greek “plethora” or 3600 square metres. A ditch would then be dug all around the perimeter and an earth rampart built up with a barricade of wooden stakes on top. Spaces for each maniple or cohort were assigned according to a standard plan. All this was done in under two hours and would provide considerable fortification while on the move. 

All this work needed practice, lots and lots of lovely practice, as centurions must have explained as they hit slacking legionaries with their vine sticks."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Aqueduct_flavour">"

Aqueducts carrying water across many miles from mountain rivers and lakes into cities were among the greatest Roman achievements. The Romans perfected a technology that would not be matched even in modern times. In Rome itself over 400 kilometres of aqueducts were built to supply water to public bath houses, fountains, drinking basins and latrines. The water was also used for agriculture, mining and other industries. 

The majority of aqueducts were buried in the ground but the iconic image remains a towering bridge-like structure marching across the landscape. The largest aqueduct was the Aqua Marcia which was some 144 kilometres long and delivered 182 million litres every day. Water gushed down on the city's inhabitants: by 200 AD eleven aqueducts delivered nearly 1400 litres per person each day. This is far more than the water supplied to the average modern city dweller today. "</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Herding_Ground_flavour">"

Romans rarely ate beef except during religious feasts. Cattle were an expensive and precious commodity to any farmer. Oxen were used as beasts of burden for transport and on farms. Food production was a driving need of the expansionism the Romans undertook. Wherever they went, the Romans needed a continuous supply of food animals to support their efforts. The Romans developed animal husbandry throughout the Empire to increase yields. They also used manure on crops."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_rome_Coastal_Patrol_flavour">"

Coastal patrols were vital to protect the majority of trade routes around the Empire. The navy used smaller, faster ships such as biremes, and had naval garrisons along the coast to police the seas. Their main mission was safeguarding merchant ships against piracy, which was a huge problem in the Mediterranean. 

Julius Caesar himself was held for ransom by pirates in his youth; foolishly, they laughed at the young Caesar but, after the ransom was paid, he hunted down and crucified his captors! Eventually Rome did dominate the Mediterranean and Romans, with a typical bit of arrogance, referred to the sea as ""Mare Nostrum"" or ""Our Sea""."</string>
<string name="building_flavour_texts_flavour_twr2_rome_eastern_Dakhma_flavour">"

Excarnation, the removal of flesh by carrion birds, was a common form of funereal practice. Bodies were placed on towers with high platforms and left for the birds and elements to consume so that only the bones remained. These dakhma or ""towers of silence"" would usually be outside a settlement, as the dead were considered unclean. Bones were eventually collected and placed in ossuaries, either in the tower or at a shrine. 

In Zoroastrianism, where a body would contaminate the purity of earth and fire, the excarnated remains were placed inside a well-like structure known as an astudan;  lime and rainwater were used to disintegrate the bones. After being filtered through charcoal and sand, the water would be allowed to flow away."</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>