<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_mountain">The mountain takes its toll. Do not linger here, move off the mountain or to a road to stop attrition taking place.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_desertion">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_besieged">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_besieging">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_deap_sea">Fleets will suffer losses due to attrition when in deep waters.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_blockaded">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_besieged">The population of this besieged settlement is dying from malnutrition. Relieve the siege by any means possible, be it words or be it swords!</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_sabotage">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_disease">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_mountain">This unit is immune to mountain pass attrition.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_mountain">Armies will suffer losses due to attrition whilst crossing mountain passes.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_swamp">Armies will suffer losses due to attrition when in swamp lands.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_blockading">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_deap_sea">This unit is immune to deap sea attrition.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_sabotage">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_sabotage">An enemy agent has succeeded in sabotaging our army, many men have lost their lives. Find and kill the person responsible.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_besieged">This settlement is suffering attritional losses as it is under siege.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_deap_sea">The elements show their true power over deep waters, endlessly buffeting the fleet and bringing death to our mariners. Keep to the coastline to ensure their safety.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_regionless">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_desert">Armies will suffer losses due to attrition when in desert regions.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_blockading">Keeping the fleet out to sea hurts us as well as the enemy. End the blockade to stop this attrition.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_regionless">Your troops are deserting because you can no longer sustain them. Resolve this crisis before your forces are crippled.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_besieging">Besieging a settlement also takes its toll on the besiegers, as disease and small skirmishes claim the weak. End this siege, soon to stop this attrition.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_blockaded">Without supplies coming in from sea trade routes our settlement grows hungry. End the blockade to replenish vital supplies.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_desertion">Your troops are deserting because you can no longer sustain them. Resolve this crisis before it cripples your forces.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_disease">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_blockading">This fleet is suffering attritional losses as it is blockading.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_desert">All perish in the desert! Find a road or leave this place to stop attrition taking place.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_regionless">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_swamp">This mire claims the unwary. A wise general would find a road or leave this place.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_swamp">This unit is immune to swamp attrition.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_snow">Armies will suffer losses due to attrition when in frozen regions.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_desert">This unit is immune to desert attrition.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_disease">Disease brings death and suffering to our troops. We must appease the gods through sacrifice for the offence we have caused!</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_card_tooltip_snow">The cold makes corpses. Find a settlement, road or warmer clime to stop attrition taking place.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_desertion">placeholder</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_besieging">This army is suffering attritional losses as it is laying siege.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_campaign_map_tooltip_blockaded">This port is suffering attritional losses as it is being blockaded.</string>
<string name="campaign_map_attritions_unit_immunity_text_snow">This unit is immune to snow attrition.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>