<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_battles_carthage">Commencing 149-148BC, the Siege of Carthage was the defining action of the Third Punic War between Rome and Carthage. With the city refusing to surrender, the Carthaginians held out for over two years. The Roman forces, led by Manius Manilius, initially suffered losses at the hands of Hasdrubal and, following Manius’ failure, Scipio Aemilianus was appointed consul and charged with taking Carthage. Under Roman law, he was technically too young for the job. His first action was to defeat Diogenes’ army holding Nepheris by blockading the harbour of Carthage, cutting off their supplies, and forcing them into the field. With Nepheris crushed, Scipio intensified the main siege. In the final assault, Tiberius Gracchus, Scipio’s military tribune and brother-in-law, was the first over the wall. After hours of bitter fighting in the streets, houses and temples, the Carthaginians surrendered. The surviving population was enslaved, and Carthage levelled. Hasdrubal himself begged for mercy. His wife, unable to face such shame, killed herself and their sons. For his service, Scipio was greatly rewarded, and during his triumph was able to add “Africanus” to his name. Unusually, Hasdrubal was displayed rather than killed, possibly because of the greater humiliation involved. Despite his bravery at Carthage, Tiberius’ military fortunes waned during the Numantine War, but his later actions as a plebeian tribune earned him the favour of the common people.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_battles_carthage">The Siege of Carthage (146 BC)</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_vesuvius">Vesuvius is perhaps the most famous volcano in the world and the only one on the European mainland to have erupted in the last hundred years. Responsible for the complete destruction of the Roman cities of Pompeii and Herculaneum, the eruption of Vesuvius in 79AD killed approximately 16,000 people, including the philosopher Pliny the Elder. </string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_damavand">Mount Damavand</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_damavand">Mount Damavand is located in the Alborz mountain range and is the highest peak in Iran. Its impressive height and volcanic nature made it a place of magic and power in Persian mythology. According to Zoroastrian texts it was the home of the three-headed dragon Azi Dahaka, who was imprisoned there until the end of days. </string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_vesuvius">Mount Vesuvius</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_colossus">The Colossus of Rhodes</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_behistun">Located in the Kermanshah Province of Iran, Mount Behistun is home to the Behistun Inscription. This multilingual inscription includes an autobiography of Darius the Great. As the same piece of text was translated into three different languages, Old Persian, Elamite, and Babylonian, it is similar to the Rosetta Stone as the key to languages thought to be lost.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_behistun">Mount Behistun</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_colossus">The Colossus of Rhodes was a giant bronze statue constructed to commemorate the Rhodian victory against Antigonus I, ruler of Cyprus.  A representation of the sun god Helios, it stood over thirty metres high, but not astride the harbour as has been suggested. It is thought to have fallen during an earthquake in 226BC. The broken chunks of statue were eventually sold off as scrap metal some 800 years later.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_hercules">According to Greek legend, the Pillars of Hercules were created by Hercules himself as one of his twelve labours. Rather than waste time scaling the mountain that had once been Atlas, Hercules punched through it, so joining the Mediterranean Sea to the Atlantic Ocean and creating the Strait of Gibraltar.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_hercules">The Pillars of Hercules</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_sanctuary">Located on the island of Samothrace off the coast of Greece, the Sanctuary of the Great Gods was home to a strange religion known as the Eleusinian Mysteries.  The Spartan leader, Lysander, the historian Herodotus, and King Philip II of Macedon, who met his future wife and mother of his son Alexander the Great at the site, were all initiates of the mysteries.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_sanctuary">The Sanctuary of the Great Gods</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_stonehenge">Stonehenge</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_stonehenge">Stonehenge has always been shrouded in mystery. Standing alone on the plains of Wiltshire in southern England, the huge standing stones are thought to have been erected sometime between 3000BC and 2000BC. As little archaeological evidence has been found, historians have been unable to conclusively define exactly how it was built and what it was used for.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_mausoleum">Commissioned by Artemisia II of Caria, the Mausoleum was built in honour of her dead husband Mausolus. The sides of the temple were adorned with reliefs by the greatest Greek sculptors of the day: Leochares, Bryaxis, Scopas and Timotheus. The top housed a great bronze chariot that contained statues of Artemisia and Mausolus himself.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_mausoleum">The Mausoleum at Hallicarnassus</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_citadel">The Bam Citadel is located in modern day Iran and was the largest sand and clay structure in the world until it was devastated by an earthquake in 2003. A marvel of architecture and engineering, it even had a very early form of air conditioning. Large towers caught the wind and funnelled it down into the buildings below.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_babylon">The great city of Babylon was home to some impressive architecture. There was the huge Ishtar Gate, an ancient wonder until it was replaced by the Pharos, the Ziggurat of Marduk, an impressive temple precinct in the heart of the city; and, last but not least, the legendary Hanging Gardens.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_oracle">Located near the Egyptian border with Libya, the walls of the temple of Amun-Re still stand to this day. In order to reach the temple travellers had to cross a vast and dangerous desert and there are many legends about whole armies disappearing beneath the sands before they could reach it.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_pharos">The Pharos of Alexandria</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_olympus">Mount Olympus</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_battles_raphia">The Battle of Raphia in 217BC was fought in the Fourth Syrian War between Ptolemaic Egypt and the Seleucid Empire. Control of Syria and its extremely useful Mediterranean coast changed hands many times in the space of a century. As Successors to, and masters of portions of, Alexander’s empire, the Ptolemaic and Seleucid dynasties could not cede control of Syria to the other party: it would have been a sign of weakness. This brought them into conflict time and time again, and, in June 217BC, the two mightiest Greek-style armies ever seen led by King Ptolemy IV Philopator, and King Antiochus III the Great, clashed at Raphia. After days of skirmishing, the battle proper began with a charge of war elephants from both sides. Antiochus drove off the Ptolemaic cavalry and pursued them, thinking the battle was won. By the time he returned to the field his own centre had broken and was in disarray. His troops fled, and the battle was lost. Ptolemy IV’s victory was not without problems. He did retain control of much of Syria but the cost weakened his position at home. His Egyptian veterans rebelled and established a separate kingdom in the southern part of Upper Egypt. The secessionists, and the rebel 35th ruling dynasty, were finally crushed in 185BC. In keeping with Egyptian tradition, the victorious Greek-dominated government destroyed any mention of the rebels that they could find.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_olympia">"The Statue of Zeus was said to be thirteen metres tall, made of ivory and gold, and sculptured by The Great Pheidias, considered by many to be the finest sculptor of the classical world. It is said that Pheidias immortalised his lover Pantarkes by carving ""Pantarkes kalos"" into Zeus’ little finger."</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_argaeus">"The Greek geographer Strabo wrote that Mount Argaeus was ""The highest mountain of all… those who make the ascent say... both seas, that of Pontus and that of Issus, are visible."" This huge volcano sits south of Kayseri in modern-day Turkey, and discoveries of Roman coins suggest that it last erupted in 253BC."</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_battles_teutobergerwald">The Battle of Teutoburg Forest (AD 9)</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_karnag">The village of Carnac in Brittany, France, is home to one of the most impressive megalithic sites in the world. Standing stones and dolmens cover a huge area and a number of theories have been put forward to explain the precise positions of these huge lumps of stone. Some believe that the standing stones map the stars in the night sky, while others argue that the dolmens may have been ancient earthquake detectors.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_rostam">The Necropolis of Rostam</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_citadel">The Bam Citadel</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_battles_intro">Once you have selected historical battles from the main menu, mouse over the title of each battle for a short description, then click on a crossed swords symbol to play that battle. The following battles are included:</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_babylon">The Great City of Babylon</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_rostam">This impressive temple complex is hewn from the mountain itself and is thought to be the final resting place of the Persian kings Darius I the Great, Xerxes I, Artaxerxes I, and Darius II. The site is also home to some impressive reliefs, the oldest of which dates back to 1000 BC and is thought to have given the site its name, Naqsh-e Rostam or Picture of Rostam. </string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_olympus">Mount Olympus is the tallest mountain in Greece and according to legend was the home of the gods. It was here that Zeus held court and toyed with the lives and fates of mortal men. The great thrones on which Zeus and Queen Hera sat were made by their son Hephaestus, the crippled smith god who also made Zeus’ lightning bolts.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_karnag">The Dolmens of Karnag</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_olympia">The Statue of Zeus at Olympia</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_battles_intro">Historical Battles</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_argaeus">Mount Argaeus</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_battles_teutobergerwald">One of Rome’s most bitter defeats, Teutoburg was the culmination of years of rebellion and politicking among the Germanic tribes. In all, three legions, the XVII, XVIII, and XIX, under Publius Quinctilius Varus, were lost when they walked into an ambush set by Arminius, a “trusted friend” of Rome. A chieftain of the Cherusci and an advisor to Varus, Arminius had been taken as a hostage to Rome, and later schooled in Roman military tactics. On the narrow and muddy forest tracks he directed them to take, beset by storms, the legions became strung out and easy prey for the waiting German warriors. Trying to regain control and impetus, Varus did manage to rally his legions and fortify a night camp, before breaking out the next morning. The escape was costly and, after a gruelling night march, the final slaughter saw the Romans squeezed between woodland and bogs on a narrow spit of land. Varus’ senior officer, Numonius Vala, fled with the remaining cavalry, and was cut down. Varus himself committed suicide. With three legions slaughtered, Roman forts and towns east of the Rhine were overrun. The shame of this defeat meant that the three lost legion numbers were never used again.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_battles_raphia">The Battle of Raphia (217BC)</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_pharos">The Pharos, or lighthouse, of Alexandria was built sometime between 280BC and 247BC and commissioned by Ptolemy I. According to legend, its light could be seen 100 miles out to sea and the light itself was created using a giant mirror that harnessed the rays of the sun and could be used to burn enemy ships.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_oracle">The Oracle of Amun-Re</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_etna">One of the most active volcanoes in the world, Etna, on Sicily, was the mythical location of Hephaestus’ forge, which may explain the mountain’s name, which originated from the Phoenician word ‘attuna’, meaning furnace. It was also the prison of Typhon, “the father of monsters”, who was cast down by Zeus.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_etna">Mount Etna</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_wonders_giza">The Necropolis of Giza</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_wonders_giza">Situated on the Giza plateau, just outside Cairo, the Giza Necropolis is still home to two of the most iconic images of Ancient Egypt, the Great Pyramid and the Sphinx. The Great Pyramid was the oldest of the ancient wonders of the world and is the only one that still stands today. </string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_content_enc_text_hist_battles_nile">The Battle of the Nile in 47BC was a clash between the armies of Julius Caesar and Ptolemy XIII, the younger brother and husband of Cleopatra VII. Ptolemy had enraged Caesar in 48BC by executing Pompey the Great who had fled to Egypt; Pompey may have been a rival, but he was a Roman and Caesar’s son-in-law. Over the following months, relations went from bad to worse. In Alexandria Caesar tried to broker a peace between Ptolemy and Cleopatra. Ptolemy’s troops were trying to isolate the Romans, and were gaining the upper hand. When Caesar heard that reinforcements were nearby he marched away from Alexandria in the hope of uniting his forces. He was successful and turned on Ptolemy’s Egyptian army. The two armies, with roughly comparable forces, met on the banks of the Nile and, in true Roman style, Caesar launched the first attack. After fierce fighting the Egyptians broke and many of them fled, including Ptolemy. According to some accounts he drowned when his ship capsized on the Nile; regardless of the details, he was safely dead and no longer a problem. Caesar had brought Egypt within the Roman sphere of influence and gained the personal gratitude of Egypt’s newly-undisputed ruler, Cleopatra.</string>
<string name="encyclopedia_historical_info_blocks_heading_enc_text_hist_battles_nile">The Battle of the Nile (47BC)</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>