<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="formations_name_mel_dbl_heavy_centre">Heavy Melee Double</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_triple_line_melee">Melee Front Triple Line||Arranges units in three lines with melee infantry in the front, missile infantry in the middle and cavalry at the back.</string>
<string name="formations_name_river_defence">River Defence</string>
<string name="formations_name_torc">Torc</string>
<string name="formations_name_bird">Bird</string>
<string name="formations_name_spear">Spear</string>
<string name="formations_name_wedge">Wedge</string>
<string name="formations_name_mel_dbl_light_centre">Flanking Melee Double</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_double_line_land">Double Line||Arranges units in two lines without placing them based on their type.</string>
<string name="formations_name_wheel">Wheel</string>
<string name="formations_name_flank">Flank</string>
<string name="formations_name_bear">Bear</string>
<string name="formations_name_boar">Boar</string>
<string name="formations_name_horse">Horse</string>
<string name="formations_name_deer">Deer</string>
<string name="formations_name_spear_point">Spear Point</string>
<string name="formations_description_simplex_acies">A basic army formation with well-spaced spearmen in the front row, equally spaced melee infantry behind with cavalry at the back and missile infantry deployed out front.</string>
<string name="formations_description_triplex_acies">An army formation that places melee infantry in three lines, with the lightest in the front and spearmen in the last line. Missile infantry are deployed in front with cavalry at the rear on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_name_issus">Issus</string>
<string name="formations_name_mis_dbl_light_centre">Flanking Missile Double</string>
<string name="formations_description_spear_point">An army formation with heavy infantry in the front, light infantry on the flanks with cavalry in the rear. Chariots are deployed in the flanks of the front row.</string>
<string name="formations_description_double_acies">An army formation with two well-spaced lines of melee infantry with spearmen on the flanks and cavalry behind. Missile infantry form a screen at the front.</string>
<string name="formations_name_wolf">Wolf</string>
<string name="formations_name_zama">Zama</string>
<string name="formations_name_mis_dbl_heavy_centre">Heavy Missile Double</string>
<string name="formations_description_mel_dbl_light_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_description_column">Arranges units in a column. Useful for crossing rivers or for advancing into settlements. Places missile infantry in the front, melee infantry in the middle and cavalry in the rear.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mis_light_centre">Flanking Missile Single||Create a strong battery of missile fire in your centre, with melee ships poised to close in from the flanks.||The further from the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_caucasian">Caucasian||An army formation with missile infantry in front followed by a line of light infantry with light cavalry on the flanks then a line of heavy infantry with heavy cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_mel_dbl_heavy_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_double_line_sorted">Double Line Sorted||Arranges units in two lines with missile infantry put into the front row, melee infantry in the second with cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mis_heavy_centre">Heavy Missile Single||Shatter the enemy's centre with missile fire whilst your heavy melee ships close in on their flanks.||The closer to the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_description_bird">An army formation with heavy infantry in front and light infantry behind them. In turn, missile infantry flank the light infantry, with cavalry on the extreme flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_torc">An army formation with heavy infantry in front, light infantry in the second line and on the flanks. Chariots are placed at the back with cavalry in the last line on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_triple_line_missile">Arranges units in three lines with missile infantry in the front, melee infantry in the middle and cavalry at the back.</string>
<string name="formations_name_triple_line_missile">Missile Front Triple Line</string>
<string name="formations_description_issus">An army formation with a main line of pikemen with heavy infantry t the right and light infantry to the left. Cavalry and missile infantry are positioned on the flanks. Based on the tactic used by Alexander the Great at the Battle of Issus.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_magnesia">Magnesia||An army formation with mixed blocks of pike infantry and elephants in the middle. Melee infantry and spearmen sit on the flanks along with missile infantry and cavalry.</string>
<string name="formations_name_triplex_acies">Triplex Acies</string>
<string name="formations_name_simplex_acies">Simplex Acies</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_armenian">Armenian||This formation places heavy melee infantry at its centre flanked by light melee infantry. Missile infantry are positioned in front, with heavy and light melee cavalry behind.</string>
<string name="formations_description_double_sailing">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_crescent">Crescent||The battle line bows inwards, drawing the enemy fleet into the centre, allowing you to encircle and trap them.</string>
<string name="formations_name_double_line_sorted">Double Line Sorted</string>
<string name="formations_description_horse">An army formation with spear infantry flanked with light cavalry in the main line, missile infantry in front and melee infantry and heavy cavalry behind.</string>
<string name="formations_description_cannae">An army formation with a light infantry centre flanked by heavy infantry. Missile infantry form the front row and cavalry are placed in the rear. Based on the formation used by Hannibal at the Battle of Cannae where he inflicted a massive defeat on a larger Roman army.</string>
<string name="formations_description_triple_line_cavalry">Arranges units in three lines with cavalry in front, missile infantry in the middle and melee infantry at the back.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_sailing">Battle Line||A standard battle line, with heavy ships forming the centre, and light and missile ships taking up the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_deer">A two-line formation with missile infantry in front, light infantry behind and light cavalry on the flanks. Heavy infantry and cavalry make up the last line.</string>
<string name="formations_description_trebia">An army formation with light infantry in the main line, heavy infantry behind and missile infantry out in front. Elephants are placed on the flanks long with the cavalry.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mis_double_line">Missile Double Line||A two-deep formation that arranges your fleet with missile ships at the fore and melee ships at the rear.</string>
<string name="formations_description_flank">An army formation with missile cavalry in front, light cavalry behind and heavy cavalry on the flank. </string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_single_line_sorted">Sorted Single Line||Arranges units in a single line with melee infantry in the middle, missile infantry beside them and cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_bear">An army formation that places heavy melee infantry in the centre flanked by light melee infantry. Heavy cavalry are on the flanks of the front line supported by light cavalry. Missile infantry make up the second row with reserve infantry behind.</string>
<string name="formations_description_boar">An army formation with spear infantry in the centre flanked by melee infantry. Missile infantry form the front row and cavalry sit on the extreme flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_name_single_line">Single Line</string>
<string name="formations_description_raphia">An army formation with a main line of pikemen with heavy infantry to the left and light infantry to the right. Cavalry are positioned on the flanks with missile infantry in front and elephants on the flanks as well. This formation is based on how the Seleucid and Ptolemaic armies fought at the Battle of Raphia.</string>
<string name="formations_description_wolf">An army formation with heavy infantry in the main line with missile infantry in front. Heavy cavalry flank the heavy infantry with light infantry and then light cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_diekplous">Diekplous||A formation of multiple columns, designed to break into the enemy line and pin their fleet into one-on-one engagements.||Best used against a single row fleet.</string>
<string name="formations_description_wheel">An army formation with a hollow centre. Heavy infantry are placed in the front behind chariots, with light infantry behind and missile infantry on their flanks. Light cavalry are placed behind and to the side of the missile infantry with melee cavalry at the back of the formation.</string>
<string name="formations_description_single_line">Arranges units in an unorganised single line. Useful for quickly getting units into a line.</string>
<string name="formations_description_zama">An army formation with missile infantry out in front of light infantry and then heavy infantry behind them. Elephants make up the next line with cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_name_single_line_sorted">Sorted Single Line</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mel_heavy_centre">Heavy Melee Single||Punch through the enemy line with your heavy melee ships and use your missile ships to harass their flanks.||The closer to the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_persian">Persian||An army formation with missile in the front line with light cavalry on the flanks and then a second line of melee infantry with heavy cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_wedge">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_description_mis_dbl_heavy_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mel_light_centre">Flanking Melee Single||Present a strong attacking front to the enemy's centre with your melee ships, whilst your missile ships cover the flanks.||The further from the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_skirmish">Skirmish||An army formation with missile infantry in the front line flanked by missile cavalry. Melee infantry form the second line with melee cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_spear">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_description_mis_dbl_light_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_description_centre">An army formation with missile cavalry making up the front line. Heavy cavalry are positioned behind them with light cavalry covering their flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_name_triple_line_cavalry">Cavalry Front Triple Line</string>
<string name="formations_description_river_defence">A simple formation with melee infantry in the centre, missile infantry on the flanks and cavalry behind to defend river crossings.</string>
<string name="formations_name_double_acies">Double Acies</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mel_double_line">Melee Double Line||A two-deep formation that arranges your fleet with melee ships at the fore and missile ships at the rear.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_wedge">Wedge||Stab through the enemy line with your forward melee ships. This will give you room to manoeuvre and rake their decks with fire before boarding.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_centre">Centre||An army formation with missile cavalry making up the front line. Heavy cavalry are positioned behind them with light cavalry covering their flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_name_raphia">Raphia</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_triple_line_missile">Missile Front Triple Line||Arranges units in three lines with missile infantry in the front, melee infantry in the middle and cavalry at the back.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_deer">Deer||A two-line formation with missile infantry in front, light infantry behind and light cavalry on the flanks. Heavy infantry and cavalry make up the last line.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_wheel">Wheel||An army formation with a hollow centre. Heavy infantry are placed in the front behind chariots, with light infantry behind and missile infantry on their flanks. Light cavalry are placed behind and to the side of the missile infantry with melee cavalry at the back of the formation.</string>
<string name="formations_description_diekplous">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_name_triple_line_melee">Melee Front Triple Line</string>
<string name="formations_name_trebia">Trebia</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_river_defence">River Defence||A simple formation with melee infantry in the centre, missile infantry on the flanks and cavalry behind to defend river crossings.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_spear">Spear||Drive a hole through the enemy's line with heavy capital ships at the point, melee ships at the centre and missile support at the rear.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_bear">Bear||This formation places heavy melee infantry at its centre flanked by light melee infantry. Heavy cavalry are on the flanks of the front line, supported by light cavalry. Missile infantry make up the second row with reserve infantry behind.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_boar">Boar||An army formation with spear infantry in the centre flanked by melee infantry. Missile infantry form the front row and cavalry sit on the extreme flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_raphia">Raphia||An army formation with a main line of pikemen with heavy infantry to the left and light infantry to the right. Cavalry are positioned on the flanks with missile infantry in front and elephants on the flanks as well.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_flank">Flank||An army formation with missile cavalry at the front, light cavalry behind and heavy cavalry on the flank. </string>
<string name="formations_name_centre">Centre</string>
<string name="formations_description_mel_heavy_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mis_dbl_heavy_centre">Heavy Missile Double||A powerful, two-deep central battery of missile ships, designed to break an enemy's line apart, with melee ships either side to push through.||The closer to the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_wolf">Wolf||An army formation with heavy infantry in the main line with missile infantry in front. Heavy cavalry flank the heavy infantry with light infantry and then light cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_zama">Zama||An army formation with missile infantry out in front of light infantry and then heavy infantry behind them. Elephants make up the next line with cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_single_line_sorted">Arranges units in a single line with melee infantry in the middle, missile infantry beside them and cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_trebia">Trebia||An army formation with light infantry in the main line, heavy infantry behind and missile infantry out in front. Elephants are placed on the flanks long with the cavalry.</string>
<string name="formations_description_skirmish">An army formation with missile infantry in the front line flanked by missile cavalry. Melee infantry form the second line with melee cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_mel_light_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mis_dbl_light_centre">Flanking Missile Double||Melee ships at the centre of this two-deep formation can push into either side of an enemy fleet whilst the central battery attacks the pinned-down forces.||The further from the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mel_dbl_light_centre">Flanking Melee Double||A two-deep core of melee ships designed to smash through an enemy's centre and split their formation. Missile ships dominate the flanks.||The further from the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_name_persian">Persian</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_cannae">Cannae||An army formation with a light infantry centre flanked by heavy infantry. Missile infantry form the front row and cavalry are placed at the rear.</string>
<string name="formations_name_double_line_land">Double Line</string>
<string name="formations_description_mis_light_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_issus">Issus||An army formation with a main line of pikemen with heavy infantry to the right and light infantry to the left. Cavalry and missile infantry are positioned on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_double_sailing">Double Line||A strong attacking front. Two rows, with missile ships at the flanks and rear, with melee ships at the centre.</string>
<string name="formations_description_sailing">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_bird">Bird||An army formation with heavy infantry in front and light infantry behind them. In turn, missile infantry flank the light infantry, with cavalry on the extreme flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_torc">Torc||An army formation with heavy infantry in front, light infantry in the second line and on the flanks. Chariots are placed at the back with cavalry in the last line along the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_triple_line_cavalry">Cavalry Front Triple Line||Arranges units in three lines with cavalry in front, missile infantry in the middle and melee infantry at the back.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_horse">Horse||An army formation with spear infantry flanked with light cavalry in the main line, missile infantry at the front and melee infantry and heavy cavalry behind.</string>
<string name="formations_name_mel_double_line">Melee Double Line</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_mel_dbl_heavy_centre">Heavy Melee Double||A two-deep formation designed to hammer through the enemy line with a strong melee core. Missile ships provide coverage on either side.||The closer to the centre, the heavier the ship.</string>
<string name="formations_description_mis_double_line">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_name_column">Column</string>
<string name="formations_description_mis_heavy_centre">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_description_armenian">An army formation which puts heavy melee infantry in the centre flanked by light melee infantry, missile infantry in front and with heavy melee cavalry behind and the heavy cavalry are flanked by light melee cavalry.</string>
<string name="formations_name_mis_double_line">Missile Double Line</string>
<string name="formations_description_magnesia">An army formation with mixed blocks of pike infantry and elephants in the middle. Melee infantry and spearmen on the flanks along with missile infantry and cavalry. Used by the Seleucids against the Romans at the Battle of Magnesia. </string>
<string name="formations_description_mel_double_line">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_description_double_line_sorted">Arranges units in two lines with missile infantry put into the front row, melee infantry in the second with cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_name_cannae">Cannae</string>
<string name="formations_name_sailing">Battle Line</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_single_line">Single Line||Arranges units in an unorganised single line.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_column">Column||Arranges units in a column with missile infantry in front, melee infantry in the middle and cavalry at the rear.</string>
<string name="formations_name_double_sailing">Double Line</string>
<string name="formations_description_crescent">PLACEHOLDER</string>
<string name="formations_description_persian">An army formation with missile in the front line with light cavalry on the flanks and then a second line of melee infantry with heavy cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_description_caucasian">An army formation with missile infantry in front followed by a line of light infantry with light cavalry on the flanks then a line of heavy infantry with heavy cavalry on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_name_caucasian">Caucasian</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_double_acies">Double Acies||An army formation with two well-spaced lines of melee infantry with spearmen on the flanks and cavalry behind. Missile infantry form a screen at the front.</string>
<string name="formations_name_mel_light_centre">Flanking Melee Single</string>
<string name="formations_name_skirmish">Skirmish</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_triplex_acies">Triplex Acies||An army formation that places melee infantry in three lines, with the lightest in the front and spearmen in the last line. Missile infantry are deployed in front with cavalry at the rear on the flanks.</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_simplex_acies">Simplex Acies||A basic army formation with well-spaced spearmen in the front row, equally spaced melee infantry behind with cavalry at the back and missile infantry deployed out front.</string>
<string name="formations_name_mel_heavy_centre">Heavy Melee Single</string>
<string name="formations_name_mis_heavy_centre">Heavy Missile Single </string>
<string name="formations_name_mis_light_centre">Flanking Missile Single</string>
<string name="formations_description_double_line_land">Arranges units in two lines without placing them based on their type. This formation is good for quickly putting units of the same type into two lines.</string>
<string name="formations_description_triple_line_melee">Arranges units in three lines with melee infantry in the front, missile infantry in the middle and cavalry at the back.</string>
<string name="formations_name_crescent">Crescent</string>
<string name="formations_name_diekplous">Diekplous</string>
<string name="formations_name_armenian">Armenian</string>
<string name="formations_name_magnesia">Magnesia</string>
<string name="formations_tooltip_spear_point">Spear Point||An army formation with heavy infantry in the front, light infantry on the flanks with cavalry in the rear. Chariots are deployed on the flanks of the front row.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>