<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_kill_character_zeal_wound">Your dignitary wounded their enemy while fending off an attack. There was some provocation…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_kill_character_wound">Your agent has been wounded in action against the enemy. They will need to recover before they can serve again. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_army_gains_level">The brave men of this army have known many victories: only their courage facing the enemy exceeds their skill at arms.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_kill_character_success">Your agent has assassinated their target! A crushing blow to the enemy!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_province_contested">You no longer control the whole of this province. Its potential has been compromised.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_settlement_success">An enemy agent has committed an act of sabotage in your settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_speciality_resource_acquired">You have acquired an important resource, providing you with new economic and military opportunities.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_food_shortage">There is a shortage of food across your lands. The people struggle to eat and whisper of your failures as leader. You can exempt your hungriest provinces from tax to remove them from the food system, and your advisers suggest that it might be wise to invest in more food-producing buildings. Consult the provinces list for details.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_kill_character_subterfuge_success">The enemy mourns a loyal servant. Your champion struck without a moment's hesitation. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_kill_character_authority_wound">Your loyal subject has been wounded, after an attempt on their life. Evidence found on the attacker's body suggests that the traitor was working for an enemy spy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_army_fail">An enemy agent has failed to disrupt one of your armies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_building_your_legendary_built_generic">The following legendary building has been completed:</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_kill_character_zeal_success">Your champion's attack robbed the enemy of loyal servant.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_settlement_authority_success">Your dignitary has incited rebellious feelings within a settlement, disrupted public order and made a rebellion more likely.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_your_general_wounded_politics">This man has been wounded in an assassination attempt by one of his own people. Treachery should be punished!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_faction_destroyed_them">This faction has been destroyed. Their enemies were too numerous.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_fleet_gains_level">This fleet has won many victories. The brave crews will be remembered for their great and valorous acts. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_army_zeal_success">An enemy dignitary has threatened your army with destruction, diminishing the troops' fervour.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_client_state_broken_by_client">This faction refused protection of its overlord. It is no longer a client state.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_faction_destroyed_minor">Your forces have trampled this faction into the dust!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_army_success">Your agent has committed an act of subversion against an enemy army.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_gains_level">This diligent man has a wealth of experience and continues to hone his abilities.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_settlement_success">Your agent has disrupted an enemy settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_kill_character_subterfuge_wound">An enemy champion has wounded your loyal subject. The cowardly attempt to assassinate with a hail of arrows failed, but wounds will will need time to heal.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_settlement_besieged_port">Your port settlement is under siege. Should a blockade stop the flow of supplies entirely, the populace will face starvation and may be compelled to surrender. Sally out with local forces or bring reinforcements to attack the besiegers!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ceasefire_declared_them">These two factions have set aside their differences and stopped fighting.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_faction_destroyed_them_minor">This faction has been destroyed. The people scatter to the winds.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_swamp">Your army suffered casualties while negotiating treacherous swamps.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_client_state_broken_by_client_yours_manipulated">Your client state has cast aside your protection. It is whispered that the lies of others led them to this…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_edict_cancelled_imperium_drop">A decline in your faction's imperium has diminished your authority. Consequently, the governor of this province can no longer carry out your edict.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_camp_unrest_rebellion">Extreme unhappiness in this province has driven the people to rebel!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_kill_character_authority_success">Your dignitary's rewards sent the greatest assassins to our enemy's door. The target is dead.  </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_speciality_wonder_discovered">You have captured a wonder! People will come from far and wide to gaze upon its magnificence! </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_authority_stop">The enemy has tried to convince your agent to betray you. Loyalty won, but your agent has been hindered by the enemy's actions.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_war_coordination_target_not_available">Your target is no longer available thanks to recent events.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_army_embarked_destroyed">Your transport fleet has been destroyed. All vessels were lost after the destruction of the escorting war fleet.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_discovered_theirs">Your forces have found a concealed foreign agent. Be wary of their intentions.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_recruited">A new agent is ready and awaiting orders.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_populace_happy">The people of this province are happy with their current circumstances.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_enemy_army_withdraws">The enemy is in full retreat, overmatched by your might!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_army_zeal_success">Your spy destroyed supplies in the enemy baggage train. The equipment lost diminishes their combat effectiveness.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_subject_message_subject_leaves">The significance of one of your subjects has declined. They no longer have any influence over your affairs.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_placeholder">[DO NOT LOCALISE]</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_sea_region_raided">The enemy fleet raiding this port settlement is having a negative effect on public order and the local economy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_dies_navy_destroyed">This intrepid admiral has gone down with his ship. His great deeds will be remembered.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_settlement_success">Your agent carried out an act of sabotage in an enemy settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_settlement_authority_success">An enemy champion has caused dissension amongst the slaves in your settlement, making a servile uprising a possibility.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_settlement_success">An enemy agent has committed an act of disruption within one of your settlements.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_army_fail">Your agent failed to sabotage an enemy army.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_fleet_destroyed">Your fleet was destroyed by enemy forces. All was lost. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_settlement_authority_success">An enemy dignitary has used loathesome lies to turn your people against you. The province may now rebel.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_enemy_navy_withdraws">Unable to match your strength, the enemy fleet has withdrawn.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_camp_unrest_imminent_rebellion">Public order in this province is critically low! The people are unhappy and rebellion is certain unless action is taken.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_barbarian_edict_cancelled_region_lost">This province is no longer united under your banner. Consequently, the chiefs of this province can no longer carry out your edict.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_settlement_surrenders">This settlement has surrendered to the enemy! You have lost any local military and economic benefits it gave.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_your_general_disbanded_ready">This man has returned home from his command. He will engage in faction politics until called upon to lead your forces once again.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_military_access_cancelled_manipulated">This faction has been manipulated into breaking its military access pact with you.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_kill_character_zeal_wound">Your loyal subject, was provoked and has been wounded in an altercation with an enemy dignitary.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_kill_character_zeal_wound">An enemy champion has tried to murder your loyal subject. The attack failed, but the target was wounded.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_lost_destroyed_with_character">Following the patron's death this ancillary has been lost.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_trade_route_raided">Enemy raids on your trade routes are depriving you of trade income.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_kill_character_authority_wound">An enemy traitor, working for your spy, has failed in a task. Instead of killing the target, they merely inflicted wounds.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_kill_character_subterfuge_success">A treacherous enemy dignitary, having secured the trust of your subject, has betrayed and murdered them.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_wounded">Your agent has been wounded in action. He will need time to recover before returning to service.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_dies_natural_causes">This man has reached the end of his days and is at peace.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_you_maintain_republic_carthage">The civil war is over! The power-mad pretenders are beaten, and democracy is restored to Carthage.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_kill_character_subterfuge_success">Your loyal subject as been murdered by an enemy champion. The coward shot them down from afar, afraid of single combat.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_region_captured">You now control this settlement. If your influence in this province is sufficient, you can develop the settlement to suit your needs.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_your_general_killed_politics">This man has been betrayed by those closest to him and assassinated.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_capital_recaptured">You have reclaimed your capital! The people rejoice! The streets echo with celebrations.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_kill_character_success">An enemy agent has assassinated one of your people. They must pay! </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_success">Your agent has convinced an enemy subject to defect. They now serve you.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_zeal_success">Your feeble and oh-so-loyal agent has betrayed you and joined the enemy. Treachery should not go unpunished!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_civilised_campmap_your_general_killed">This great man has died valiantly in battle. His bravery will be remembered.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_region_captured">Your settlement has fallen into enemy hands! If you do not recapture it you will lose its military and economic benefits.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_army_subterfuge_success">Your army's provisions have been poisoned by an enemy spy. Many troops are ill and some have died.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_lost_natural_causes">This ancillary character has died of natural causes.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_killed_with_navy">Your agent has gone down with the fleet. Rescue was not possible.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_edict_issued"> Word has been received: the governor of this province will carry out your edict until you command otherwise.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campaign_won">You stand triumphant! Your name and deeds will be remembered forever.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_settlement_subterfuge_success">By bribery your dignitary has convinced merchants to cease trading in the enemy's settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_settlement_subterfuge_success">Your champion's daring raid against the settlement wreaked havoc and freed a number of slaves.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_barbarian_campmap_your_general_killed">This noble warrior has died valiantly in battle. Tonight he dines with the glorious dead, but who will lead his warriors?</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_fail">Rivals have attempted to coax one of your agents into joining them. But your agent remains loyal… for now.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campaign_lost">All that was once yours lies in ruins. Your people beg the gods for mercy but the gods are deaf. Your rule will be little more than a footnote in the histories.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_kill_character_subterfuge_wound">Your spy failed to kill the target. The dose, however, was enough to wound…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_client_state_broken_by_overlord">This faction is no longer protecting its former client state.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_faction_joins_your_enemies_diplomatic">This faction has been manipulated into joining an alliance against you, further threatening you and increasing your enemies' strength.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_stop">One of your agents has been hindered by a rival's attempt to change their allegiance. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_unit_recruited">A unit has been recruited and is ready to serve.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_kill_character_authority_success">A traitor, working for your spy, has successfully eliminated the enemy target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_army_success">An enemy agent has disrupted one of your armies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_faction_confederated">This tribe has agreed to join forces with you. The confederation will strengthen your peoples and strike fear into enemy hearts!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_army_success">An enemy agent has subverted one of your armies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_enemy_naval_invasion">An enemy army has landed within your territory.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ally_attacked">Your ally is under attack. Will you join them?</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_kill_character_authority_success">Your valiant champion has vanquished the enemy in single combat.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_satrapy_broken_by_overlord_yours_manipulated">You are vulnerable, as your now-former overlord no offers protection. This sudden change of heart must be the work of an unknown enemy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_kill_character_subterfuge_wound">Your loyal subject has been betrayed by an unscrupulous enemy dignitary. The target will live, but will need time to recover. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_subterfuge_stop">Your agent did not get the enemy to join your cause. Nevertheless, the enemy's progress was slowed.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_you_lost_rome">Rome, the Eternal City, has been captured! You must retake it at once!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_lost_killed_with_character">This ancillary character has been killed along with their patron.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_settlement_zeal_success">An enemy arson attack has severely damaged a building in your settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_gains_level_female">This tireless lady has a wealth of experience and continues to hone her abilities.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ambush_failed">Your army was spotted by the enemy before it could spring an ambush against them.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_dies_natural_causes_female">This lady has reached the end of her days and is at peace.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_army_success">Your agent has disrupted an enemy army.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_wounded_female">Your agent has been wounded in action. She will need time to heal before returning to your service.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_kill_character_subterfuge_wound">Your loyal subject has narrowly escaped slow, painful death. A return to full health will not be quick. An enemy spy tried to use poison.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_building_constructed">The following building has been completed:</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_military_tech_advance">You have completed a technological advancement, giving you an advantage over your rivals.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_your_general_returns_to_capital">This man has been wounded, and will need time to heal.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_subterfuge_stop">Your loyal agent has been hindered by an enemy attempt to change their loyalty. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_army_authority_success">Your champion's impressive show of force demoralised the enemy. Strike. and they will crumble before your might!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_killed_with_army">Your agent has been slain during the total destruction of the army in which they served.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_client_state_declared">This faction has become a client state. In return for their tribute they are protected by their new overlord.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_army_zeal_success">An enemy spy has infiltrated your baggage train and wrecked the supplies. Damage to the army's equipment has diminished their effectiveness.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_military_access_prompt">Your military access pact with this faction is about to end. A new pact is needed if you want further access to their lands.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_trespass_foreign_land">Your troops have entered another's lands without a military access pact. If they linger, and you don't gain such a pact, you may incur this faction's wrath!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_authority_stop">Although your agent was unable to persuade the enemy to join your cause, they were able to hinder the enemy's progress. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_settlement_subterfuge_success">An enemy champion has brutally attacked and devastated your settlement. To add insult a number of slaves escaped in the chaos. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_slums">As a result of ruin or neglect, slums have developed in this settlement. Work will be needed if the slums are to be removed.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_gained_character_without_ancillary">This character has gained an ancillary. It has been assigned directly to them. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_kill_character_authority_success">The price on your loyal subject's head has been collected.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_nonaggression_broken_yours_manipulated">This faction has been manipulated into breaking its non-aggression pact with you. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_gained_other">Your faction has gained an ancillary. It has been added to the reserves to await assignment.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_blockading">Your fleet has suffered losses but maintains the blockade against an enemy port.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_development">The population surplus in this province has grown. You can now expand one of its settlements to construct more buildings.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_faction_encountered_you">You have encountered a new faction. Diplomacy with them is now possible.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_war_declared">Actions replace words: diplomacy has failed, and these two factions are at war to settle their differences.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_settlement_success">An enemy agent has committed an act of subversion in one of your settlements.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_kill_character_zeal_wound">Despite a swift, merciless attack your champion only wounded the enemy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_alliance_broken">The alliance between these factions has been broken.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_success">Your agent has listened to the honeyed words of the enemy and has defected.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_internal_mission_failed">This mission has not been completed in the allotted time.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_military_access_expired">Your military access pact with this faction is over. A new pact is needed if you want continued access to their lands.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_lost_killed">This ancillary character has been killed.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_kill_character_subterfuge_success">Having won the trust of the enemy, your dignitary betrayed and assassinated them.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_you_become_emperor_rome">The civil war is over. The Roman Republic is no more! Rome will be an Empire, led by the greatest patrician families, ruling gloriously over the known world. Excelsior!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_bankruptcy_no_cash">Your treasury is empty. You have spent more money than your taxation and trade produces, and you cannot pay the upkeep of your forces. This may lead to loss of morale and, eventually, desertion.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_kill_character_authority_wound">An enemy dignitary has put a price on the head of your subject! Fortunately, the assassins only managed to wound the target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_wounded_theirs">An enemy agent was caught acting against your interests. They were wounded trying to escape.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_army_fail">Luckily, an enemy agent failed in an act of sabotage against one of your armies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_kill_character_subterfuge_wound">The enemy discovered your dignitary's plans. Forced to act quickly, your agent only wounded the target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_you_civil_war">When fighting against enemy forces it is easy to neglect battles closer to home. Power struggles within your faction have sparked an all-out civil war. Brother now fights brother…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_discovered_yours">Your concealed agent has been found by foreign forces. They are now vulnerable to hostile agents.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_settlement_fail">An enemy agent has failed in an act of sabotage in one of your settlements.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_settlement_authority_success">Your champion has incited enemy slaves towards an uprising!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_kill_character_authority_success">An enemy champion has killed your loyal subject in single combat. An honourable death, perhaps, but a loss nonetheless. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_satrapy_broken_by_satrapy_yours_manipulated"> Your satrapy turned against you! This sudden change of heart is surely due to the scheming of an unknown enemy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_army_retreats_region">Your army has been forced to withdraw to friendly territory.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_disease">Your forces have suffered casualties from a lethal disease.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_army_fail">An enemy agent has failed to subvert one of your armies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_winter">The bitter winter cold has inflcited losses on your army.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_army_success">An enemy agent has committed an act of sabotage against one of your armies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_army_subterfuge_success">Using all the cunning at his disposal, your dignitary has misled the enemy commanders.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_populace_troubled">The people of this province are troubled by their circumstances.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_opportune_failure">Your agent was not successful, but the effort was not entirely wasted:</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_camp_unrest_slave_uprising">The slaves in this province have turned on their masters and rebelled!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_you_become_emperor_carthage">The civil war is ended. Carthage is a great empire again. To secure Carthaginian mastery of the known world we must destroy any opposed to Punic hegemony!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_army_razes_settlement">Your forces have razed this settlement to the ground. You will build great things upon its ashes.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_populace_jubilant">The people of this province are jubilant! They sing your praises and make offerings to the gods in your name.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_war_starving_out">The people of this settlement are dying of starvation. Surrender is imminent. Sally out now, before it is too late!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_desert">Your army has suffered casualties while crossing barren, sun-baked desert.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_cultural_victory">Cultural victory achieved.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_satrapy_declared">This faction is now a satrapy. They no longer have diplomatic freedom. Their new overlord protects them in return for their tribute. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_your_general_convalesced">His wounds healed, this man awaits the chance to command your forces once again.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_your_general_killed">This true hero of Rome has died valiantly whilst fighting for the people. Honour him!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_region_raided">An enemy raid on this settlement has reduced local production and public order.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_emergent_faction">A new power has emerged from the chaos of war, ready to make its mark.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_army_authority_success">An enemy dignitary has undermined your general's authority, diminishing his ability to command his troops in battle.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ambusher_discovered_theirs">A concealed army has been discovered by your forces.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_army_authority_success">Your spy has intercepted enemy orders including information about their lands and military affairs.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_you_captured_rome">Your forces have recaptured Rome! The Eternal City is secure, but enemies are everywhere.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_settlement_subterfuge_success">A dishonourable enemy spy has poisoned the wells in your settlement. The garrison and people suffer as a result.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_army_zeal_success">An enemy champion has led a brutal assault against one of your patrols. Few have lived to tell the tale.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_war_coordination_target_available">Thanks to recent events, you can now suggest a target to your allies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_alliance_declared">These factions have formed an alliance, strengthening them both.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_war_coordination_ally_mobilisation">Your ally is preparing to move against your suggested target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_politics_character_defects">His gravitas enhanced, this man has defected from your cause and now seeks to seize power for himself!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_faction_joins_war">This faction has joined the war. They may want easy gains at the expense of others, or they may be acting for their allies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_economic_victory">Economic victory achieved.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_kill_character_subterfuge_success">Your loyal subject has been murdered! It seems likely that an enemy spy used poison.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_convalesced">An agent has recovered from injury and is ready to serve you again.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_trade_agreement_cancelled_port_loss">Trade with this faction is no longer possible due to the loss of a vital port.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_army_zeal_success">Having threatened the enemy with complete destruction, your dignitary has diminished their zeal. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_province_controlled">You have seized control of the entire province! This will boost its economic and military potential and you may now issue local edicts.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_army_zeal_success">Your champion has assaulted an enemy patrol. The brutal attack reduced their numbers and weakened their resolve. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_army_loots_settlement">Your forces have looted this settlement, gaining much wealth! This savagery, however, has caused damage and outraged the people.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_dies_commanding_replace">This force needs leadership now its commander is gone. Who will answer the call?</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_army_success">Success! Your agent sabotaged an enemy army.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_kill_character_subterfuge_wound">Your champion's arrow wounded its target. The enemy will not trouble us for a while.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_settlement_zeal_success">Your dignitary has increasing your cultural influence in this province. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_military_victory">Military victory achieved.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_bankruptcy_imminent">Your treasury is almost empty! Do something, or you will soon be bankrupt.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_army_authority_success">An enemy spy has intercepted orders being carried to your army. Vital military information is now known by your enemies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_trespass_your_land">This faction has marched troops into your lands without permission!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_dies_suspicious">This man had a suspicious death: the work of enemy agents is a constant threat to the lives of your subjects. Another tragedy should be prevented.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_unit_recruited_ship">A new fleet of ships has been built and is ready for action.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_army_authority_success">Your dignitary has undermined this enemy's authority over his troops. Strike now, while his ability to lead is damaged.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_camp_unrest_imminent_slave_uprising">Public order in this province is critically low. A slave revolt is inevitable unless action is taken.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_kill_character_wound">Your agent wounded, rather than assassinated, the target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_barbarian_edict_issued">Word has been received: the chiefs of this province will carry out your edict until you command otherwise.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_populace_outraged">The people of this province are outraged! There is great risk of a local uprising! Something must be done to improve public order.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_client_state_broken_by_overlord_yours_manipulated">You are vulnerable. Your overlord has removed his protection. The lies of others may have prompted his actions.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_you_maintain_republic_rome">The civil war is over! The power-hungry patrician families have failed, and the glory and stability of the Roman Republic are unchallenged again.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_settlement_besieged">Your settlement is under siege. Without supplies the people will face starvation and may be compelled to surrender. Sally out with local forces or bring reinforcements to attack the besiegers!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_settlement_fail">Your agent has failed to disrupt an enemy settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_subject_message_new_subject">The name of one of your subjects is on the lips of everyone. Whether this will prove beneficial remains to be seen.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_subterfuge_success">The enemy was tempted by your agent's offers and abandoned their cause.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_bankrupt_desertion">Your lack of funds has caused desertions, leaving your armies severely weakened.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_capital_lost">Your seat of power has fallen. Your people are at the enemy's mercy. Your forces now doubt your ability as a leader…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_movement_blocked">The path is blocked by another agent or force. You must seek an alternate route or remove the obstacle.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_army_sacks_settlement">Your forces have sacked this settlement, scouring it for valuables before moving on in search of new prey.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_trade_agreement_cancelled_dissolved">Trade with this valued ally is no longer possible.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_anti_army_fail">Your agent has not disrupted an enemy army.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_kill_character_zeal_success">Your servant has been brutally murdered by an enemy champion. Killed without warning or any chance of honourable defence…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_army_fail">Your agent has failed in an act of subversion against an enemy army.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_kill_character_subterfuge_success">Your spy slipped poison into the enemy's food. Or drink. Does it matter? Death followed quickly.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_their_army_sacks_settlement">Enemy forces have sacked your settlement! They took every valuable that they could find before moving on in search of new prey.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_besieged">The besieging army has deprived your forces of supplies. Many are dying.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_settlement_success">Your agent committed an act of subversion within an enemy settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_liberation">The home settlement of this previously-destroyed faction has been liberated. They may re-emerge as a faction. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_copy_protection_message">We have detected that the game executable has been tampered with and is likely to fail. This is usually due to an attempt to play a pirated copy of the game but may, in some cases, be caused by a virus or cheat program. If you own a genuine copy of Total War™: ROME 2 please exit the game, verify your game cache in Steam, scan for viruses, and disable any cheat programs you are running. If you do not own a genuine copy of Total War™: ROME 2 please purchase one from Steam.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_speciality_resource_lost">You have lost an important resource and its benefits. Recapture should be a priority.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_kill_character_zeal_success">Your loyal servant was murdered in cold blood! The killer's identity is unknown but an enemy agents is suspected.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_kill_character_zeal_wound">Despite a good effort your spy did not kill the target, only inflict wounds, before escaping.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_besieging">Your army is suffering heavy losses maintaining the siege. The enemy are doing all they can to fight them off.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_settlement_fail">Your agent failed in an act of subversion at an enemy settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_faction_breaks_treaty_diplomatic">Manipulated by liars and fiends, this faction has broken your diplomatic agreements.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_settlement_authority_success">Words have power, and your spy diminished local public order and increased the chance of rioting in this settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_kill_character_authority_wound">The enemy has no honour, and fled when it became obvious that your noble champion overmatched them.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_kill_character_authority_wound">The price your dignitary offered for the enemy's head was not enough. The bumbling assassins only wounded the target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_blockaded">Your forces have been deprived of supplies by a blockading fleet. Many are dying. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_army_subterfuge_success">An enemy dignitary has misled your army's commanders, compromising their strategic potential.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_camp_unrest_imminent_riots">Public order in this province is critically low. Negative public attitude will undoubtedly lead to riots unless action is taken.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_settlement_fail">Your agent has failed to sabotage anything in the enemy settlement.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_zeal_stop">Your agent did not coerce the enemy into joining your cause. Nevertheless, the enemy's progress was hindered.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_settlement_zeal_success">Your spy set a fire and caused severe damage to enemy buildings. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_populace_content">The people of this province are content with current circumstances.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_high_seas">Storm-tossed seas have damaged your fleet.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_settlement_zeal_success">Your champion led an assault against an enemy garrison as they patrolled the streets. Few lived to tell the tale! </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_army_authority_success">An enemy champion's impressive show of force has demoralised your army. The men are afraid to face this foe.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_attrition_mountain">Your army has suffered casualties while crossing perilous mountain passes.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_satrapy_broken_by_overlord">This faction has removed its protection from its former satrapy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_military_access_cancelled">This faction has broken your established military access pact. Their intentions may be hostile…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_barbarian_edict_cancelled_imperium_drop">A decline in your faction's imperium has diminished your authority. Consequently, the chiefs of this province can no longer carry out your edict.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_dignitary_kill_character_zeal_success">Having provoked the enemy, your dignitary was forced to kill them. Strictly in self-defence.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_settlement_subterfuge_success">Your spy has managed to poison the water in the enemy settlement. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_army_subterfuge_success">An enemy champion's raids and harassment have diminished your troops' effectiveness.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_lost_destroyed">This ancillary was destroyed as a result of enemy action.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_kill_character_fail">Your agent failed to assassinate the target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_camp_unrest_riots">Poor public attitude towards your rule has caused in rioting in this province.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_authority_success">Treachery! Your once-loyal agent has betrayed you!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_settlement_subterfuge_success">The merchants trading within your province have been bribed by an enemy dignitary. Trade income has fallen to an all-time low.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_trade_agreement_cancelled">Your relationship with this faction has deteriorated. They have ended trade relations with you.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_politics_character_high_gravitas_warning">This man's gravitas is great indeed. Beware: if his gravitas continues to grow, he may defect from your cause in an attempt to seize power for himself.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_kill_character_zeal_wound">Your loyal subject was wounded by a brutal attack by an enemy spy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_fail">Your agent has failed to convert the enemy to your cause.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_kill_character_fail">The enemy has failed to assassinate one of your own servants, but they will undoubtedly try again.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_settlement_zeal_success">An enemy dignitary has spread cultural propaganda throughout your province. The people are starting to believe the lies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_sea_region_controlled">Your complete control of this sea region boosts its economic and military potential.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_stop">Your agent failed to rally an enemy to your cause, but the agent did hinder the target.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_anti_settlement_authority_success">Dissent is gowing as the lies spread by an enemy spy in your settlement grip people's minds. Left unchecked, the province riot.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_spy_kill_character_authority_success">Your loyal subject has been murdered, betrayed by someone close. Once captured the villain admitted to working for an enemy spy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_politics_political_event">A new political intrigue has developed!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ceasefire_declared">Peace has been brokered between you and your enemies.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_settlement_fail">An enemy agent has failed in the subversion of one of your settlements.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_zeal_stop">The enemy failed to coerce your agent into betraying you! Their threats were worthless but your agent's work has been hindered.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_character_dies_suspicious_female">This lady died under suspicious circumstances. The work of enemy agents is a constant threat to the lives of all. Steps should be taken to prevent further tragedy. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_faction_joins_your_enemies">This faction has formed an alliance with your enemies. This threatens you and strengthens your enemy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_province_populace_unhappy">The people of this province are unhappy. If uprisings are to be avoided public order should be improved.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_AI_backstab_warning">There is treachery in the air! Nothing is certain, but your allies plot to betray you!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_faction_confederated_them">This tribe has joined with another, strengthening both their causes and offering greater protection to the people.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_edict_cancelled_region_lost">This province is no longer united under your banner. Consequently, the governor of this province can no longer carry out your edict.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_kill_character_authority_wound">Your loyal subject has been wounded in single combat with an enemy champion. Although the injuries are not fatal, they do need time to heal.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_alliance_broken_yours_manipulated">This faction has been manipulated into breaking its alliance with you.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_port_blockaded">This port settlement is being blockaded by an enemy fleet. Blockades disrupt trade and put the local population at risk of starvation. Break the blockade with local forces or bring reinforcements to attack the enemy!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ambusher_discovered_yours">Your concealed army has been found by foreign forces. </string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_trade_agreement_cancelled_embargo">At the request of a third party, this faction has ended their trade agreement with you.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_champion_anti_settlement_zeal_success">An enemy champion has mercilessly assaulted the patrols of your settlement's garrison, leaving many dead and more injured.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_army_destroyed">The enemy utterly destroyed your army. All are dead or enslaved.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_any_steal_character_subterfuge_success">Your supposedly loyal agent has succumbed to bribery and has joined the enemy.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_champion_anti_army_subterfuge_success">The enemy fear their own shadows thanks to your champion's incessant harassment! Fear makes men weak, and they a lesser threat if you attack now.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_faction_destroyed">You have destroyed this faction! They were no match for your might!</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_your_sea_region_contested">You no longer control this sea region. Its economic and military potential are compromised.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_zeal_success">Fearing death, the enemy abandoned their cause and joined you. Your agent is most persuasive…</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_kill_character_zeal_success">An enemy dignitary has provoked your loyal subject into a fit of rage and murdered them. In self defence.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_their_dignitary_anti_settlement_fail">An enemy agent, has failed in an act of disruption within one of your settlements.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_anti_army_subterfuge_success">Your spy infiltrated the enemy camp and poisoned the provisions. Their loss is your gain.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_ancillary_gained_character_with_ancillary">This character has gained an ancillary. It has been added to the reserves to await assignment.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_internal_mission_cancelled">This mission was cancelled due to unforeseen circumstances.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_any_steal_character_authority_success">Your agent has successfully persuaded an enemy to abandon their cause and join you.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_agent_your_spy_kill_character_zeal_success">Moving in shadow, your spy was able to brutally murder the enemy with a concealed weapon.</string>
<string name="message_event_text_text_roman_campmap_prestige_level_increases">Your power knows no bounds! You can now maintain additional armies, fleets, and agents, and issue more provincial edicts.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>