<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_spartan_empire_heading">Spartan Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_spartan_empire_heading">Spartan Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_spartan_empire_heading">Spartan Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_7_spartan_empire_heading">Spartan Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_8_spartan_empire_heading">Spartan Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_fall_seleucid_description">After years of strife, the Seleucid Empire was weak and tottering. Rome saw opportunity, and moved to end the Seleucids' rule... </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_conquest_syria_heading">Conquest of Syria</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_blockade_port">Blockade the following port settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_treasury">Treasury:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_event_issuer_europeans">Issuing faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_blood_money_heading">Blood Money</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_research_n_civil_techs">Research at least %n of the civil technologies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_3_heart_kingdom_description">Despite adopting many Egyptian customs, the Ptolemaic dynasty were still Hellenic, foreign rulers. Some civil unrest might have been avoided if the Pharaohs had consolidated their hold in northeast Africa rather than constantly making war against the other Successors.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_client_1_of_many">Completely control at least one of the following provinces either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_war_seleucid_heading">War With The Seleucid Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_fail">Mission Failed!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_parthian_wars_description">The Parthian Empire had ambitions exceeded only by Rome. With much of the east now Parthian, attention turned westwards just as Rome looked to the east. War between the empires was inevitable.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_protector_armenia_heading">Protector of Armenia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_sabotage_force_invade">Use an agent against the following invading army:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_7_celtic_dominion_heading">Celtic Dominion</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_8_celtic_dominion_heading">Celtic Dominion</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_8_scourge_heading">Scourge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_scourge_heading">Scourge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_6_scourge_heading">Scourge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_into_africa_description">In establishing themselves as a western Mediterranean power, the Epirotes came into conflict with the Carthaginians. Continued hostilities and growing Epirote power would have made an invasion of Carthaginian lands in Africa inevitable.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_nooption_including_n">Control the following %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_have_n_confederated_factions">Have %n factions join your confederation.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_war_macedon_description">Undeterred by his losses in Italy, Pyrrhus returned home and went to war against the Macedonians.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_military_excellence_description">Under Alexander Macedon's army became tactically innovative and well organised. A wise king would look to repeat this achievement, revolutionising military thought as much as possible to leave opponents behind in the race for advancement. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_masters_western_mediterranean_heading">Masters of the Western Mediterranean</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_assassinate_faction">Assassinate a character belonging to the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_establishing_fleet_heading">Establishing A Fleet</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_war_parthia_description">Pontus and Parthia never fought, as Armenia served as a diversion. Had Pontus resisted Rome, eastward expansion would certainly have brought the Pontics into battle with Parthian armies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_destroy_samnites_description">"""The Samnites still hold our leader and refuse to release him. This land shall not know peace until Rutilus is reclaimed and every town and village in Samnium knows nought but Roman rule."""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_skirmisher_cavalary_description">"Excellent all-round horsemen, the Parthians were famed and feared for their mounted archers. These men could harass enemies and continue to fire into pursuing enemies even as they seemingly ran from battle, the so-called ""Parthian Shot""."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_4_war_rome_description">Historically, it was the Romans who invaded Britannia. Had the Britons moved into Europe, they would surely have faced war the Roman Republic as they extended their domain to the Alps and beyond.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_8_consolidation_east_description">Beyond the Persis were the remaining Achaemenid territories of old. A true Persian noble would secure these for the glory of the Pontus.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raid_region">Raid any settlement or trade route.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_war_carthage_heading">War With Carthage</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_fall_macedon_heading">The Fall of Macedon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_recruit_unit_region">Recruit a unit in the following province:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_horse_lords_description">The Gauls were considered exceptional horsemen, and would, in time, provide most of Rome's auxiliary cavalry.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_naval_advantage_description">Carthage's main strengths were undoubtedly its navy, a long history of seafaring and trade. Because Carthage had many ships manned by skilled citizen crews they had the upper hand in many of their wars. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_success">Mission Successful!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_8_conquest_germania_heading">The Conquest of Germania</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_into_asia_heading">Into Asia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_6_successor_conflict_description">Even after Alexander's death, Macedon dominated Athens. Successor kingdoms such as Ptolemaic Egypt fought for control of Alexander's empire and legacy. For the good of all Greeks, they had to be stopped.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_successor_conflict_description">Even after Alexander's death, Macedon dominated Athens. Successor kingdoms such as the Seleucid Empire fought for control of Alexander's empire and legacy. For the good of all Greeks, they had to be stopped.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_king_britons_heading">King of the Britons</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_invasion_britannia_heading">The Invasion of Britannia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_king_gauls_heading">King of the Gauls</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_4_arabian_trade_monopoly_heading">Arabian Trade Monopoly</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_8_dodona_heading">Dodona</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_7_war_parthia_description">Had Macedon tried to regain Alexander's empire, expansion to the east would have brought war with the mighty Parthian Empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_grant_agent_multi">Agents:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_confederate_faction">Make the following faction join your confederation:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_abort">Mission Aborted!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_to_ashes_description">When Carthage fell to the Roman legions, Scipio Aemilianus ordered the city burned to the ground, its people massacred, and the surrounding lands be laid to waste.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_4_war_paint_description">Roman historians wrote that Britons went into battle covered in blue painted symbols. The symbols remain a mystery: more than frightening decorations, were they a mark of divine protection?</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_9_taming_wilderness_heading">Taming the Wilderness</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_naval_prowess_description">Roman seamanship was sadly lacking when compared to that of the Carthaginians, and they were forced to learn quickly.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_pushing_northward_description">The barbarian threat was a constant concern in Macedon, and Alexander's father, Philip II, had expeditions against the northern hordes. If Macedon had surived the Roman onslaught, decisive action to quell the barbarians would have been probable.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_masters_northern_mediterranean_heading">Masters of the Northern Mediterranean</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_berserk_heading">Berserk</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_convert_region">Spread your culture to the majority of this province:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_war_with_friends_description">In Asia Minor, only Armenia exceeded the might of Pontus, although the two had a long history of co-operation. Conflict, however, might well have come if Pontus had expanded. It is likely that the Pontics would have looked to subdue Armenia rather than destroy it.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_capture_salernum_description">"""The enemy garrison at Salernum is small, and will not withstand our army. Act quickly and take the settlement before it can be reinforced."""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_client_including">Completely control %n provinces either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_war_egypt_description">When Pyrrhus allied with Macedon, it was to aid him consolidate his power and conquer lesser foes. Any subsequent ruler of Epirus would have had to behave the same way, and with all the Successor states, including Ptolemaic Egypt. Alliances may have been made, but war would always come.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_1_securing_colonies_description">Carthage planted colonies along the Mediterranean coast, and some remained within the Carthaginian Empire; others fell to conquerors. The protection of colonies from the attentions of Rome and the African Kingdoms was always a concern.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_rebellion_slaves">Slave revolt!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_destroy_gauls_heading">Capture Aternum</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_4_celtic_weakness_heading">Celtic Weakness</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_2_naval_power_description">The Ptolemaic Pharaohs built and maintained one of the largest and most capable fleets of the period. It was needed protect their trade and support their military ambitions around the Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_across_the_aegaean_description">Greek resistance to the Romans grew, and word of Mithridates' campaign brought additional hope. Armies under Archelaus were sent across the Aegaean to liberate Athens and send a message: Rome would have to reckon with Pontus.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_army_faction">Defeat an army belonging to the following faction in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_9_united_kingdom_heading">United Kingdom of Britons</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_mercenary_units">Maintain %n mercenary units.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_7_conquest_britannia_heading">The Conquest of Britannia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_fall_macedonia_description">Macedonian attempts to create a new empire tried Roman patience. Beaten in war, the Macedonians became a puppet state and then a Roman province.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_1_fall_sparta_description">Cleonymus of Sparta claimed the Spartan throne and came to Epirus for help. Pyrrhus went to war: he wanted Sparta for himself.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_1_tribal_warfare_heading">Tribal Warfare</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_have_n_client_states">Be the overlord of %n client states.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_monument_gods_description">Octavian's rise to power owed much to the military skills of his comrade-in-arms, Agrippa. To mark his final victory at Actium over Mark Antony, Consul Agrippa built a Pantheon to the Gods on the Campus Martius in Rome.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_7_legacy_seleucus_heading">The Legacy of Seleucus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_4_beasts_war_description">Alexander and the Successors used many exotic units in battle, because of what they had experienced in war. These exotic forces included elephants who struck fear into the hearts of man and beast alike.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_tyrian_purple_heading">Tyrian Purple</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_spartan_war_rome_description">Romano-Spartan alliances never lasted long. Roman expansion into Hellas during the Macedonian Wars led to the subjugation of many Greek states. Spartans resisted.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_be_at_war_with_faction">Be at war with the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_laconic_way_description">Spartans were famed for their warrior skills. The doctrines and discipline born of their completely militarized society made them a force to be feared.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_laconic_way_description">Spartans were famed for their warrior skills. The doctrines and discipline born of their completely militarized society made them a force to be feared.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_char_made_peace">You are no longer at war with this character's faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_barbarian_frontier_description">Epirotes understood tribal warfare: they had fought off Illyrian invasions from the north. Securing that frontier would ensure the safety of Epirus and the rest of the Hellenic world.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_barbarian_frontier_description">Epirotes understood tribal warfare: they had fought off Illyrian invasions from the north. Securing that frontier would ensure the safety of Epirus and the rest of the Hellenic world.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_8_barbarian_frontier_description">Epirotes understood tribal warfare: they had fought off Illyrian invasions from the north. Securing that frontier would ensure the safety of Epirus and the rest of the Hellenic world.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_securing_peninsula_heading">Securing the Peninsula</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_1_unlikely_allies_heading">Unlikely Allies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_6_briton_war_description">Germans disdained Gauls. Although the Britons did not clash with Germans before the end of Roman Britain, earlier Germanic tribes would certainly have seen these British Celts as similarly worthless and soft.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_trade_masters_heading">Trade Masters</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_nooption_including">Control %n settlements either by direct ownership or through military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_prosperous_relations_description">After Bactria broke away from the Seleucid Empire, it became a powerful nation in its own right. The Parthians saw an opportunity for trade with the wealthy Greco-Bactrian kingdom.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_6_athenian_empire_heading">Athenian Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_athenian_empire_heading">Athenian Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_athenian_empire_heading">Athenian Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_athenian_empire_heading">Athenian Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_9_legacy_diodotus_heading">The Legacy of Diodotus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_last_successor_kingdoms_heading">Last of the Successor Kingdoms</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_mission_added">This mission has been added to your missions list.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_2_powerful_allies_heading">Powerful Allies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_navy_faction">Defeat a fleet belonging to the following faction in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_when_stop_description">Carthage's strength was always at sea. This great maritime empire only fell when faced by boundless Roman ambition and cruelty. Had the Carthaginians won, it is entirely reasonable to think they would have had an alliance with Parthia, a mighty land empire with strong trade links, rather gone to war all over again.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_danubian_frontier_heading">The Danubian Frontier</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_satrapy_including_n">Control the following %n settlements either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_char_faction_destroyed">The faction to which this character belonged has been destroyed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_alliance_faction">Forge a defensive or military alliance with the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_trade_experts_heading">Trade Experts</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_fall_macedon_heading">The Fall of Macedon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_client_including_n">Control the following %n settlements either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_alexander_successors_heading">Alexander's Successors</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_research_n_techs_of_type_x_progress">Current technologies researched: %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_dawn_new_empire_heading">Dawn of a New Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_successor_conflict_description">Like other Greek city-states, Sparta resisted the Macedonian Empire. Successor kingdoms looked to conquer all of Alexander's old empire, including Greece. Such an outcome would merely replace one set of masters with another. Spartans could not allow that to happen!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_successor_conflict_description">Like other Greek city-states, Sparta resisted the Macedonian Empire. Successor kingdoms looked to conquer all of Alexander's old empire, including Greece. Such an outcome would merely replace one set of masters with another. Spartans could not allow that to happen!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_common_cause_description">Philip V of Macedon made a point of allying with Carthage Rome when Hannibal began his invasion.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_3_subjugation_seleucia_heading">The Subjugation of Seleucia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_naval_supremacy_description">The strength of Carthage lay in its navy; its people had a long history of seafaring for war and trade. The Carthaginians had the upper hand at sea in many of their wars because of their skilled citizens and sailors.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_chariot_warfare_heading">Chariot Warfare</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_1_free_athens_description">Since Philip II's defeat of the Greek states in the 4th Century BC, Athenians had lived in Macedon's shadow. They looked to any opportunity to free themselves from Macedonian dominance.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_hold_entirety_of_n_provinces">Hold %n provinces in their entirety.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_including">Control %n settlements (either by direct ownership or through client states) including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_1_fall_macedon_heading">War With Macedon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_alexander_successors_heading">Alexander's Successors</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_2_warbands_description">The Germans were a warrior people. Fearsome warbands would muster under a charismatic leader, to raid or conquer weak neighbours.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_client">Control %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_1_assertion_power_heading">Assertion of Power</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_mp_competitive">Defeat your opponent either by effecting the complete destruction of their faction, or by holding the following key settlements:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_owning_faction_made_peace">You are no longer at war with the target's faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_3_strange_allies_heading">Strange Allies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_generic_current_total_out_of_coop">Current combined total: %n / %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_dominating_levant_description">Had the Carthaginians returned to their age-old homelands, they would have needed to secure the Levant by conquering the old Phoenician hinterlands beyond.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_carthage_destroyed_heading">Carthage Must Be Destroyed</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_return_phoenicia_heading">Return to Phoenicia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_powerful_ally_description">Gallic tribes often fought amongst themselves. When not fighting each other, there was always the chance to be mercenaries. Working for outlanders always meant friends might help when rivals in the tribes came calling... </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_hegemony_description">When the Epirotes oppressed the Greek cities and colonies they had been invited to protect, their ambitous were nade clear. Domination of Hellenic lands would end any doubt that Epirus was the supreme Greek power.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_masters_southern_mediterranean_heading">Masters of the Southern Mediterranean</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_1_fall_epirus_description">War broke out when Prince Cleonymus conspired with Epirus to gain the Spartan throne. The Epirotes underestimated the Spartans. They were defeated, and their ruler, Pyrrhus, died in battle…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_5_wealth_successors_heading">Wealth of the Successors</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_war_rome_description">"The Romans were first hailed as liberators, freeing Greece from Macedonian oppression. When it became clear that the Romans were not going home after the ""liberation"", conflict flared with Athens and the other Greek states."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_war_carthage_heading">War With Carthage</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_have_n_allies">Have a defensive or military alliance with %n factions.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_tarantine_warriors_description">When Rome declared war on Taranto, Pyrrhus fought the Romans alongside his Tarantine allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_into_britannia_description">Rome's legions marched on. With Gaul conquered, military forays could be made across the sea to punish the Britons.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_war_elephants_heading">War Elephants</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_satrapy_including_n">Control the following %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_subjugation_armenia_description">Tension between Rome and Parthia escalated and the Parthians took every opportunity to weaken Rome's hold in the east. Armenia, a client of Rome, was invaded by the Parthians, gaining a foothold in the Caucasus, and stopping Armenian support being sent to the Romans.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_1_hellenic_league_heading">Hellenic League</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_into_syria_description">The ambition Mithridates took him westward, and lead to the trading centre of Dura. This conquest was the first Parthia attack into Syria, now the last bastion of Seleucid power. It would not be the last.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_sabotage_building_any">Use an agent against any settlement.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_capture_region_faction">Capture a settlement belonging to the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_7_hand_that_feeds_heading">The Hand That Feeds</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_eastern_wars_heading">Eastern Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_fall_seleucids_heading">Fall of the Seleucid Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_galatian_war_heading">War With Galatia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_philhellenic_friends_heading">Philhellenic Friends</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_8_leagacy_diodotus_description">If the Ptolemaic dynasty had defeated the Graeco-Bactrian kingdom, they would have needed to control the central Bactrian provinces. This would have supported any claim to be the true heirs of Alexander.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_1_reestablishing_ties_description">Macedon and Epirus had close ties. Alexander the Great's mother had been an Epirote. Pyrrhus forged an alliance with Macedon before going to Italy. If Pyrrhus had not turned against Antigonus later on his return and instead maintained relations, he might have survived his attack on Sparta.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_ports_including">Hold %n port settlements, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_7_war_north_description">Barbarian invasions were always a threat to Greece and the civilised world. The fierce northern tribes would have been worthy enemies for the Spartans!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_success_clan">"""This is an auspicious day: we have successfully accomplished our mission and can now reap the benefits of our efforts!"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_7_footsteps_legends_heading">In the Footsteps of Legends</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_capture_region">Capture the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_ever_eastward_description">Roman ambition and war with Parthia took Romans eastward. At its greatest extent, the Roman Empire included Mesopotamia and the shores of the Caspian Sea.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_eastern_wars_heading">Eastern Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_1_punic_wars_description">Magas, the half-brother of Ptolemy, claimed Cyrenaica and crowned himself king. His independence from Egypt was short-lived.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_research_tech">Research a technology in the following category:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_9_fall_parthia_heading">The Fall of Parthia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_army_specific">Defeat the following army in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_navy_specific">Defeat the following fleet in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_3_scourge_heading">Scourge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_8_scourge_heading">Scourge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_mithridatic_wars_description">After the fall of Macedon, Rome meddled in Asia Minor. As Pontus fought Rome's allies and clients there, the Romans became directly involved. Mithridates VI's order to massacre 80,000 Romans in was final, fatal cause of open war.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_4_expedition_description">Gauls migrated across Europe, settling as far from home as the Hellespont and Asia Minor. A kingdom of Britons in Europe might have followed much the same path, moving ever southwards and eastwards…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_5_expedition_description">Gauls migrated across Europe, settling as far from home as the Hellespont and Asia Minor. A kingdom of Britons in Europe might have followed much the same path, moving ever southwards and eastwards…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_6_expedition_description">Gauls migrated across Europe, settling as far from home as the Hellespont and Asia Minor. A kingdom of Britons in Europe might have followed much the same path, moving ever southwards and eastwards…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_7_expedition_description">Gauls migrated across Europe, settling as far from home as the Hellespont and Asia Minor. A kingdom of Britons in Europe might have followed much the same path, moving ever southwards and eastwards…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_military_developments_heading">Military Developments</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_macedonian_wars_heading">The Macedonian Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_eastern_wars_heading">Eastern Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_consolidation_greece_heading">The Consolidation of Greece</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_invasion_greece_heading">The Invasion of Greece</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_gallic_expedition_heading">Gallic Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_gallic_expedition_heading">Gallic Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_gallic_expedition_heading">Gallic Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_6_gallic_expedition_heading">Gallic Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_7_gallic_expedition_heading">Gallic Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_8_gallic_expedition_heading">Gallic Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_territorial_expansion_heading">Territorial Expansion</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_into_hispania_description">Rome's military campaigns went far afield. Before the legions secured territory on the Iberian Peninsula.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_spartan_hegemony_description">When Sparta rose against Athenian domination, it was victorious and became the leading Hellenic state. Athens was put in her place, and  much of Greece lived in the shadow of the Spartan hegemony.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_event_reward">Reward:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_region_captured_allied">This settlement has been captured by an allied faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_1_luxurious_wares_heading">Luxurious Wares</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_into_germania_description">Rome fought the Germanic tribes with unremitting hostility. It took many years before Rome advanced into Germany, to be met with fierce resistance at every step. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_spartan_hegemony_description">When Sparta rose against Athenian domination, it was victorious and became the leading Hellenic state. This authority extended to the Hellespont and across the Aegaean into Asia.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_invasion_africa_heading">The Invasion of Africa</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_a_region_in_n_provinces">Hold at least one settlement in %n individual provinces.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_9_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_region_made_peace">You are no longer at war with the owner of this settlement.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_including">Completely control %n provinces (either by direct ownership or through client states) including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_capture_buxentum_description">"""The surviving Lucanian aristocracy beg us to reclaim their city. The Samnites are a mountain people and not known for their skills on the water. We should strike from the sea."""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_1_cappadocia_description">Pontus and Cappadocia engaged in years of war and intrigue. Cappadocia came under Pontic rule through marriage, and then alternated between was alliances and defiance. Mithridates VI invaded Cappadocia and placed his own son on the throne, to little effect.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_consolidation_italia_heading">The Consolidation of Italia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_mercenary_units_co_op">Together with your cooperative ally, maintain %n mercenary units.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_new_enemies_description">Parthian rulers had boundless ambition and powerful enemies. Had Ptolemaic Egypt survived to the time that Parthia was establishing a presence in the Levant, the two states would certainly have gone to war.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_greek_alliance_heading">Greek Support</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_4_rome_destroyed_heading">Rome Must Be Destroyed</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_friend_rome_description">As Rome warred against Carthage, it looked to other Mediterranean powers for aid. Sparta offered support, and did the same when Rome fought Macedon.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_subjugation_macedon_description">Despite the disaster in Italy, the Epirotes won a number of victories over the Macedonians and siezed control of their lands. They ousted King Antigonus. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_war_egypt_description">Having declared war on the Seleucids, Ptolemy I of Egypt looked to add Asia Minor to his lands. He sent an invasion force against Pontus; Mithradates I had to fight back.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_war_egypt_description">Wars with Ptolemaic Egypt were limited while Egypt was distracted by the other Successor states. Had conflict between Pontus and Egypt continued, a desire to finish the Egyptians, and a need to support the Seleucids, could have brought about the Pontics conquest of Egypt.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_epirote_empire_heading">Epirote Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_epirote_empire_heading">Epirote Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_epirote_empire_heading">Epirote Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_8_barbarian_frontier_description">As harsher weather forced the northern tribes to migrate south, the need for a defended frontier became clear. The barbarians would not get past Spartans! </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_consolidation_asia_description">Pontus secured its position in much of Asia Minor: Galatia was taken from the Gauls, Cappadocia was sneakily absorbed, and Bithynia only survived thanks to ties to Rome.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_consolidation_asia_description">Over time, Pontus consolidated its dominance in Asia Minor. War with Rome gave Mithridates VI the chance to move south and west, seizing control of the Aegaean and Mediterranean coasts.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_8_legacy_leonidas_heading">Legacy of Leonidas</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_1_hellenic_league_heading">Hellenic League</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_faction_destroyed">This faction has been destroyed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_2_confederation_heading">Confederation</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_regions">Hold %n settlements.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_rebellion">Rebellion!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_1_research_military_description">Tacitus writes of Germans rousing their fighting spirit through ceremonial weapon dances: celebrations of past glories, and anticipation of tomorrow's bloody harvest.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_the_levant_heading">The Levant</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_vengeance_description">"When the colonies of ""Megale Hellas"", or ""Greater Greece"", were attacked by the Roman Republic, they asked Epirus for help. Wanting an an empire of his own, Pyrrhus led an army across the Adriatic and to war with Rome."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_fall_pergamon_heading">The Fall of Pergamon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_3_trade_network_heading">Trade Network</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_trade_network_heading">Trade Network</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_end_rebellion">Crush the uprising in the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_hold_entirety_of_n_provinces_1_of_many">Hold the entirety of at least one of the following provinces:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_4_scythian_problem_heading">The Scythian Problem</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_reach_rome_heading">The Reach of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_treasures_arabia_description">The Arabian kingdoms had a monopoly on trading spices and wares from India and East Africa. A Roman army under Gallus was sent to secure this trade by whatever means necessary.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_phoenician_colonies_description">Carthaginian dominance in the western Mediterranean was supported by a network of colonies. Loss of the colonies in Corsica and Sardinia would diminish Carthaginian power in the Tyrhennean Sea.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_destroy_rebels_heading">Destroy the Rebel Army</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_units_progress">Current units: %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_6_military_supremacy_description">The Celts were known to be warlike. Whether for self-preservation or conquest, it was vital for a tribe's warriors to maintain any advantage over their rivals.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raise_fleet">Raise a fleet</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_into_gaul_description">Tribes from Belgica crossed settled in southern Britannia. Unfavourable changes in the weather or war might have produced movement in the other direction: Britons settling in greater Gaul.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raze_sack_n_settlements_religion_1_of_1">Raze or sack at least one settlement of this culture:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_iberia_heading">Iberia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_gallic_wars_description">The Gauls knew about war with Rome. Under Brennus a Gallic army had reached the gates of Rome itself and sacked the city. Despite largely subduing the Gallic tribes south of the Alps, Rome had not forgotten that humiliation, and wanted all Gaul brought to heel.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_fall_egypt_description">With Greece subjugated, the Successor Kingdoms were the last independent parts of Hellenic civilisation. Epirus would see the Ptolemaic Egypt would destroyed or brought to heel!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_3_consolidation_heading">Consolidation</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_into_asia_description">With a stabled western frontier, Epirus might have turned east. The Greek colonies of Asia once flourished, and could do again under Epirote rule.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_conquest_thracia_heading">The Consolidation of Thracia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_fall_pontus_description">The ambitions of King Mithridates of Pontus brought him into conflict with Rome. When a third war broke out between Pontus and Rome, the Romans decided to end the matter once and for all.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_1_tribal_coop_description">Tribes would often ask others for aid or military support against a common enemy. The Sequani helped  when the Arverni went to war against the Aedui.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_your_region_lost">You have lost this settlement to another faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_true_greek_description">Epirus was a long way from the Aegaean city-states; to some Greeks the Epirotes were therefore little more than barbarians. Shared ancestry and culture could not be ignored, and  Epirus was as Greek as any snobbish city-state on the Aegaean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_fall_rome_description">Pyrrhus was ambitious and great commander. He beat the Romans on many occasions, but at too high a cost in Epirote lives. Had he won his battles less bloodily, the Roman Republic might well have been unable to resist an Epirote invasion…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raise_force">Raise a force</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_eliminate_in_battle_faction">Eliminate a general belonging to the following faction in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_satrapy">Completely control %n provinces either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_9_fall_seleucid_heading">The Fall of the Seleucid Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_trade_with_greeks_description">"""The colonists in Magna Graecia make a handsome living from trading on the seas. We should set up a trade agreement with them, and profit in turn."""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_into_germania_heading">Into Germania</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_5_masters_macedon_heading">Masters of Macedon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_across_adriatic_heading">Across the Adriatic</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_5_trade_goods_description">Britons had been trading with Carthaginians for generations, bartering tin for Mediterranean luxuries. Trade with any honest partners was vital to any tribe seeking an advantage over their rivals. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_seleucid_wars_heading">The Seleucid Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_client_state_of_faction">Make a client state of the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_ports">Hold %n port settlements.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_1_beyond_britannia_description">The ancient Britons are not known to gone to war overseas. Had they invaded mainland Europe, they would have needed warships to take control of the seas, and carry their warriors to battle.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_diplomacy">Relations with this faction will be affected:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_units">Maintain %n units in total.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_magna_graecia_heading">Magna Graecia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_buildings_damaged">Buildings in this settlement have been damaged.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_treasury_at_least_x">At the start of your turn, have an amount of %n talents in your treasury.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_military_reforms_description">The military reforms of Gaius Marius created Rome's first standing army, paid for in full by the state. Rome's war-making potential significantly improved, but Gaius Marius was treated with suspicion…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_roman_wars_description">Tension between Parthia and Rome was inevitable as the boundaries of two great powers grew nearer to each other. Open warfare broke out repeatedly for centuries.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_nooption_including">Completely control %n provinces either by direct ownership or through military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_beyond_gaul_description">A large tribe would have eventually expanded beyond Gaul, and conquered all who stood in the way.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_fall_egypt_description">No Athenian hegemony could allow the conquest of Greece by any erstwhile heirs to Alexander. Athens would, sooner or later, have to destroy Ptolemaic Egypt!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_grant_agent_single">Agent:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_subjugate_n_factions_satrapy">Subjugate %n different factions by making them your satrapies or by capturing their last remaining settlement.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_king_germania_heading">King of Germania</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_germanic_wars_heading">The Germanic Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_6_italia_subdued_description">Had Vercingetorix defeated Caesar's legions, a vengeful Gallic host might have swarmed across the Alps, subjugating the Romans instead.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_into_gallia_description">Rome's military campaigns knew few bounds. It was not long before the Legions had marched over the Alps and taken land in Gaul.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_securing_tyrrhenian_heading">Securing the Tyrrhenian Sea</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_5_masters_sea_description">Egypt's navy was very capable, as their many victories against other Successor states showed. If the kingdom had not declined, their fleet might have been the the most powerful in the Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_8_trade_empire_description">Carthage was a trade-based empire. Their Phoenician forebears had been master merchants, and the Carthaginians used this knowledge to master the Mediterranean seaways and the ocean beyond the Pillars of Hercules. They also established trade with many African kingdoms and Iberian tribes.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_sabotage_force_faction">Use an agent against an army belonging to the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_across_aegaean_heading">Across the Aegaean</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_consolidation_heading">Consolidation</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_fall_seleucids_heading">The Fall of the Seleucid Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_into_north_description">The raids by the Dacians Pannonians had troubled Hellenic lands for many years, and continued when Rome conquered the area. To protect the people, an Epirote Empire would have had to conrol the north.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_into_north_description">The civilised world was always threatened by barbarians: Celts, Germans, Sarmatians and Scythians. Further expansion north by an Epirote Empire would stem these marauders.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_1_pontic_ascendancy_description">The rulers of Pontus aspired to great power. Struggles against the kingdoms of Asia Minor allowed them to gain control of their neighbours.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_2_pontic_ascendancy_description">"The kings of Pontus always aspired to something greater. Mithridates VI looked to control the Black Sea's eastern shore, a ""protector"" against the Scythian hordes that menaced the petty kingdoms there."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_pontic_ascendancy_description">The rulers of Pontus had aspired to much. Although control of the Black Sea's coasts was vital, disputes with Pergamon, Cappadocia and Rome drew them towards the Mediterranean world.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_pontic_ascendancy_description">The rulers of Pontus wanted more! The untamed lands beyond the Black Sea, the home of barbarians kingdoms such as the Scythians, were hard to tame.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_pontic_ascendancy_description">"The rulers of Pontus claiming descent from the Achaemenid kings of Persia when it suited their ambitions. ""Recapturing"" former Achaemenid territories and enhancing the glory of Pontus might have made these claims more believable."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_pontic_ascendancy_description">The rulers of Pontus were ambitious. War with Rome limited them to Asia Minor, but they could have extended their reach into and across the Mediterranean: Egypt and the the promise of riches in Africa and Arabia were tempting goals.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_pontic_ascendancy_description">The kings of Pontus had their ambitions. Wars to keep the barbarians away from the Black Sea's coasts gained them support in many lesser kingdoms. Once secured, the next step could have been a punitive invasion of the Scytho-Sarmatian heartlands.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_overlords_description">The Parthians relied on a system of satrapies, or vassal states, that were allowed a little independence as long as they provided tribute, troops and bowed to Parthian mastery. In this, they followed the Seleucids and the Persian Empire of old. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_overlords_description">The Parthians relied on a system of satrapies, or vassal states, that were allowed a little independence as long as they provided tribute, troops and bowed to Parthian mastery. In this, they followed the Seleucids and the Persian Empire of old. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_grant_unit_multi">Units:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_enemy_of_enemy_heading">The Enemy Of My Enemy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_9_eastern_question_description">The Parthians and the Romans knew little but war with each other. The wars took a toll, helping both empires towards their ends. How glorious, how imperious, it would have been if Rome had prevailed!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_across_channel_description">Migration and expansion were the keys to the strength and survival of a tribe. The Belgic tribe of the Atrebates even crossed the seas to establish a presence in Britannia.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_a_region_in_n_provinces_1_of_1">Hold at least one settlement in the following province:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_8_masters_southern_seas_heading">Masters of the Southern Seas</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_1_subjugation_epirus_description">After his defeat by Rome, Phyrrhus of Epirus returned to Hellas and conquered Macedon. Antigonus liberated his lands, triggering war with Pyrrhus and his kin which ended with Macedonian control of Epirus.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_9_masters_northern_seas_heading">Masters of the Northern Seas</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_alexander_ambition_description">Alexander died before he fulfilled his military ambitions. If a Macedonian Empire had risen anew, his successors may have tried to match his aims: had Alexander marched west along the African coast rather than east towards India, Carthage would have been crushed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_7_alexander_ambition_description">Alexander died without achieving all  his military ambitions. If a Macedonian Empire arose again, his successors might have wanted to fulfil his intentions: Alexander want to conquer the Arabian peninsula.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_1_ships_war_description">Demetrius, father of Antigonus, dreamed of a new Macedonian Empire to Alexander's achievement. He prepared ships to cross the Mediterranean to claim the lands of the Successor Kingdoms.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_fall_pergamon_heading">Pergamon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_consolidation_gaul_heading">Consolidation of Gaul</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_family_influence">Party Influence:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_birth_parthia_heading">Birth of the Parthian Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_3_friend_rome_description">When the Ptolemaic dynasty asked Rome for help against the other Successors, Rome readily agreed. Egyptian grain was Rome's price.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_trade_any">Establish trade relations with any faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_4_soldiers_fortune_heading">Soldiers of Fortune</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_1_confederation_heading">Confederation</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_pressing_westward_description">With the Seleucid Empire under pressure in the west from Rome and the other Successors, Parthia was able to gradually encroach into the heart of Seleucid territory.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_2_philhellenism_heading">Philhellenism</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_bactrian_alliance_description">When Didotus II inherited the Greco-Bactrian throne, Arsaces II of Parthia saw the opportunity to establish an iron alliance against the Seleucid Empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_9_take_carthage_heading">The Taking of Carthage</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_fall_carthage_heading">The Fall of Carthage</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_into_africa_description">Rome's military campaigns became wide ranging. It was not long before the Romans had crossed the Mediterranean to Africa.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_hold_entirety_of_n_provinces_including">Hold the entirety of at least %n of the following provinces:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_1_punic_wars_description">Conflict between Carthage and Rome was a consequence of both sides interfering in a war between the Greek colonies of Messina and Syracuse. The war became one for complete control of Sicily. The First Punic War had begun.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_success_shogun">"""An envoy has been sent from our allies. They are most grateful that we have been able to accomplish the task set us."""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_8_ultimate_knowledge_description">Having become a dominant power, the Ptolemaic dynasty could have devoted Egyptian energies to the pursuit of knowledge. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_nooption_1_of_many">Completely control at least one of the following provinces either by direct ownership or through military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_westward_heading">Ever Westward</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_types_of_mercenary_units">Maintain %n different types of mercenary units.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_nooption_including_n">Control the following %n settlements either by direct ownership or through military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_last_kingdom_egypt_description">Wars between Macedon and the Ptolemaic Egypt were common. Had the Macedonians survived Rome's attacks, they would surely have mounted an expedition to settle with the Egyptians. This would have bolstered Macedonian claims to be Alexander's rightful successors.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_event_activity">Task:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_last_kingdom_egypt_heading">The Last Kingdom of Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_successor_allies_heading">Successor Allies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_tribal_hegemony_heading">Tribal Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_peace_any">Make peace with any enemy faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_region_captured_neutral">This settlement has been captured by a neutral faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_white_india_description">"Trade with Arachosia or ""White India"" as the Parthians called it, was threathened by the collapse of the Mauryan Kingdom. Arachosia was at risk of invasion by the Greco-Bactrians and the successors to the Mauryans. The Parthians needed the trade route, and secured the area for themselves."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_strange_allies_description">Gallic and Germanic warriors had little love for each other yet in desperate times any ally was better than none. The Sequani sought the help of the Suebi under Ariovistus to conquer their enemies. The alliance did not last; they were betrayed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_8_great_migration_heading">The Great Migration</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_9_great_migration_heading">The Great Migration</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_imperium_romanum_description">"Caesar had became Rome's supreme ruler, king in all but name. Terrified by his ambitions, some in the Senate assassinated him. Despite of this hostility, his heir, Octavian, consolidated power and, by holding many offices of state at once, became ""pinceps"", the emperor in all but name."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_4_great_migration_heading">The Great Migration</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_great_migration_heading">The Great Migration</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_6_great_migration_heading">The Great Migration</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_7_great_migration_heading">The Great Migration</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_types_of_mercenary_units_co_op">Together with your cooperative ally, maintain %n different types of mercenary units.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_mercenary_force_heading">Mercenary Force</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_legacy_of_ptolemy_description">If the Macedonians had defeated Ptolemaic Egypt, they would have needed to secure control of Egyptian lands, if only to prove their status as Alexander's true heirs.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_breadbasket_rome_description">As Rome grew, so too did the need for its people to be fed. As such, trade with and conquest of lands situated along the fertile coasts of North Africa became key to maintaining the Roman hegemony.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_naval_escalation_heading">Naval Escalation</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_1_etruscan_decline_description">Rome became the dominant Italian power, and it was only a matter of time before the Etruscans, the former masters of Italy, were subjugated.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_bread_circuses_description">Keeping Rome's mob happy never a simple matter. An ever-more expensive series of games were needed to keep them distracted and compliant.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_german_hordes_heading">The German Hordes</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_issued">Mission Issued!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_expansion_description">"Although careful not to make new enemies, the Parthians were ready to ""liberate"" neighbouring lands from the feeble grip of the Seleucids; this helped secure their own position. "</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_4_heart_empire_description">Seleucid power waned, and even the Seleucids' capital in Mesopotamia fell to the Parthians, along with the cities of Ekbatana in Media and Susa in Persis. Parthian mastery of the old heart of Seleucid power, and the seat of great Persian kings of old, was secured.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_7_fall_egypt_description">All Alexander's successors looked to reconquer his old empire. Ptolemaic Egypt constantly meddled in Greco-Macedonian affairs. Spartan, the defenders of Greece, would see Egypt submit or be destroyed!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raid_faction">Raid a settlement or trade route belonging to the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_securing_peninsula_description">"Greek colonies in Italy asked for Epirote protection against Roman aggression. This request was an opportunity for Pyrrhus to grab control of Italy and ""Megale Hellas"" in a single war. Epirus could be a major power, and would dominate the Adriatic and central Mediterranean."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_fall_rome_description">Pontus could never match the military power of Rome, and the Third Mithridatic War marked the fall of the kingdom. But under other circumstances, perhaps, a Pontic army might have marched to the gates of Rome, bringing the Republic to its knees…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_units_specific">Maintain a total of %n units of the following type:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_7_fall_rome_description">The decline of the Roman Empire had many causes, but being unable to resist incessant Germanic invasions eventually brought about collapse.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_char_died">This character has died.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_consolidation_egypt_description">In the past, Egypt had fallen to great powers: Persia, Macedon and now Pontus would provide a new dynasty of Pharaohs, and rule these rich and ancient lands.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_containing_region_captured_allied">The region which contains the target has been captured by an allied faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_war_with_armenia_heading">War with Armenia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_satrapy_including">Completely control %n provinces either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_naval_superiority_description">Over the centuries the Athenians in particular had proven themselves to be masterful sailors. Under Athenian leadership, a combined Greek fleet even repelled the great of the Persian invasions during the Greco-Persian wars.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_heavy_cavalry_heading">Heavy Cavalry</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_heavy_cavalry_heading">Heavy Cavalry</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_7_primary_heading">"""Through hardships…"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_6_primary_heading">"""I came, I saw, I conquered"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_5_primary_heading">"""Ever upward!"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_fall_rome_description">Had Sparta regained its military greatness and resisted the Romans, it would have had to deal permanently with the Roman menace. As staunch defenders of Hellenism, the Spartans could have laid low the upstart Roman Republic…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_4_primary_heading">"""Woe to the vanquished"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_3_primary_heading">"""I shall find a way"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_2_conquest_syria_heading">The Conquest of Syria</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_2_primary_heading">"""If you would have peace, prepare for war"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_1_primary_heading">"""Assent to my bold undertakings"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_4_trade_monopoly_heading">Trade Monopoly</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_trade_monopoly_heading">Trade Monopoly</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_9_primary_heading">"""Unconquered"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_8_primary_heading">"""…unto the stars"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_masters_atlantic_heading">Masters of the Atlantic</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_satrap_of_faction">Make a satrapy of the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_return_persia_heading">Return to Persia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_spartiate_description">"Sparta's military superiority was based on the Spartiates, ""the equals"", who were trained from childhood in the arts of war. They were rightly feared by all their enemies."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_school_hellas_heading">School of Hellas</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_school_hellas_heading">School of Hellas</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_peace_faction_destroyed">All factions with whom you were at war have been destroyed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_common_cause_heading">Common Cause</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_trade_india_description">Arachosia, once a satrapy of Persia, Macedon and the Seleucids, was controlled by Indian Mauryan Empire at the end of the 5th Century BC. It gave the the Mauryans control of the overland trade from India. Without seagoing merchants, Parthia tried to establish relations and gain from this trade.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_fall_carthage_heading">The Fall of Carthage</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_1_syrian_wars_description">Wars between Alexander's Successors became common. Pharaoh Ptolemy faced Antiochus I, the Seleucid king, who wanted to rule lands west of Syria…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_6_trade_wealth_heading">Trade Goods</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_destroyed">The target has been destroyed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_2_southward_description">Changes in the weather and war made it necessary for tribes to migrate far from their homelands. The Cimbri came from the far northern coasts to the Alps, and fought the Romans as they did so.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_financial_support_description">Sparta's armies and fleets always came at great cost to its economy. In regaining Sparta's military might, Cleomenes made treaties with Egypt, and gained the money needed for Sparta's military.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_grant_unit_single">Unit:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces">Completely control %n provinces (either by direct ownership or through client states).</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_heavy_cavalry_heading">Heavy Cavalry</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_6_sack_rome_description">Before the rise of Rome's empire, only the Gauls had managed to sack the city. It was not until the last years of the Empire that it would fall to a Germanic invasion.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_generic_current_total_coop">Current combined total: %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_end_dynasty_heading">To End a Dynasty</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_1_phoenician_traders_description">Once Phoenician colonists, the Carthaginians had a well-deserved reputation for seamanship and naval commerce. They traded across  the Mediterranean for generations.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_1_thirst_knowledge_description">Ptolemy had a passion for learning. He sought out manuscripts from every corner of the world for the Great Library.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_black_sea_description">The Bosporan kingdom was constantly threatened by Scythians. In return for Pontic protection, the Bosporans surrendered control their lands.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_persian_legacy_heading">Persian Legacy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_subjugate_n_factions">Subjugate %n different factions by capturing their last remaining settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_controlling_seas_heading">Controlling the Seas</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_8_consolidation_north_description">With a foothold in the north one task would remain: to bring the barbarians to heel by any means necessary. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_beyond_tyrrhenian_description">The conquest of Italy was a beginning. Across the Tyrrhenian Sea  lay territories vital to Epirus' domination of the western Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_recruit_agent">Recruit the following agent:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_your_region_lost_rebels">You have lost this settlement to the rebels.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_subjugate_n_factions_client">Subjugate %n different factions by making them your client state or by capturing their last remaining settlement.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_master_puppets_description">Asking too much of the army could bring disaster. The Senate understood that it was better to have puppet states dancing to a Roman tune rather than have the expense and difficulty of taking complete control.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_need_allies_heading">The Need for Allies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_1_punic_wars_heading">The Punic Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_gallic_wars_description">"Julius Caesar went to war in Gaul, supposedly to ""protect"" Rome from invasion by Gallic and Germanic barbarians. Personal glory played its part too."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_macedonian_phalanx_description">The Macedonian pike phalanx was developed by Phillip II, Alexander the Great's father, and used to great effect by both rulers. It gave Macedon a reputation for fielding the best phalangites in the world.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_alexander_path_heading">Alexander's Path</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_alexander_path_heading">Alexander's Path</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_alexander_path_heading">Alexander's Path</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_alexander_path_heading">Alexander's Path</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_9_alexander_path_heading">Alexander's Path</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raid_region_specific">Raid the settlement or trade routes within the following region:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_athenian_hegemony_description">After the Greco-Persian wars, Athens had become the dominant Hellenic state. Their authority extended from Thessalia to the Hellespont.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_3_athenian_hegemony_description">After the Greco-Persian wars, Athens had become the dominant Hellenic state. Athens dominated much of Greece and many Greek colonies, but Sparta and other Peloponnesian states resisted. The Athenians never fully consolidated their power.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_athenian_hegemony_description">After the Greco-Persian wars, Athens had become the dominant Hellenic state. Athenian influence and power extended across the Aegaean, and they protected the cities and colonies there.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_athenian_hegemony_description">After the Greco-Persian wars, Athens had become the dominant Hellenic state. Had the other Greek states not resisted the Athenians, they could have had power over the distant Black Sea colonies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_9_gaul_extent_description">Gallic tribes migrated eastwards, past the Hellespont and into Asia Minor. A supreme Gallic kingdom would surely seek to bring these far-flung brothers back into a Gallic empire. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_6_war_parthia_description">Having defeated the Seleucids and become the major power of the near east, it would only have been a matter of time before Ptolemaic Egypt went to war with the Parthian Empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_fall_rome_description">War with Rome did not end well for Macedon: it became a client kingdom. If the Macedonians had not lost, they would have inevitably thought of crossing the Adriatic to finish with Rome once and for all.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_1_war_tribes_heading">Tribal Warfare</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_client_including_n">Completely control the following %n provinces either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_paragons_wisdom_heading">Paragons of Wisdom</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_4_arabian_trade_monopoly_heading">In Wine There Is Truth</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_satrapy_1_of_many">Completely control at least one of the following provinces either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_transalpina_description">Control of the Mediterranean coast west of the Alps was vital for trade between Rome and Iberia. It also gave Rome interests in in Gaul and a bridgehead for further campaigns.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_maintain_trade_with_n_factions">Maintain trade relations with %n factions.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_9_cradle_civilisation_description">It is, perhaps, a poetic conceit to imagine the greatest civilisation of all ruling the very cradle of civilisation itself!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_6_legacy_cassander_description">If the Ptolemaic dynasty had defeated Macedon, they would have needed to control the main Macedonian provinces. This would have justified any claim to be the heirs of Alexander.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_combined_arms_heading">Combined Arms</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_combined_arms_heading">Combined Arms</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_6_fall_rome_description">Had Athens regained its independence the subjugation of Rome would have been a desirable, perhaps inevitable, goal. Bringing Rome to her knees would have securing the northern Mediterranean and gained the respect of Greeks everywhere.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_fall_seleucid_heading">The Fall of the Seleucid Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_4_tribal_hegaemony_description">In times of war, it was common for tribes to unite under a single leader. Many together had a better chance of victory; the Marcomanni, under Marobuduus, established a tribal confederation against the Romans.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_beyond_avarice_heading">Beyond Avarice</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_2_western_trade_description">To the west, the Roman Republic was expanding in earnest. Egypt, with trade connections and an ample excess of grain, would become a key trading partner.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_acropolis_description">"In many Greek cities the acropolis, the ""extremity of the city"" loomed over all. Part fortress and defensible refuge for the people in time of war, it was also a home to temples and sanctuaries. The Acropolis of Athens and its buildings were extremely impressive."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_masters_black_sea_description">For many years Carthaginian naval dominance in the Mediterranean was unchallenged. To extend this into the Black Sea it would be vital to sieze key ports along the Black Sea coasts.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_germanic_hordes_heading">The German Hordes</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_4_legacy_seleucus_heading">The Legacy of Seleucus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_agoge_heading">Agoge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_agoge_heading">Agoge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_into_fold_description">Arsaces, founder of the Parthian Empire, came from the Dahae tribal group. Parthian ascendancy brought these people fully into society. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_1_expansion_description">Germania was vast, the tribes dispersed and the people driven only by a need to survive. Expansion beyond the forests required vision, great charisma, power and ambition.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_bonus_completed">Bonus objectives completed: %n / %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_macedonian_wars_heading">The Macedonian Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_protection_rome_heading">The Protection of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_subjugation_seleucia_description">With the fall of the Ptolemiac dynasty in Egypt, Macedonian efforts might have been directed against the the Seleucids. Once allies, all could be united under Macedonian rule!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_1_war_pergamon_description">The Attalid Kingdom of Pergamon often came to blows with Macedon, as it resisted Macedonian expansionism in the Hellespont and the Aegaean. Mutual hatred was made worse during the Macedonian Wars when the Pergamese allied with the Romans.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_7_naked_warriors_description">Some warriors fought without clothing, confident that their skills and the gods would protect them. Although not invincible, their numbers and fearsome appearance struck terror into enemy hearts.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_gaul_subdued_heading">Gaul is Subdued</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_trade_network_heading">Trade Network</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_nooption">Completely control %n provinces either by direct ownership or through military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_a_region_in_n_provinces_including">Hold at least one settlement in %n individual provinces, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_5_sack_rome_description">"Rome was sacked on more than one occasion by barbarians, including by the Gauls under Brennus and later by migrating Germanic tribes. If the Britons had fought their way to the gates of ""Roma Eterna"" they might well have sacked the city too."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_character_gravitas">Gravitas:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_distant_lands_description">Migration and massed invasions would take tribes far from their homelands. These would even lead the Gallic tribes to establish themselves in the Hellespont and Asia Minor.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_nothing_personal_heading">Nothing Personal</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_seafarers_carthage_description">Naval superiority was key to Carthaginian power. The Carthaginians, not being fools, would have made every effort to maintain the most advanced navy in the Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_supply_heading">A Matter of Supply</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_9_fall_rome_description">Long years of bitter war weakened both Rome and Parthia, aiding the final destruction of both empires by lesser kingdoms and barbarians. It is entirely possible that matters might have ended differently if the Parthians had overthrown the tyranny of Rome!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_spice_road_description">Control of the lucrative trade routes from the east guaranteed wealth for the Parthians. Had they not been distracted by wars in the west, they might have invaded the Arabian peninsula. This would have given them control of the trade in exotic spices as well.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_satrapy_including">Control %n settlements either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_legacy_brennus_description">When Brennus sacked Rome he sent a clear message: that only a fool does not respect the people of Gaul and their warriors. The Romans did not forget!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_7_last_successor_kingdoms_heading">Last of the Successor Kingdoms</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_9_eastern_question_heading">The Eastern Question</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_across_channel_heading">Across the Northern Seas</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_overlords_heading">Overlords</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_overlords_heading">Overlords</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_event_time">Turns remaining:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raze_sack_n_settlements">Raze or sack %n different settlements.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_enemy_of_enemy_description">Alexander the Great's death led to wars between all who claimed his empire. The Ptolemaic dynasty of Egypt frequently attacked the Macedonians, making them likely allies for anyone seeking to overthrow Macedon.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_consolidation_description">By mastering the fiercely independent warriors of Caledonia in the north, and those of Hibernia across sea to the west, a high king of the Britons would have ensured the safety of his people at home. His attention could be directed towards greater goals...</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_income_at_least_x">At the end of your turn, have an income of at least %n talents.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_fall_seleucids_description">The Seleucid Successors were not only Macedonian, but also heavily influenced by many Persian traditions. They were a threat to Greek independence and worthy only of Spartan contempt! The Spartans had good reasons to wish the Seleucids destroyed!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_satrapy_including">Control %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_across_aegaean_description">As a result of war with the Ptolemaic Egypt, Macedon managed to take Asian lands from Egypt and her allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_into_north_heading">Into The North</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_into_north_heading">Into The North</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_1_pontic_ascendancy_heading">Pontic Ascendancy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_2_pontic_ascendancy_heading">Pontic Ascendancy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_pontic_ascendancy_heading">Pontic Ascendancy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_pontic_ascendancy_heading">Pontic Ascendancy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_pontic_ascendancy_heading">Pontic Ascendancy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_pontic_ascendancy_heading">Pontic Ascendancy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_pontic_ascendancy_heading">Pontic Ascendancy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_consolidation_gaul_description">No tribe ever successfully consolidated all of Gaul, but Vercingetorix came close when he faced Julius Caesar's invasion. A Gaul unified under a single leader might have been aweome indeed!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_alexander_ambition_heading">Alexander's Ambition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_7_alexander_ambition_heading">Alexander's Ambition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_fall_pergamon_description">Pharnaces I fought the Kingdom of Pergamon for control of key areas in Asia Minor. When the last king of Pergamon died he entrusted his entire kingdom to Rome, robbing Pontus of any reward.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_1_ships_war_heading">Ships of War</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_1_subjugation_epirus_heading">The Subjugation of Epirus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_8_masters_southern_seas_description">Carthaginian naval dominance in the Mediterranean was unchallenged. To extend that power, it would have been vital to sieze key ports beyond the Arabian Peninsula.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_9_masters_northern_seas_description">Carthaginian naval dominance in the Mediterranean was unchallenged. To extend that power, it would have been vital to sieze key ports in the far north, beyond any kind of civilization.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_4_soldiers_fortune_description">Carthage was famous for using mercenaries: during Hannibal's march towards Rome, he recruited many Celtic mercenaries into his army, helped by a common dislike of the arrogant Romans.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_event_issuer_shogun">Issuing faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_3_friend_rome_heading">A Friend of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_birth_parthia_description">The lands of Parthia finally broke away from the Seleucid Empire. Without the protection of the Seleucids, the Parthians were powerless to prevent Arsaces from conquering the land. In doing so he established the great Parthian Empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_1_punic_wars_heading">The Punic Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_into_africa_heading">Into Africa</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_satrapy">Control %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_9_take_carthage_description">Many cities fell before the Germanic kingdoms, but not all was wanton destruction. When the Vandals invaded North Africa, Carthage did not resist and the occupation caused little devastation to the city and the surrounding lands.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_fall_carthage_description">There would be only one solution to the problem of mastery in the Mediterranean: Carthage would submit to Athenian rule or be destroyed!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_1_confederation_description">Tribes often joined together for mutual protection; the Brigantes started as a confederation of smaller tribes. They became a stumbling block to the Roman invasion of northern Britannia.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_faction_declared_war">You are now at war with this faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_2_philhellenism_description">Asia Minor was home to many Greeks. The Persian kings of Pontus came to appreciate Hellenic culture for the links it gave with Greek kingdoms and colonies, and as a help in controlling conquered peoples.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_bactrian_alliance_heading">The Bactrian Alliance</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_pressing_westward_heading">Pressing Westward</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_westward_description">Parthia's campaigns pushed westward. Their progress was checked by Rome among others, but the Parthian desire to conquer Asia Minor and the Levant could not be gainsaid.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_8_ultimate_knowledge_heading">Ultimate Knowledge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_eliminate_in_battle_any">Eliminate any general in battle.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_client">Control %n settlements either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_maintain_trade_with_n_religions">Maintain trade relations with factions from %n different cultures.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_tribal_hegemony_description">In times of war, a single strong leader would often emerge from among the tribes. Vercingetorix once led a great confederation of Gallic tribes against common enemy: the Romans under Julius Caesar.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_last_kingdom_egypt_description">As war split the Republic, Mark Antony took Cleopatra, queen of Egypt, as lover and ally, hoping to defeat Octavian, Caesar's heir. Antony and Cleopatra's failure and suicides became romantic legend, and marked the end of Ptolemaic Egypt.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_successor_allies_description">Antigonid Macedon and the Seleucids' empire came to be in the wars over Alexander the Great's legacy. Despite hostilities, they became frequent allies against a common foe, Ptolemaic Egypt, another Successor regime, often at war in Syria and the Levant.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_last_kingdom_egypt_heading">The Last Kingdom of Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_not_invading">This faction is no longer invading your territory.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_satrapy">Control %n settlements either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_7_great_migration_description">A later migration of Germanic tribes took them across much of Europe. When Britannia was abandoned by Rome, German warlords were invited to keep out the barbarians from the north. It did not take long before the Britons and the Germans were fighting too. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_6_great_migration_description">Later migrations of Germanic tribes saw them sweep across much of Europe. Romano-German conflicts lasted for centuries, ending in the Visigoth conquest of Italy.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_great_migration_description">A great migration of Germanic tribes saw them move across much of Europe. Conflict with the later Eastern Roman Empire led to the German conquest of the Hellespont and northern Greece.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_4_great_migration_description">A great migration of Germanic tribes saw them sweep across much of Europe. The Carpathian basin became home to many, until the later Hunnic invasion forced them westward.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_imperium_romanum_heading">Imperium Romanum</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_9_great_migration_description">Later migrations of the tribes saw Germans sweep across much of Europe. Some tribes even crossed the Mediterranean, and made a Germanic kingdom in Africa.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_8_great_migration_description">Later migrations took the Germanic tribes across much of Europe. The Suebi eventually established a kingdom in Hispania.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_strange_allies_heading">Strange Allies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_research_tech_type">Research the following technology:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_issued_objective">Objective Issued!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_white_india_heading">White India</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_generic_current_income">Income in previous turn: %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_bread_circuses_heading">Bread and Circuses</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_1_etruscan_decline_heading">Etruscan Decline</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_sabotage_force_any">Use an agent against any army.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_naval_escalation_description">As Macedon consolidated its strength in Hellas and Asia, wars with the other Successors could have driven a need for naval power to secure Macedonian mastery in the Eastern Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_client_including_n">Control the following %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_breadbasket_rome_heading">Breadbasket of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_mercenary_force_description">Despite not having a large standing army, the Parthian Empire was able field a force of nobles, elite troops and levies stiffened with mercenaries as needed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_success_europeans">"""An envoy has been sent from our allies. They are most grateful that we have been able to accomplish the task set us."""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_legacy_of_ptolemy_heading">The Legacy of Ptolemy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_hold_entirety_of_n_provinces_including_n">Hold the entirety of all the following provinces:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_the_levant_description">Rome's military campaigns took her legions far from home. Disputes in Asia and Africa required a foothold in the Levantine states of the eastern Mediterranean coast.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_1_research_military_heading">Fighting Spirit</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_assassinate_char">Assassinate the following character:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_faction_made_peace">You are no longer at war with this faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_a_region_in_n_provinces_including_n">Hold at least one settlement in the following provinces:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_event_issuer_clan">Issuing faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_2_confederation_description">It was common for tribes to join together for protection and prosperity. The Suebi were, almost certainly, a collection of tribes and clans who became so interdependent they were a single tribe.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_treasures_arabia_heading">Treasures of Arabia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_phoenician_colonies_heading">The Phoenician Colonies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_reach_rome_description">The ambiltion of Rome in the north was apparently limitless. Control of lands beyond the earlier Gallic and Hellenic possessions became likely.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_4_scythian_problem_description">The Scythian tribes were a constant thorn in the side of the Parthians, raiding Parthian lands as the empire was occupied elsewhere. Retaliation became a pressing necessity. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_vengeance_heading">Vengeance</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_fall_pergamon_description">The chaos of the Cretan War, when Macedon fought Aegaean and Asian Greek city-states and fended off Roman and barbarian attacks, prevented them Macedon subjugating the Pergamese. Had events favoured the Macedonians, they would have brought the war with Pergamon to an end.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_3_trade_network_description">Long before the rise of Macedon and Rome, the Greek states and colonies were a trading network that spanned the Mediterranean from the Levant to the Pillars of Heracles. Athens, as a major naval power, was at its centre. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_trade_network_description">Long before the rise of Macedon and Rome, the Greek states and colonies were a trading network that spanned the Mediterranean from the Levant to the Pillars of Heracles. Athens, as a major naval power, was at its centre. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_gallic_wars_heading">The Gallic Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_trade_faction">Establish trade relations with the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_iberia_description">Having had influence over the southern Iberian Peninsula, it is clear that Carthage should have sought to dominate the whole of Iberia. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_into_gaul_heading">Into Gaul</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_destroy_rebels_description">"""With our enemy regrouping to attack us once more, the rebellion in Latium cannot be tolerated. Defeat the rebel army to stamp your authority in Rome."""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_6_military_supremacy_heading">Military Supremacy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raze_sack_n_settlements_religion">Raze or sack %n different settlements of this culture:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_1_tribal_coop_heading">Tribal Cooperation</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raze_sack_n_settlements_1_of_1">Raze or sack the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_conquest_thracia_description">Thrace had always been a concern for Macedonian rulers: it was important to control routes to Asia and the Black Sea, and to hold the northern borders against the barbarians.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_fall_pontus_heading">Fall of Pontus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_into_asia_heading">Into Asia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_regions_1_of_1">Hold the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_event_description">Details:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_client_state_of_faction_any">Make a client state of any faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_fall_egypt_heading">The Last Dynasty of Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_3_consolidation_description">The greatest tribes held the greatest territories, held by the sword or spear or as a confederation of lesser tribes. The Suebi came to hold much of ancient Germania, although the rise and fall of tribes was an endless process.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_across_adriatic_description">Rome had to control the Adriatic to stop rampant Illyrian piracy and discourage Hellenic states taking sides against the Republic.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_5_masters_macedon_description">After the fall of the Seleucids, only Macedon, the last Successor state, would have been left to challenge Egypt. The Macedonians and their Antigonid rulers would have to submit to divine Pharaoh…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_5_trade_goods_heading">Trade Goods</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_9_fall_seleucid_description">With Greece subjugated, the Successor Kingdoms were the last independent parts of Hellenic civilisation. Epirus would see the Seleucid Empire would destroyed or brought to heel!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_into_germania_description">Had the Britons left their island home, war with the Germanic tribes might have drawn them into Germania, either directly or through Gaul.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_trade_with_greeks_heading">Trade with the Greeks</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_true_greek_heading">True Greek</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_bonus_added">New bonus objectives have been added to your objectives list.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_military_reforms_heading">Military Reforms</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_client_including">Control %n settlements either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_peace_faction">Make peace with the following enemy faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_1_beyond_britannia_heading">Beyond Britannia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_magna_graecia_description">"Since the 8th Century BC, Greeks had settled on the southern coasts of Italy, leading to wars between the colonies and their Roman and Carthaginian neighbours. ""Megale Hellas"" or ""Great Greece"", might have been vital to any further Hellenic expansion across the Mediterranean."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_seleucid_wars_description">With many satrapies in disorder, the Seleucid Empire could not risk their falling under the control of the Parthians or becoming independent. The Seleucids marched to war against Parthia and to reclaim their lands.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_beyond_gaul_heading">Beyond Gaul</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_roman_wars_heading">The Roman-Parthian Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_8_trade_empire_heading">The Carthaginian Trading Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_5_masters_sea_heading">Masters of the Sea</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_research_n_techs_of_type_x">Research %n of all technologies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_securing_tyrrhenian_description">Thanks to the First Punic War, Carthage ceded control of its Corsican and Sardinian colonies to Rome. Had things gone differently, the Carthaginians could have secured the islands for their own military purposes, and been able to mount invasions across the Tyrrhenean Sea.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_6_italia_subdued_heading">Italia is Subdued</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_into_gallia_heading">Into Gallia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_king_germania_description">Despite the rise of many powerful kings, the tribes of Germania never became united under a single leader. A pan-Germanic confederation of tribes would have been a mighty power!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_germanic_wars_description">Rome waged war against many Germanic tribes, either as a result of ill-fated German attempts to conquer the lands beyond the Rhine, or because of the seemingly endless Germanic migrations heading south.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_fall_egypt_heading">The Fall of Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_be_at_war_with_n_factions_with_religion">Be at war with %n factions of the following culture:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_6_war_parthia_heading">War With Parthia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_9_gaul_extent_heading">Gaul's Great Extent</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_units_specific_co_op">Together with your cooperative ally, maintain a total of %n units of the following type:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_alexander_path_description">Alexander the Great's conquests became legend, a myth of greatness for every Macedonian. As he cut a path eastward, many lands fell before him. Any who face his true successors should suffer the same terrible fate!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_alexander_path_description">Alexander the Great's conquests became legend, a myth of greatness for every Macedonian. As he cut a path eastward, many lands fell before him. Any who face his true successors should suffer the same terrible fate!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_alexander_path_description">Alexander the Great's conquests became legend, a myth of greatness for every Macedonian. As he cut a path eastward, many lands fell before him. Any who face his true successors should suffer the same terrible fate!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_alexander_path_description">Alexander the Great became a legend, a god of war for every Macedonian who could carry a sword. Any who opposed Alexander fell before his armies. The same fate awaited any who faced his true successor!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_9_alexander_path_description">Alexander the Great became a legend, a god of war for every Macedonian who could carry a sword. Any who opposed Alexander fell before his armies. The same fate awaited any who faced his true successor!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_athenian_hegemony_heading">Athenian Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_3_athenian_hegemony_heading">Athenian Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_athenian_hegemony_heading">Athenian Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_athenian_hegemony_heading">Athenian Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_macedonian_phalanx_heading">Macedonian Phalanx</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_4_arabian_trade_monopoly_description">Carthage was a famed producer of wine, exporting it all across the Mediterranean. During peacetime their customers included Romans.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_1_war_tribes_description">Despite a common heritage, war did erupt between Gallic tribes. The Arverni had an old rivalry with the Aedui that finally resulted in an Arverni victory.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_paragons_wisdom_description">Romans were quick to recognise and use technological advances, thanks to their own ingenuity and a willingness to adopt foreign good ideas.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_4_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_6_legacy_cassander_heading">The Legacy of Cassander</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_9_cradle_civilisation_heading">Cradle of Civilisation</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_transalpina_heading">Transalpina</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_eliminate_in_battle_char">Eliminate the following general in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_hold_entirety_of_n_provinces_1_of_1">Hold the entirety of the following province:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_2_western_trade_heading">Western Trade</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_beyond_avarice_description">Wealth is power. A Carthaginian empire of comparable size to that of Rome with strong trade links would have been wealthy beyond any mortal dreams of avarice.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_fall_seleucid_description">No Athenian hegemony could allow the conquest of Greece by any erstwhile heirs to Alexander. Athens would, sooner or later, have to destroy the Seleucids!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_6_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_4_tribal_hegaemony_heading">Tribal Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_combined_arms_description">Macedon's excellent pikemen and heavy cavalry were well known. The key to their early victories was the ability to use these units together. Such tactical expertise was not properly matched until Roma's imperial legions.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_combined_arms_description">Macedon's excellent pikemen and heavy cavalry were well known. The key to their early victories was the ability to use these units together. Such tactical expertise was not properly matched until Roma's imperial legions.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_blockade_faction">Blockade a port settlement belonging to the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_germanic_hordes_description">Germanic tribes thought the Gauls weak and decadent, good only for dying in battle. The Gauls had no qualms about fighting back.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_4_legacy_seleucus_description">If the Ptolemaic Pharoahs defeat the Seleucid Empire, they will need to control the core Seleucid lands, and so make justify the claim to be the true successors to Alexander the Great.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_masters_black_sea_heading">Masters of the Black Sea</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions">Control %n settlements (either by direct ownership or through client states).</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_acropolis_heading">Acropolis</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_6_subjugation_seleucia_heading">The Subjugation of Seleucia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_macedonian_wars_description">Macedon, although weakened since Alexander the Great' s death, tried to dominate Greece and the Hellespont. Warlike measures were needed to prevent the rise of a second Macedonian Empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_protection_rome_description">When the Republic first grew in size, Rome did not always subjugate conquered states. Instead, they were offered client status, some autonomy and protection in return for tribute.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_7_naked_warriors_heading">Naked Warriors</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_1_war_pergamon_heading">War with Pergamon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_gaul_subdued_description">When the Gallic leader, Vercingetorix, surrendered at Alesia, it did not take Rome long to assert total control over Gaul.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_lift_blockade_port">Lift the blockade upon the following port settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_into_fold_heading">Into the Fold</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_agoge_description">From seven, Spartan boys prepared to be soldiers. Training was brutal, and standards were astonishingly high. Those who failed could never be Spartan citizens.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_agoge_description">From seven, Spartan boys prepared to be soldiers. Training was brutal, and standards were astonishingly high. Those who failed could never be Spartan citizens.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_1_expansion_heading">Expansion</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_nothing_personal_description">Macedon and the Seleucid Empire had worked together to thwart the Ptolemaic dynasty and its ambitions beyond Egypt. Sooner or later, however, the Seleucids and Macedonians would have had to settle the small matter of mastery over Alexander's legacy.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_seafarers_carthage_heading">Seafarers of Carthage</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_5_sack_rome_heading">The Sack of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_distant_lands_heading">Distant Lands</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_trade_network_description">The Epirotes yearned to be a great Mediterranean power. They had made little contribution to the wave of Greek mercantile colonies, so the Epirotes would have to to establish a trading empire of their own.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_legacy_brennus_heading">Legacy of Brennus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_7_last_successor_kingdoms_description">The Ptolemaic dynasty seemed to have a taste for war with all of Alexander's other Successors. Sooner or later a powerful Egypt would have gone to war against the eastern Greco-Bactrian kingdom. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_spice_road_heading">The Spice Road</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_research_n_military_techs">Research at least %n of the military technologies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_at_least_one_source_of_each_resource">Hold at least one of every strategic resource.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_subjugate_faction_client">Subjugate this faction by making them your client state or by capturing their last remaining settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_nooption">Control %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_9_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_supply_description">The Parthians' relied on their superb archers in battle. As a consequence, they had to develop a supply system to keep their bowmen well stocked with arrows.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_nooption_including">Control %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_4_heart_empire_heading">Heart of the Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_maintain_trade_with_n_factions_progress">Current trade relations: %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_expansion_heading">Expansion</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_german_hordes_description">Germanic tribes saw the Gauls as weak and decadent. Had the Celtic Britons established themselves on mainland Europe, the Germans might well have seen them as more of the same…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_securing_peninsula_heading">Securing the Peninsula</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_7_fall_egypt_heading">The Last Dynasty of Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_war_with_armenia_description">The Kingdom of Armenia, also profited from the Seleucids' decline. The Armenians expanded their domain south of the Caucasus, confronting both Romans and Parthians as they did so.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_consolidation_egypt_heading">The Consolidation of Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_7_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_masters_atlantic_description">Carthaginian naval control in the Mediterranean was unchallenged for decades. To extend this beyond the Pillars of Hercules, it would have been vital to sieze key ports along the Atlantic coast.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_heavy_cavalry_description">While the Parthians were famed as horse archers, their heavy cavalry also struck fear into enemy hearts. With horses and riders armoured from head to foot, Parthian cataphract had near-unstoppable charge into battle.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_heavy_cavalry_description">While the Parthians were famed as horse archers, their heavy cavalry also struck fear into enemy hearts. With horses and riders armoured from head to foot, Parthian cataphract had near-unstoppable charge into battle.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_8_primary_description">Your accomplishments as leader are many, but there is no rest. Take your place among the gods!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_9_primary_description">The world is yours! Just reach out…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_4_primary_description">Your enemies are many, your equals: none. Show the world what happens to any who stand in your way.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_5_primary_description">You have come far, and there is no turning back. Conquer! Glory awaits!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_fall_rome_heading">The Fall of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_6_primary_description">Victors write history. Who remembers anyone when their names are dust?</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_7_primary_description">It takes courage to die for one's people. Your troops' sacrifice will be remembered!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_1_primary_description">From humble beginnings come great things. Take your first step. Establish a foothold and launch your people to greatness.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_4_trade_monopoly_description">Control of the trade routes between the west and the far east, including what would become the Silk Road, was extremely profitable for the Parthians.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_trade_monopoly_description">Control of the trade routes between the west and the far east, including what would become the Silk Road, was extremely profitable for the Parthians.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_2_primary_description">Your endeavours will be opposed. Raise forces to conquer your enemies and protect your people.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_3_primary_description">Beloved ruler or dread tyrant. Builder or destroyer of civilisations. There are many paths to glory: which will you follow?</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_2_conquest_syria_description">A series of victories over the Seleucids secured Egyptian control over most of Syria.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_naval_superiority_heading">Naval Superiority</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_6_trade_wealth_description">Trade was important to the Gauls, giving them items they could not make for themselves. As the Gauls migrated many peoples became trading partners.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_1_syrian_wars_heading">The Syrian Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_common_cause_description">Southern Britons shared ancestry with the Gallic Celts, and they were known to aid each other in times of trouble. British warriors fought against the Roman invasion of Gaul, and fleeing Gauls were offered sanctuary in Britannia.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_fall_carthage_description">Epirus might have aspired to become the dominant power in the western Mediterranean, bringing tensions with Carthage. War would only have ended once Carthage was crushed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_3_trade_india_heading">Trade with India</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_return_persia_description">"Although heavily influenced by Greeks and Greek culture, Pontus was ruled by ethnic Persians. If the kingdom had continued to grow, they might well have reclaimed Persis. The unique Pontic blend of Greco-Persian culture would have come ""home"" to the old Persian Empire."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_spartiate_heading">The Spartiate</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_school_hellas_description">Athens was considered to be a shining example of Hellenic civilisation, home to the greatest of artists, scholars, politicians and philosophers. Often at the front of Hellenic cultural developments and enlightenment, Athens was an aspirational model for every Greek state.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_school_hellas_description">Athens was considered to be a shining example of Hellenic civilisation, home to the greatest of artists, scholars, politicians and philosophers. Often at the front of Hellenic cultural developments and enlightenment, Athens was an aspirational model for every Greek state.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_establish_empire">Establish the Roman Empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_satrap_of_faction_any">Make a satrapy of any faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_1_thirst_knowledge_heading">Thirst for Knowledge</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_end_dynasty_description">Had Carthage overcome Rome, war would have certainly happened with other Mediterranean states. The Ptolemaic dynasty turned Egypt into a naval and commercial rival to Carthage. The destruction of Egypt would have been necessary to maintain Carthaginian mastery.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_1_phoenician_traders_heading">The Phoenician Traders</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_recruit_unit_type">Recruit the following type of unit:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_6_sack_rome_heading">The Sack of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_heavy_cavalry_description">"Macedon developed the use of cavalry into a military art. Heavy cavalry, such as Alexander's ""Companions"", were central to Macedonian tactics, and rightly feared by any who faced them."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_2_southward_heading">Southward</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_financial_support_heading">Financial Support</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_8_consolidation_north_heading">The Consolidation of the North</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_controlling_seas_description">Carthage's reputation for naval superiority was the result of dominating the smaller seas that made up the Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_provinces_with_cultural_dominance_including">Hold at least one settlement in %n provinces in which your culture is dominant, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_black_sea_heading">Across the Black Sea</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_persian_legacy_description">Throughout their history,  Parthians looked to the greatness of their Persian forebears in cultural and military accomplishments. This trend continued under the Sassanids, who would succeed the Arsacid Parthians as masters of the east.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_1_punic_wars_description">Despite treaties and trade with Carthage, Rome's ambition brought about many years of conflict.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_gallic_wars_heading">The Gallic Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_master_puppets_heading">Master of Puppets</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_need_allies_description">After Hannibal won his great victory at Carrhae, Philip of Macedon, fearing the Romans and their amibtions, formed an alliance with Carthage. Macedon was to be left its independence if the Carthaginians crushed Rome.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_beyond_tyrrhenian_heading">Beyond The Tyrrhenian Sea</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_to_ashes_heading">To Ashes</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_trade_income_at_least_x">At the end of your turn, have a trade income of at least %n talents</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_7_war_parthia_heading">War with Parthia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_4_arabian_trade_monopoly_description">Trade with the Arabian kingdoms was needed for exotic goods, for both the Egyptian elite and to ship on for profit. The Ptolemaic Pharaohs could have taken the Arabian peninsula and its trade for themselves.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_8_dodona_description">Despite being on the fringe of Hellenic civilisation, Epirus was home to the ancient and revered Oracle of Dodona. Here the priests and priestesses watched the sacred oaks and discovered the wishes of Zeus and Dione.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_containing_region_captured_neutral">The region which contains the target has been captured by a neutral faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_5_berserk_description">Germanic warriors sometimes entered battle in an unhinged fury, shouting terrifying  warcries and not stopping the slaughter until every enemy had run or lay dead on the battleground.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_masters_northern_mediterranean_description">Carthaginian naval dominance was unchallenged, but to maintainit, control of key ports in the northern Mediterranean would have been a necessity.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raze_sack_n_settlements_including">Raze or sack %n different settelements including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_5_pushing_northward_heading">Pushing Northward</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_9_taming_wilderness_description">The barbarian wastes of the north were a challenge even for Rome. With greater commitment and a little luck, a world where barbarism was crushed would have been possible...</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_naval_prowess_heading">Naval Prowess</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_naval_units">Maintain %n naval units.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_4_war_paint_heading">War Paint</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_be_at_war_with_faction_any">Be at war with any faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_2_naval_power_heading">Naval Power</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_4_celtic_weakness_description">Germanic tribes had little love for their weak, decadent Celtic neighbours. Wars were frequent.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_fully_own_n_sea_regions">Have complete control over %n sea regions.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_destroy_gauls_description">"""The Gauls lend strength to our mortal enemies. Justice must be served for this slight against Rome and its people. Aternum must be captured, the Gods demand it!"""</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_war_with_friends_heading">War Between Friends</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_fail_description">You have failed to accomplish this mission within the allotted time, thereby losing any advantage that might have been gained.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_war_egypt_heading">War With Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_1_securing_colonies_heading">Securing the Colonies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_capture_salernum_heading">Capture Salernum</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_1_fall_sparta_heading">The Fall of Sparta</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_7_conquest_britannia_description">Although Gauls settled peaceably in Britannia, an aggressive, successful tribe might have shown less restraint. Their northern brothers across the sea would submit or be destroyed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_fall_macedonia_heading">The Fall of Macedonia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_assassinate_any">Assassinate any character.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_ports_client_including">Control %n port settlements either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_across_the_aegaean_heading">Across the Aegaean</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_9_united_kingdom_description">An unstoppable advance of British warriors during antiquity makes it likely that a kingdom of Britons could have united the Celtic world under a single banner.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_laconic_way_heading">This is Sparta!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_laconic_way_heading">This is Sparta!</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_4_beasts_war_heading">Beasts of War</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_spartan_war_rome_heading">War With Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_tyrian_purple_description">"Purple dye, or ""Tyrian purple"", was one of the rarest and most prized luxury items of the time. The Carthaginians were experts in extracting the dye from seashells, and dominated the trade in it."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_subjugate_faction">Subjugate this faction by capturing their last remaining settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_1_tribal_warfare_description">Tribal wars were common: warlords were hungry for glory. One day come two great Germanic tribes, the Cherusci under Arminius, and the Marcomanni under Maroboduus, take up spears against each other.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_7_legacy_seleucus_description">If the Macedonians had defeated the Seleucids, they would have needed to secure the main Seleucid provinces, and fortify their claim to Alexander's legacy.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_monument_gods_heading">Monument to the Gods</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_1_unlikely_allies_description">Threatened by Egypt, Mithridates I found unlikely allies in the Galatians, a tribe of Celtic Gauls who had settled in Asia Minor migrating from western Europe.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_securing_peninsula_description">With all the Italian peninsula under Roman control, the heart of the Republic was made secure for centuries.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_hold_entirety_of_n_provinces_including_less_than_n">Hold %n provinces in their entirety, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_barbarian_frontier_heading">The Barbarian Frontier</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_barbarian_frontier_heading">The Barbarian Frontier</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_8_barbarian_frontier_heading">The Barbarian Frontier</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_lift_blockade_any">Lift any blockade.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_regions_including">Hold %n settlements, including the following:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_construct_building_region">Construct a building in the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_8_athenian_empire_description">With control of the Aegaean, Athens might have considered military and economic mastery of the whole Mediterranean. An Athenian presence in Hispania or Gaul would have allowed them to regain control of colonies such as Massilia, as well as dominate trade in the west.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_5_athenian_empire_description">"With control of the Aegaean, Athens might have considered military and economic mastery of the whole Mediterranean. War with Rome may have drawn them west and a foothold in Illyria or ""Megale Hellas"", a step towards invading Italy and the north…"</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_athenian_empire_description">With control of the Aegaean, Athens might have considered military and economic mastery of the whole Mediterranean. An Athenian presence in North Africa would have allowed them to dominate the southern Mediterranean coastline and its peoples.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_6_athenian_empire_description">With control of the Aegaean, Athens might have considered military and economic mastery of the whole Mediterranean. Conquest of the Levantine coast would have allowed Athens secure control of the eastern Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_1_prosperous_relations_heading">Prosperous Relations</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_trade_masters_description">Carthage was a trade-based empire. Their Phoenician forebears had been master merchants, and the Carthaginians used this knowledge to master the Mediterranean seaways and the ocean beyond the Pillars of Hercules. They also established trade with many African kingdoms and Iberian tribes.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_confederate_faction_any">Make a faction join your confederation.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_6_briton_war_heading">By Any Other Name</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_2_powerful_allies_description">Pontus often wanted stronger ties with the Seleucid Empire, supported them against Ptolemy of Egypt, and got involved in in Seleucid family feuds.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_9_legacy_diodotus_description">If Macedon were to utterly defeat the Greco-Bactrian kingdom, it would become vital to secure the core Bactrian provinces. This would make Macedon's king Alexander's obvious successor. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_last_successor_kingdoms_description">What is a Macedonian Empire that does not reach Alexander's borders? the Kingdom? To match Alexander, Macedon's king would have had to subjugate Bactria and secure an Indian frontier.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_army_invade">Defeat an invading army belonging to the following faction in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_3_heart_kingdom_heading">Heart of the Kingdom</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raise_army">Raise an army</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_blood_money_description">"While not lacking in military expertise, the Carthaginians lacked the men to field large citizen armies. Many ""Carthaginian"" soldiers were therefore mercenaries, recruited from among allies or in conquered lands."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_provinces_with_cultural_dominance">Hold at least one settlement in %n provinces in which your culture is dominant.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_have_n_satrapies">Be the overlord of %n satrapies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_spartan_empire_description">With control of Hellas and the far-flung Greek city-states, Sparta might have made efforts to secure its power. A campaign into the lands north of Greece would end any threat from uncivilized barbarians.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_spartan_empire_description">With control of Hellas and the nearby Greek city-states, Sparta might have made efforts to extend its power. Before Sparta allied with Rome during the Punic Wars, Cleonymus landed in Italy with the intent of undermining Roman rule.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_spartan_empire_description">With control of Hellas and the nearby Greek city-states, Sparta might have made efforts to extend its power. Control of North Africa's fertile coast would have helped maintain a Spartan empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_7_spartan_empire_description">With control of Hellas and the nearby Greek city-states, Sparta might have made efforts to extend its power. The Greek colonies of the Black Sea would have fared better under Spartan guidance, and fought off the steppe hordes...</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_8_spartan_empire_description">With control of Hellas and the nearby Greek city-states, Sparta might have made efforts to extend its power. The Greek colonies of the western Mediterranean could have been incorporated into a Spartan empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raise_army_region">Raise an army at the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_fall_seleucid_heading">Dissolution of the Seleucid Empire</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_conquest_syria_description">Rome's conquest of Syria was a blow to the Parthians as it stopped them reaching the Mediterranean and the opportunities it offered. The Parthians returned to the attack, gaining several great victories over Rome, and only narrowly failing to conquer Antioch.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_3_scourge_description">The Celts were seen as a scourge by many so-called civilised observers, people who looted or destroyed everything in their path. Had the Britons crossed into mainland Europe, they might have behaved no better.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_6_scourge_description">The Celts were seen as a scourge by many so-called civilised observers, people who looted or destroyed everything in their path. Had the Britons crossed into mainland Europe, they might have behaved no better.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_8_scourge_description">The Celts were seen as a scourge by many so-called civilised observers, people who looted or destroyed everything in their path. Had the Britons crossed into mainland Europe, they might have behaved no better.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_into_africa_heading">Into Africa</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_8_celtic_dominion_description">Despite a shared culture, Britons in mainland Europe would have had tense, even warlike, relations with other Celts. Supremacy over the Gallic tribes would require control of key lands in Gaul.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_7_celtic_dominion_description">Despite a shared culture, Britons in mainland Europe would have had tense, even warlike, relations with other Celts. Supremacy over the Gallic tribes would require control of key lands in Gaul.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_protector_armenia_description">Rome managed to influence the Kingdom of Armenia on many occasions, only to see the Parthians do the same. Eventually Rome installed a puppet king and made Armenia a client buffer state to thwart Parthian plans.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_7_war_seleucid_description">When Pyrrhus allied with Macedon, it was to aid him consolidate his power and conquer lesser foes. Any subsequent ruler of Epirus would have had to behave the same way, and with all the Successor states, including the Seleucids. Alliances may have been made, but war would always come.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_7_parthian_wars_heading">Parthian Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_war_macedon_heading">War With Macedon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_war_parthia_heading">War with Parthia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_faction_became_allied">You have become allied to this faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_2_establishing_fleet_description">When war broke out, the Romans could not match Carthaginian naval might. A war fleet worthy of Rome was needed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_8_military_excellence_heading">Military Excellence</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_masters_western_mediterranean_description">For many years, Carthage had undisputed naval supremacy. In order to maintain control of the Mediterranean, the Carthaginians would have needed control of key ports.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_outcome_abort_description">Due to the following unforeseen circumstances, you are no longer able to accomplish this mission:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_army_any">Defeat any army in battle.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_nooption_including_n">Completely control the following %n provinces either by direct ownership or through military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_client">Completely control %n provinces either by direct ownership or through client states and military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_2_skirmisher_cavalary_heading">Skirmisher Cavalry</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_destroy_samnites_heading">Destroy the Samnites</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_4_war_rome_heading">War With Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_8_consolidation_east_heading">The Consolidation of the East</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_force_raiding_any">Defeat any raiding force in battle:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_2_horse_lords_heading">Horse Lords</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_naval_advantage_heading">The Naval Advantage</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_2_fall_macedon_description">For many years Macedon had dominated Athens. Had the Athenians gained their their independence, it is likely they would have turned on the Macedonians to settle scores once and for all.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_blockade_port_any">Blockade any port settlement.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_naval_units_co_op">Together with your cooperative ally, maintain %n naval units.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_war_carthage_description">The Carthaginians, as inheritors of Phoenicia's trading empire, had always tried to control the Mediterranean, and Greek colonies too. Any Athenian dominance at sea would have made a Carthaginian war grimly inevitable.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_invasion_britannia_description">Although Gauls settled peaceably in Britannia, an aggressive, successful tribe might have shown less restraint. Their northern brothers across the sea would submit or be destroyed.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_king_gauls_description">Most of the free Gallic tribes gave Vercingetorix command of their warriors so that he could fight the Romans and defeat Julius Caesar's invasion. Never before had a man become the King of Gaul in all but name…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_generic_current_total">Current total: %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_king_britons_description">"Even when the Romans invaded, no single king gained the allegiance of all Britannia. Even so, the Romans referred to Cunobelinus as ""King of the Britons""; he had mastery of much of the south east where the Roman landings took place."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_6_successor_conflict_heading">Successor Conflict</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_7_successor_conflict_heading">Successor Conflict</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_8_conquest_germania_description">The Gauls and the Germanic tribes had a history of conflict. Had the Gauls successfully resisted the Romans they might have turned towards Germania.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_into_asia_description">Rome's legions marched far from home. Conflict with Pontus, and a desire to crush the Cilician pirates, meant Romans had to take action in Asia Minor.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_8_leagacy_diodotus_heading">The Legacy of Diodotus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_1_reestablishing_ties_heading">Reestablishing Ties</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_make_alliance_any">Forge a defensive or military alliance with any faction.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_philhellenic_friends_description">As Rome's frontiers advanced, once again Athens found itself threatened. The belligerence of Pontus towards Rome, and Pontic appreciation of  Greek culture, made the kingdom an ideal ally.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_galatian_war_description">Although Pontus and the Galatians were often allies, Pontic ambition and the Galatians' taste for battle meant they fought against each other too. </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_fall_seleucids_description">War between the Parthians and the Seleucids was interminable, and other long wars left the Seleucids utterly beaten. It fell to the Romans to deliver the last blow but, had they held back, then Parthia would have crushed the Seleucids once and for all.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_defeat_navy_any">Defeat any fleet in battle.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_eastern_wars_description">Wars between Sparta and the despotic empires of the east became the legend. When Philip of Macedon called on subjugated Greek states to join him in invading Persia, the Spartan kings refused. If Spartans did not command, what was the point? It was a meaningless </string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_7_footsteps_legends_description">Match Alexander's achievements was a defining dream for all the Successors. The Seleucid dynasty was waning even as the Egyptians warred with them over Syria. The Pharaohs would have delighted in besting their predecessors in becoming the undesputed rulers such lands.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_provinces_satrapy_including_n">Completely control the following %n provinces either by direct ownership or through satrapies and military allies:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_7_war_north_heading">War in the North</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_8_scourge_description">The Germans had little regard for the soft ways of civilisation. The tribes would attack, loot and burn soft, civilised settlements before seeking new targets.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_3_scourge_description">The Germans had little regard for civilised settlements. The tribes would attack, loot and burn soft, civilised places before looking for new prey.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_9_fall_parthia_description">Parthia was an obstacle to Pontic ascendancy. Had war erupted between Pontus and Parthia it there would have been hard fighting to the bitter end.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_ever_eastward_heading">Ever Eastward</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_1_punic_wars_heading">The Reclamation of Cyrenaica</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_eastern_wars_description">Wars between Sparta and the despotic empires of the east became the legend. After the fall of the Athenian empire, the Spartans established themselves in Asia Minor. Many in the old Persian east feared that they would go even further…</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_unlock_building">Enables the construction of:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_consolidation_greece_description">A true friend to the Greeks and a lover of all things Hellenic would ensure the safekeeping of their lands and culture. Who but the king of Pontus could perform this noble service for civilisation?</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_gallic_expedition_description">During the 4th and 3rd Centuries BC, Gallic tribes such as the Volcae migrated eastward into central Europe and past the Hellespont. Pannonia was taken quickly, overrun by Gauls from the north and west.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_4_gallic_expedition_description">During the 4th and 3rd Centuries BC, Gallic tribes such as the Volcae migrated eastward into central Europe and past the Hellespont. The Illyrians, already beset by Greeks, were easy prey for Molistomos' warband.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_5_gallic_expedition_description">During the 4th and 3rd Centuries BC, Gallic tribes such as the Volcae migrated eastward into central Europe and past the Hellespont. The chieftain Bolgios led a successful invasion of Macedonia, killing their king in battle.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_6_gallic_expedition_description">During the 4th and 3rd Centuries BC, Gallic tribes such as the Volcae migrated eastward into central Europe and past the Hellespont. After successful campaigns in the area, Cerethrius established a Gallic kingdom in Thracia.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_7_gallic_expedition_description">During the 4th and 3rd Centuries BC, Gallic tribes such as the Volcae migrated eastward into central Europe and past the Hellespont. Nicomedes, king of Bithynia, brought many Gauls to Asia to stop his brother's insurrection.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_8_gallic_expedition_description">During the 4th and 3rd Centuries BC, Gallic tribes such as the Volcae migrated eastward into central Europe and past the Hellespont. Nicomedes, king of Bithynia, brought many Gauls to Asia to stop his brother's insurrection.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_invasion_greece_description">The Parthians were inevitably influenced by Greek culture as they took lands once conquered by Alexander and his successors. As a reflection of this hellenisation, or perhaps to echo the glory of their Persian ancestors, a Parthian invasion of Greece could have been carried out.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_2_military_developments_description">War with Rome forced military development to quicken. While Carthage was superior at sea, the Romans were master of land warfare, and showed a terrifying willingness and ability to adopt foreign ideas for warfare to suit Roman military needs.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_macedonian_wars_description">By the end of the 3rd Century BC, the Romans had defeated Carthage in the First Punic War, and turned their attention towards Macedon. The Romans portrayed themselves as liberating the  Greek states from Macedonian oppression.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_mithridatic_wars_heading">The Mithridatic Wars</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_4_expedition_heading">Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_5_expedition_heading">Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_6_expedition_heading">Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_7_expedition_heading">Expedition</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_5_eastern_wars_description">Wars between Sparta and the despotic empires of the east became the legend. Had Sparta invaded, they might have advanced eastward towards the old heartlands of the Persian Empire.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_1_luxurious_wares_description">The Greek colony of Massalia, on the Mediterranean coast, was an important trading partner for the Gallic tribes. Here they could obtain luxuries, wines and exotic goods from the Mediterranean and beyond.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_abort_region_became_allied">You have become allied with the owner of this settlement.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_3_into_hispania_heading">Into Hispania</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_territorial_expansion_description">"To protect the kingdom and its allies, the rulers of Epirus sent armies north into Illyria and west across the Adriatic, into the greater Greece of ""Megale Hellas""."</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_spartan_hegemony_heading">Spartan Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_9_fall_rome_description">A Ptolemaic Egyptian empire comparable to Alexander's conquests could have endured years of conflict with Rome. Such an Egypt would not be able to have peace until the Romans had been subjugated.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_8_invasion_africa_description">Unlike their Achaemenid Persian predecessors, the Parthians had little interest in naval matters. Instead of creating a mighty fleet to dominate the Mediterranean after reaching the Levantine coast, it is more likely that the Parthians would have conquered the north African coast by land.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_generic_current_total_out_of">Current total: %n / %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_subjugate_faction_satrapy">Subjugate this faction by making them your satrapy or by capturing their last remaining settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_units_co_op">Together with your cooperative ally, maintain %n units in total.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_8_into_germania_heading">Into Germania</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_spartan_hegemony_heading">Spartan Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_subjugation_macedon_heading">The Subjugation of Macedon</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_construct_building">Construct the following building:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_3_friend_rome_heading">Friend of Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_4_rome_destroyed_description">By the end of the Third Punic War, Carthage and Rome were locked in a death struggle, and the Roman Senate sanctioned the utter destruction of Carthage. The Carthaginians had always been more restrained but, pushed beyond endurance they might well have settled on a policy of wiping Rome from the face of the earth.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_7_consolidation_italia_description">To solve the Roman problem once and for all, Pontus would have to dominate the Italian peninsula. The Republic could never be free.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_7_new_enemies_heading">New Enemies</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_5_greek_alliance_description">Mithridates VI became firm friends with Aristion, the Athenian ambassador. With Mithridates' help, Aristion became Tyrant of Athens. He assured his people that, with Pontic aid, Greece could be free of Rome.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_1_cappadocia_heading">Cappadocia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_pro_capture_buxentum_heading">Capture Buxentum</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_capture_region_any">Capture any settlement.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_1_hellenic_league_description">There was a delicate balance of power in Greece. Cities formed leagues to protect themselves from, or threaten, their neighbours. Athens and Sparta had often fought each other, but as Macedon became weakened by war the time was right for an anti-Macedon Hellenic League.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_8_legacy_leonidas_description">King Leonidas ruled Sparta at the time of the Persian Wars, and is remembered for his heroic stand with 300 Spartans at Thermopylae. His courage, sense of duty, and military skill were inspirational to every Spartan.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_8_barbarian_frontier_heading">The Barbarian Frontier</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_sabotage_building_faction">Use an agent against a settlement belonging to the following faction:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_achieve_victory">Achieve any of the three victory conditions.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_3_consolidation_asia_heading">The Consolidation of Asia Minor</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_consolidation_asia_heading">The Consolidation of Asia Minor</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_4_war_egypt_heading">War With Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_pontus_6_war_egypt_heading">The Fall of Egypt</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_epirote_empire_description">Mastery of the Mediterranean would have required Epirus to develop a long reach. Control of the old Greek and Phoenician trading colonies in the north-west Mediterranean would have been an excellent start.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_epirote_empire_description">Mastery of the Mediterranean would have required Epirus to develop a long reach. Control of north-west Africa, as far as Libya, would have provided fertile lands and untold riches from the trade routes established centuries earlier by the Phoenicians.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_epirote_empire_description">Mastery of the Mediterranean would have required Epirus to develop a long reach. Southern Asia Minor would have provided trade with the east and a base for launching expeditions into the Levant and beyond.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_a_port_adjoining_sea_regions">Hold a port settlement adjoining each of the following sea regions:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_5_danubian_frontier_description">Rome's military campaigns took the legions far from home. After the conquest of Macedon, expansion to the north brought Roman legionaries to banks of the Danube, and battle with the tribes across the water...</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_7_when_stop_heading">When to Stop</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_briton_2_chariot_warfare_description">The Britons were among the last Celts to use chariots in battle. During her war of revenge against the Romans, the Iceni warrior-queen Boudica is said to have commanded while riding on a war chariot.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_1_free_athens_heading">Free Athens</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_control_n_regions_nooption">Control %n settlements either by direct ownership or through military allies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_3_subjugation_seleucia_description">The Ptolemaic and Seleucid dynasties warred incessantly. Unfortunate dynastic and domestic problems hampered Egypt's efforts. Without these, the Pharoah may have crushed the Seleucid Empire by the early 2nd Century BC.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_3_common_cause_heading">Common Cause</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_naval_supremacy_heading">Naval Supremacy</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_2_fall_macedon_description">Sparta and the other Greek states grew weary of Macedonian attempts to rule Hellas. While Sparta was weaker than in the past, so were the Macedonians, and an ambitious Sparta, might have brought Macedon to heel once and for all.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_3_trade_experts_description">Carthage had a trade empire based on unrivalled knowledge of the Mediterranean shipping lanes and of the ocean beyond the Pillars of Hercules. The Carthaginians also had an extensive land trade with many African kingdoms and Iberian tribes.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_4_successor_conflict_heading">Successor Conflict</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_6_successor_conflict_heading">Successor Conflict</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_sabotage_building">Use an agent against the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_5_alexander_successors_description">Alexander the Great's mother was an Epirote and the two lands had seemingly good relations. In seeking to dominate Africa, any Epirote ruler would have done well to secure the support of Alexander's successors, the Ptolemiac dynasty in Egypt.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_macedon_2_dawn_new_empire_description">Although resistance by the Greek city-states and a war with the Roman Republic prevented Antigonus securing control of Greece and the Greek colonies, he came close to reasserting Macedonian dominance in the Aegaean.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_1_assertion_power_description">Having survived invasion, civil turmoil and the plotting of rival Latin tribes, the Roman Republic occupied more than half of the Italian peninsula by the middle of the 3rd Century BC.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_1_fall_macedon_description">The Spartans came to despise Phillip II of Macedon and his grand ambitions. A war against Epirus saw Spartans and Macedonians set aside their differences, but the accord did not last.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_payload_fame">Imperium:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_alexander_successors_description">Alexander the Great's mother was an Epirote and the two lands had seemingly good relations. In seeking to dominate Asia, any Epirote ruler would have done well to secure the support of Alexander's successors, the Seleucids.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_2_warbands_heading">Warbands</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_return_phoenicia_description">Carthaginians were descended from Phoenicians, once a powerful people in the eastern Mediterranean and the Levant. Had Carthage not fallen to a Roman attack, would the Carthaginians have retaken their ancestral homelands?</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_4_carthage_destroyed_description">After years of warfare, the differences between Romans and Carthaginians could only end in fire and blood. The Roman Senate called for the utter destruction of Carthage.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_6_dominating_levant_heading">Dominating the Levant</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_german_3_strange_allies_description">The Germanic and Gallic tribes had little love for one another, but in desperate times they would ally. Under Ariovistus, the Suebi gave military support to the Sequani in their war against the Aedui.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_sparta_1_fall_epirus_heading">The Fall of Epirus</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_5_wealth_successors_description">At the time of his death, Alexander the Great had created a wealthy and powerful empire stretching across the known world. Matching this achievement was an aspiration for all his Successors.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_carthage_5_masters_southern_mediterranean_description">For many years Carthaginian naval dominace was unchallenged. To maintain this state of affairs it might well have been necessary to sieze control of key southern ports.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_4_hegemony_heading">Hegemony</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_gaul_3_powerful_ally_heading">A Powerful Ally</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_raise_fleet_region">Raise a fleet at the following settlement:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_rome_6_into_britannia_heading">Into Britannia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_2_tarantine_warriors_heading">Tarantine Warriors</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_construct_building_chain">Construct a building from the following chain:</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_4_war_rome_heading">War With Rome</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_3_war_carthage_description">The Sicilian Greek colonies invited Pyrrhus to aid them in their war against the Carthaginians, who dominated the island.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_athens_1_hellenic_league_description">There was a delicate balance of power in Greece. Cities formed leagues to protect themselves from, or threaten, their neighbours. Athens and Sparta had often fought each other, but as Macedon became weakened by war the time was right for an anti-Macedon Hellenic League.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_6_subjugation_armenia_heading">The Subjugation of Armenia</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_epirus_6_war_elephants_description">When Pyrrhus invaded Italy, he surprised the Romans by using war elephants: these terrifying beasts could devastate enemy armies.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_mis_activity_own_n_naval_units_progress">Current naval units: %n</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_egypt_7_hand_that_feeds_description">As the Ptolemaic dynasty's power dwindled, their Roman allies reduced Egypt to little more than a client state of the Republic. After Caesar's assassination Queen Cleopatra attempted to reclaim Egypt's former glory. Even if Egyptian power had remained strong, war with Rome for the Mediterranean would have been highly likely.</string>
<string name="mission_text_text_objective_parthia_5_into_syria_heading">Into Syria</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>