<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="prologue_chapters_subtitle_2">Campaign Tutorial</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_subtitle_3">Advanced Campaign Tutorial</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_subtitle_1">Battle Tutorial</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_description_1">"It is 316BC, and the fledgling Roman Republic is engaged in a long and deadly war against the Samnite peoples of the hills and mountains of central Italy. The campaigning season has just opened and in a bid to gain the initiative both consuls, Laenas and Rutilus, have marched out at the head of a combined army.

News has just reached Rome that this army has been defeated in the field.

Consul Rutilus is reported captured by the Samnites, and the remnants of his consular army are now besieged at Capua. A call to arms has been sounded to any able-bodied men to assist Capua's plight.
Tribune Gaius Fulvius Silanus, commander of the grain store at Tarracina, prepares to mobilise his garrison troops in response."</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_description_3">"With the nose of the Samnite attack bloodied on the slopes of Vesuvius and the home front now secure, the Romans can take the fight to their enemy. To this end the Senate have appointed Silanus to the position of proconsul, giving him responsibility for all state affairs and a mandate to build an army and invade Samnite territory.

First to feel the wrath of Rome will be Salernum, taken relatively recently and with a populace still resenting the Samnite invaders. With the port at Salernum captured, the Romans will be free to launch attacks from both land and sea.

Silanus knows he has the support of every Roman as he seeks to reconquer Salernum, avenge the demise of the Lucanians, take the fight to the Samnite capital, and discover the fate of Consul Rutilus."</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_description_2">"The actions of Silanus and the swift response of Rome's Lucanian allies have resulted in victory over the Samnites at Capua. The field was not won without cost, however. Consul Laenas is slain, Consul Rutilus is still missing, and the remainder of the Roman army has been decimated.

With fresh Samnite armies bearing down upon Rome and her allies, the Senate has tasked Silanus with the defence of the Campanian plain, which guards the approach to Rome itself. Should Silanus fail then Rome will be defenceless."</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_title_2">The Defence of Campania</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_title_3">The Invasion of Samnium</string>
<string name="prologue_chapters_title_1">The Siege of Capua</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>