<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_16">However, our ships stand ready to intercept. Armed with ballistae and our finest archers, they are more than a match for the Roman fleet. Our first priority should be to send them forwards.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_15">The Roman fleet attacks from the south. Beware, as they may disembark troops to bolster their land forces.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_14">Our ballistae will rain down the fires of Zeus-Amun upon their heads.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_13">Our war elephants will crush their front lines as they come forward.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_11">Our war elephants and scythed-chariots will smash through their front lines as they approach.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_10">The Romans are attacking in force, but we hold an excellent defensive position on the hill. Maintain the high ground, and the advantage it offers, at all costs.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_09">However, the Egyptian fleet bars your way and must be destroyed before such a landing can be attempted.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_08">Your task will be to disembark these troops either here, to support the main advance, or here to the rear of the enemy position.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_07">Aboard these ships are some of Rome’s toughest legionaries.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_06">This is the Roman fleet, under your control.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_05">The assault must succeed before Egyptian reinforcements arrive from the north.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_04">In order to win this battle, the Roman army must capture and hold the Egyptian baggage train at the top of the hill.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_03">Ptolemy’s position is fortified by the terrain. His hilltop camp is guarded by the Nile to the east, steep slopes to the south, and surrounded by marshes.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.E3_Intro_02">Julius Caesar has joined forces with his allies and is marching on Ptolemy’s army.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Pre_01">It is 52BC, and for six years Julius Caesar has campaigned in Gaul, cementing Roman rule through conquest and diplomacy.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Pre_03">The Roman people, keen to see a swift end to the war, elect Varro and Paullus as Consuls.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Pre_03">His attention settled on the Parthian Empire. How better for Crassus to prove himself the greatest hero in Rome than to defeat an empire that Pompey could not?</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Pre_03">Philip, aggressively expanding his influence in Greece, had come to blows with Rome in past.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Pre_02">After several major victories against Rome, Hannibal continues his campaign around Italy.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Pre_02">He had wealth and power. A Triumph before all of Rome: this is what he wanted most of all.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Pre_02">In 201BC Rome received envoys from Pergamon and Rhodes requesting assistance in a conflict against Philip V, King of Macedon.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Pre_03">The tribes united behind the leader of the Averni, Vercingetorix, and prepared to rise again.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Pre_01">It is 216 BC, in the midst of the Second Punic War.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Pre_01">The achievements of his fellow triumvirs cast a long shadow over Crassus.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Pre_01">Following her victory over Carthage in the Second Punic War, Rome was once again an ascendant power in the Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Pre_02">Following the destruction of the 14th Legion in an ambush, however, dissent began to spread throughout Gaul.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Pre_00">In 53BC Rome was ruled by three members of a Triumvirate: Pompey, Caesar and Crassus.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Pre_05">However, Vercingetorix has sent word out to allied tribes nearby. Caesar knows that Alesia will expect reinforcements soon.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Pre_04">After a series of battles across Gaul, Caesar finally pins down Vercingetorix in a hill fort at Alesia.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Pre_06">Little did Crassus know that Ariamnes was in the service of the Parthian Empire.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Pre_05">This new Roman army marches onto the Apulian plain, determined to halt Hannibal's advance through Italy.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Pre_05">Instead he took a local chieftain, Ariamnes, as his guide. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Pre_05">The two forces would close upon each other around the Cynoscephalae hills in central Greece.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Pre_04">The Senate gives them command of an army larger than any the Republic has fielded before, specifically to deal with the Carthaginian threat.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Pre_04">Crassus travelled to Syria with his son, arrogantly ignoring the will of the Senate and offers of support.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Pre_04">The Roman Senate, eager to check his ambitions and expand Rome's own influence, dispatched an army to confront Philip.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Pre_04">Ptolemy, intending to defeat this army, travels down the Nile river to meet them.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Pre_05">However it is Caesar who finds Mithridates first, and leads a combined force against Ptolemy on the banks of the Nile.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Pre_02">Julius Caesar supports Cleopatra's claim, but is outnumbered and besieged at Alexandria.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Pre_03">His ally, Mithridates of Pergamon, marches into Egypt to relieve him.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Pre_01">It is 47 BC and Cleopatra VII and Ptolemy XIII vie for the throne of Egypt.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Pre_02">Over the past three years, the Seleucid King Antiochus III has pushed through Syria.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Pre_03">By 151BC, the debt was paid. However Rome had her eye on Carthage's territory, and excuses were found to resume hostilities.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Pre_03">Marcus Crassus, sent to quash the rebellion, eventually besieged them in the toe of Italy.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Pre_04">He knew all about Rome's military strengths, and her weaknesses...</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Pre_01">It is 49BC and Rome is in turmoil.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Pre_03">Ptolemy IV has gathered an army of natives in an effort to meet him at Raphia.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Pre_02">For 50 years Carthage paid a crippling indemnity and submitted to Roman authority.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Pre_02">Spartacus and his army of escaped slaves have plundered their way across Italy.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Pre_02">Julius Caesar and Pompey the Great were allies who ruled Rome in a triumvirate, but the death of the third member, Marcus Crassus, at Carrhae, upset the balance of power.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Pre_01">Carthage had been subjugated by Rome since the conclusion of the Second Punic War.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Pre_01">71 BC, The Third Servile War.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Pre_05">The Roman governor, Gaius Suetonius Paulinus, regrouped what little forces he could muster to meet the Iceni horde in battle. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Pre_03">Caesar's conquests in Gaul had made him the most popular commander in Rome. Fearful of his power, and supportive of Pompey, the Senate ordered he disband his army.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Pre_01">It is 217BC, a century after the death of Alexander the Great. His successors still vie for dominance over the once-prosperous empire.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Pre_04">Joined by neighbouring tribes, Boudicca's army descended upon the Roman colonies of Camulodunum, Londinium, and Verulamium, destroying the defences stationed there.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Pre_04">Ignoring the order Caesar crossed the Rubicon river into Italy with his Legions, provoking civil war.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Pre_03">Swearing vengeance, his widow Boudicca raised an army and led a revolt against the invaders.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Pre_05">Pompey fled to Greece with the remains of the Roman senate. There he rallied his Legions to make a stand for the Roman Republic.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Pre_06">With three armies closing in, Spartacus rallied his troops on the banks of the River Silarus to fight their way out of the trap.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Pre_01">In 9 AD, after a busy summer campaign, the Roman general Publius Quinctillus Varus marched his legions towards winter quarters south of the Rhine.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Pre_02">Following the death of the Iceni king Prasutagus, the Romans seized his lands and humiliated his family.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Pre_06">Caesar gave chase and narrowly avoided disaster in battle at Dyrrachium. After a brief respite the two armies would clash once again at Pharsalus.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Pre_04">With the country in crisis, he knows that defeat would mean nothing less than the end of his dynasty in Egypt.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Pre_05">In 147BC Rome sent the popular young commander Scipio Aemilianus to end the war once and for all.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Pre_05">Wary of the approaching reinforcements, Spartacus and some of his army managed to break through Crassus’ siege, fleeing towards Brundisium.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Pre_02">Though he didn't know it he was being led into an ambush by his trusted lieutenant Arminius.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Pre_01">In 60AD unrest was stirring in Roman occupied Britain.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Pre_04">Carthage found itself under siege, but resisted Rome's attacks for two years.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Pre_04">Gnaeus Pompey also marched southwards with his legions to join the war, as well as a third Roman force from Brundisium. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Pre_03">A noble of German birth, Arminius was raised in Rome and served in her legions.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Pre_02">Despite the stunning successes of the Carthaginian commander, Hannibal, in Italy, the Roman general Scipio had invaded Africa and was threatening Carthage herself.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Pre_02">While civil war had engulfed the Roman world, Pharnaces had made gains against Rome's allies in the region.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Pre_03">Carthage recalled Hannibal and his army to fight Scipio.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Pre_03">Victorious against Pompey, Caesar now could focus his attention on the opportunistic Pontic king.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Pre_01">In 202BC the Second Punic war between Rome and Carthage looked to be nearing its conclusion.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Pre_01">Following the Battle of the Nile in 47BC, Julius Caesar left Egypt and travelled to confront Pharnaces, King of Pontus.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Pre_04">Hannibal and Scipio were the two best commanders of their age, neither general having lost a battle before.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Pre_05">They would finally meet at Zama.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Camp2.Rom.Outro_01">In here, Proconsul.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Post_01">The fall of Alesia ended the last organised resistance to Roman occupation in Gaul.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Post_02">Caesar's notoriety would grow to such an extent after Alesia that the political landscape in Rome split in two.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Post_03">The eventual result would be civil war and the end of the Republic.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Post_01">The Macedonian phalanx, for so long the superior weapon of war, found itself outmaneuvred by the Roman manipular army.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Post_03">Their victory in the Cynoscephalae hills would herald Rome's growing interest in Hellenistic affairs.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Post_02">Philip was permitted to keep his kingdom but would never again be allowed to field an army.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Post_04">Within 60 years the whole of Greece would find itself annexed as Roman territory.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Post_02">The First Triumvirate was broken by Crassus’ lust for glory. Only Pompey was left to check the growing ambitions of Caesar.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Post_03">For Surena there was little reward for victory.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Post_01">The Roman Empire shook with the defeat at Carrhae.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Post_04">The Parthian King Orodes grew jealous of his acclaim and ordered his execution.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Post_04">It was at the Battle of Zama that the Second Punic War would be decided.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Post_02">Rome changed its strategy and waged a war of attrition against Hannibal, slowly wearing his forces down.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Post_03">Eventually Hannibal and his men were recalled to Africa to defend Carthage from an advancing Roman army, led by Scipio.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Post_01">The defeat at Cannae decimated Roman morale. Nevertheless, they refused to treat with Carthage, rejecting peace terms sent by Hannibal.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Post_01">The defeat and death of Ptolemy cemented Cleopatra's position as ruler of Egypt.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Post_02">Julius Caesar spent the next few months in Egypt romancing the young queen before turning his attention back to domestic matters.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Post_03">Roman dominance over southern Britain would go unchallenged for the next 350 years.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Post_02">Her rebellion crushed, Queen Boudicca chose  to end her life, taking poison.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Post_01">The Iceni army was defeated by superior Roman tactics and discipline.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Post_01">Caesar's victory at Pharsalus saw the end of the Republic. He became dictator of Rome for life.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Post_02">Pompey fled to Egypt where he was assassinated on the order of Pharaoh Ptolemy XIII.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Post_03">Instead of winning his favour, this act infuriated Caesar who had granted amnesty to his enemies, and he became drawn into the civil war in Egypt.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Post_04">Caesar would end up facing Ptolemy in battle the next year along the banks of the Nile.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Post_02">However his actions left a deep impression on Roman society, and his name is still remembered today.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Post_01">In reality, the slaves were defeated at Silarus River, and Spartacus was killed.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Post_02">The destruction of Carthage assured Roman supremacy in the western Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Post_01">Almost half a million people perished in the defence of Carthage, and the city was razed to the ground.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Post_01">Raphia was to be the largest battle of the wars of the Diadochi, the successors of Alexander the Great.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Post_02">Ptolemy's victory would cement the position of his dynasty in Egypt for almost two hundred years.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Camp2.Rut.Outro_01">Yes... Yes, I am Consul Rutilus. To whom do I have the pleasure of addressing?</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Post_01">Carthage soon capitulated on hearing of Hannibal's loss. The Second Punic War was finally over.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Post_03">This would not prove to be enough for Rome, however. Within 60 years Carthage would be ground to dust.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Post_02">Rome imposed crippling terms on Carthage, and she would never again challenge Rome's power in the Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Post_01">Pharnaces would escape the battlefield at Zela, only to be killed by a political rival on his return home.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Post_02">"Caesar's message to Rome reporting his victory would pass into history: ""Veni, Vedi, Vici"" - I came, I saw, I conquered."</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Capua.Leanas_01">Defend the bridges to the last man! Capua must not fall!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_07">The Samnite dead still litter the field, yet already new threats loom and menace our borders.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_06">It is clear that evil, left unchecked, will always find Rome.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_05">Yet it is our homes that burned, our allies massacred and our leader Rutilus that lies slain, butchered by our desperate enemy as their city fell.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_04">We did not seek this war!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_03">Fate and the cruelty of man compelled each of us to draw our weapons,| stand back-to-back and defend our lands against a common foe!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_02">We have travelled far together, down a path not of our choosing.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_01">Soldiers of Rome!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_09">Eastern peoples from across the sea construct mighty Empires whilst we feud with our neighbours.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_08">Greeks on our very shores plot to strip us of our lands and livelihoods.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_12">With the favour of the Gods, we shall forge our destiny together! For Rome!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_11">Our fight is for our way of life, and it has only just begun!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.SI.Outro_10">Barbarians seek to plunder our homes and villages.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Intro_06">But my loyalty is to my people.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Intro_05">Rome may have raised me, trained me.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Intro_04">Arminius? A traitor? I think not.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Outro_04">Arminius… No!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Intro_03">The German will betray you. He will betray Rome!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Outro_03">No one knows. Even fewer care.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Intro_02">You are walking into a trap, Varus!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Outro_02">What about Varus?</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Intro_01">Varus… O! Quintillus Varus… give me back my legions!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.TF.Outro_01">Thank the gods we made it out of that infernal forest! May Nerio give strength to those we left behind.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Intro_05">The Romans must win the battle thrust upon them before they can take the fight to the enemy camp.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Intro_04">As Caesar's men move into position, however, the Pontic forces begin to abandon the high ground and attack!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Intro_03">Facing him, Pharnaces has a large army, positioned near the hilltop town of Zela.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Intro_02">After a forced-march across Anatolia, Caesar has arrived on the battlefield.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZE.Intro_01">August 2nd, 47BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SC.Intro_01">147 BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Intro_07">The outcome of the Second Punic war hinges on the result of this battle.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Intro_06">Ptolemy must be victorious at Raphia or his kingdom will surely fall!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Intro_06">Yet Hannibal still has his war elephants. The Romans must find a way to deal with this threat.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Intro_05">They will not bear being close to them in the coming battle.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Intro_05">With his Numidian allies Scipio has a cavalry advantage over Hannibal's horsemen.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Intro_04">However, Ptolemy’s Atlas elephants are panicked by the larger Indian breed commanded by Antiochus.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Intro_04">Hannibal, meanwhile is forced to rely mostly on mercenaries and fresh recruits, keeping his most elite troops in reserve.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Intro_03">Ptolemy has amassed a large and varied force to meet the Seleucid threat.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Intro_03">Scipio is able to bring experienced legionaries to the battle.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Intro_02">Antiochus, conqueror of Syria, and his Seleucid army, now marches on Egypt. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Intro_02">Hannibal and Scipio finally meet on the battlefield.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.RA.Intro_01">22 June, 217BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.ZA.Intro_01">October, 202 BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Intro_06">If Hannibal's line can hold, and his cavalry can dominate the flanks, then he can control the Legion's advance. The Roman numbers will mean nothing.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Intro_05">The Roman army is relying on brute strength to smash through the Carthaginians. Hannibal could use this relentless push against them. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Intro_04">Although inferior in number, Hannibal's army is highly manoeuvrable, with superior cavalry.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Intro_03">Rome has brought what it hopes will be overwhelming force to the field. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Intro_02">After two days of skirmishing, Roman and Carthaginian forces finally meet on the banks of the Aufidus River.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CN.Intro_01">August 2nd, 216 BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Camp2.SI.Outro_02">Your successor.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Camp2.SI.Outro_01">You are Rutilus?</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Intro_05">Defeat would mean the annihilation of his army and the end of Roman rule in Gaul!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Intro_04">Caesar and his army now face an attack on two fronts.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Intro_03">The Romans have built two walls of fortification. One to blockade the city, and another to defend against the Gallic reinforcements that now arrive.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Intro_02">Julius Caesar's army surrounds Vercingetorix and his forces at Alesia.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.AL.Intro_01">September, 52BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Capua.SI.Intro_05">The city has been sighted. It is surrounded by the Samnites, a people native to the mountains of central Italy. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Capua.SI.Intro_04">Further reinforcements are expected from Rome.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Capua.SI.Intro_06">The Samnites are sworn enemies of Rome.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Capua.SI.Intro_01">Capua, Italy</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Capua.SI.Intro_03">I, Gaius Fulvius Silanus, have hurried south with my meagre command to aid the consul.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.Pro.Capua.SI.Intro_02">The beaten army of Consul Laenas lies under siege in Capua.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Intro_04">Caesar must find a way to overcome Ptolemy’s superior position and put an end to the Alexandrine War.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Intro_03">Ptolemy’s position is fortified by nature. His hilltop camp is guarded by the Nile to the east, steep terrain to the south and surrounded by marshes.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Intro_02">Julius Caesar has joined forces with his allies and is marching on Ptolemy’s army.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.NI.Intro_01">February, 47BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Intro_05">The legacy of two of Rome's greatest commanders and the future of the Republic will be decided on this field today.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Intro_04">Among them are the fabled 10th Legion; the first men Caesar ever commanded and his most elite soldiers.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Intro_03">However Caesar's Legions are veteran troops from his conquest of Gaul. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Intro_02">Pompey, secure in his numbers, waits for Caesar to attack him. His Legions outnumber Caesar's two-to-one and he commands a superior cavalry force.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.PH.Intro_01">9th August, 48BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Intro_05">Queen Boudicca has Suetonius cornered. The Romans must weather whatever attacks the Iceni can throw at them if they are to escape the field alive.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Intro_04">With their flanks secure, the Romans can face down their enemy head-on.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Intro_03">Suetonius has positioned his troops with their backs to a gorge.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Intro_02">Gaius Suetonius and his Roman army are heavily outnumbered by the Iceni force bearing down upon them.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.WS.Intro_01">60BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Intro_07">If the Romans reach the town they will be able to rest. Surena's best chance to strike is now!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Intro_06">He draws his tired men into battle formation to try to fight through to Carrhae.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Intro_06">Spartacus must find a way to swiftly defeat Crassus before Pompey arrives to reinforce him.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Intro_05">Ariamnes, however, has convinced him that the Parthians are weak, and Crassus' own son urges him to strike.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Intro_05">Pompey and his army are closing in from the north. If Spartacus does not act now he will have to fight them both at the same time.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Intro_04">Crassus' generals have advised him to make camp and fight in the morning.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Intro_04">Crassus' army, however, blocks the route.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Intro_03">The Roman general's guide, Ariamnes, has fed him lies and led him through the parched desert.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Intro_03">Intent on escaping Italy, he has ordered his army to exit the valley via the southern pass.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Intro_02">The Parthian general Surena awaits the Romans near Carrhae.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Intro_02">Spartacus is on the run and camped in the valley of the River Silarus.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CR.Intro_01">53BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.SR.Intro_01">Spring, 71 BC</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Intro_06">Control of this area of the battlefield could prove pivotal in securing victory!</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Intro_05">Battle is being joined on two fronts. On the right, an opportunity has opened for the Romans to secure a local advantage. </string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Intro_04">Philip has sent up more forces to secure the hills. Flamininus, splitting his forces in two, has done the same.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Intro_03">There they have sighted forward scouts of the Macedonian army, and engaged them.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Intro_02">Titus Quinctius Flamininus, commander of the Roman forces, has sent reconnaissance troops into the Cynoscephalae hills.</string>
<string name="scripted_subtitles_localised_text_Rom.HB.CY.Intro_01">197BC</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>