<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Karian_Axemen_Tooltip">These lightly-armoured axemen can hack their way into the flanks and rear of enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Axe_Warriors_Tooltip">In the hands of skilled men, axes are terrifying weapons.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Spear_Brothers_Tooltip">These battle-hardened warriors can be relied on to stand and fight with courage and skill.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Spear_Champions_Tooltip">These warriors will stand, fierce in the face of any enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Hoplites_Tooltip">Even Romans recognise the manly virtues embodied in the phalanx.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Azat_Knights_Tooltip">These heavy cavalry are an elite force, deadly in battle, and loyal to the last breath.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Eas_Skirm_Cav_Tooltip">These mounted skirmishers are a useful force of mercenaries for any general.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Noble_Blood_Cav_Tooltip">These spear-armed cavalrymen fight well in close combat, making them a useful striking force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Heroic_Riders_Tooltip">Brave to the point of foolhardiness, these warriors are the heroes of their tribe. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">Giant ballistae can shoot spear-like missiles over huge distances.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_harpax_six">Able to launch grapnels at enemy ships, these vessels are superb in boarding actions.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ibe_Scutarii_Tooltip">Well-paid large men with falcatas can settle a surprisingly large number of arguments.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_two">With a ramming attack that can break an enemy hull, these ships are deadly weapons.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Gladiator_Spear_Tooltip">Spears are the same in the arena and in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Bri_Slingers_Tooltip">A good slinger is worth his weight in slingstones, many times over.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Nubian_Bowmen_Tooltip">These bowmen are skilled enough to choose an eye to hit when they fire.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Thr_Warriors_Tooltip">Thracians are belligerent folk, best put to use in the service of Roman glory.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Noble_Horsemen_Tooltip">These noblemen are well able to smash an enemy line, given the chance to charge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Onager_Tooltip">The kick of the wild ass can bring down cities and kings.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Lusitani_Nobles_Tooltip">These high-born, skilled warriors are deserving of their deadly reputation.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Periokoi_Spears_Tooltip">Those who dwell in the shadow of the Spartans can have martial glory of their own.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Nobles_Tooltip">These fierce men know that noble blood must be proved with the blood of others.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Rhodian_Slingers_Tooltip">These Rhodian slingers are fully worth their pay for the havoc they can cause.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Levy_Freemen_Tooltip">The chance to win glory and position makes these men fierce opponents.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Galatian_Swords_Tooltip">Armed with javelins and swords, these men can give a good account of themselves.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Heroes_Sparta_Tooltip">If all Spartans are heroes, how awe-inspiring are their heroes?</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ibe_Slingers_Tooltip">Killing for money rather than glory does not make slingers any less deadly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Peltasts_Tooltip">Buying a screening force of javelinmen is money well spent.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ger_Club_Levy_Tooltip">Heads broken, to order, at very reasonable rates.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ger_Club_Levy_Tooltip">In the right hands, simple weapons are still deadly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ara_Camel_Spear_Tooltip">These desert riders are hardy fighters, and the stench of their camels unnerves horses.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Pike_Tooltip">This tightly pack formation of pikemen is a potent clenched fist aimed at an enemy line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Sword_Champions_Tooltip">A longsword, armour and a brave heart can conquer many enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Spartan_Pike_Tooltip">These men combine Spartan traditions with Macedonian pikes to deadly effect.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ibe_Scutarii_Tooltip">These Iberians are well able to serve Rome in the front of a battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Painted_Ones_Tooltip">Inhumanly decorated, and inhumanly savage, these men are dangerous indeed.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_egyptian_lft_five">From a shipboard tower, all enemies become little targets to be potted at will.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Afr_Elephant_Tooltip">All creatures must serve in Roman wars.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Syrian_Archers_Tooltip">The chance to strike down Rome's enemies at a distance should be embraced, always.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Bowmen_Tooltip">No Thracian warlord ignores the chance to kill an enemy who is beyond sword-reach.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Eas_Horse_Skirm_Tooltip">Any Roman general finds mounted skirmishers useful from time to time.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_barbarian_transport">Trade ships used to carry goods, people, and fierce warriors.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Heroic_Nobles_Tooltip">"Those ""of the blood"" must purchase their nobility with enemy lives."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Garamantian_Warriors_Tooltip">Trained only for war, these men are fine exponents of the javelin and spear.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Spear_Horsemen_Tooltip">The cavalrymen can do worthwhile damage if they get in amongst the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Bri_Slingers_Tooltip">A good slinger is worth his pay for the havoc he causes in enemy ranks.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Thr_Warriors_Tooltip">Money spent on Thracians is money well spent when each carries the rhomphaia.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Youths_Tooltip">These young men seek battle to enhance their status and to gain experience.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Persian_Light_Archers_Tooltip">Archers should be valued for ability to strike down a distant foe.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gal_Noble_Horse_Tooltip">A mounted, armoured fist is always useful in a Roman army.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Num_Noble_Infantry_Tooltip">These warlike Numidians command the respect of any who face them and live.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Bow_Horsemen_Tooltip">Horse archers should never be underestimated: enemies always respect them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Hoplites_Tooltip">A Greek phalanx, bought with foreign gold, is still Greek, and deadly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Cel_Light_Horse_Tooltip">No Roman general would refuse able cavalry able to fight and scout.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bar_Screaming_Women_Tooltip">If their own men do not fight, then these harridans will take on the foe!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Peltasts_Tooltip">A good Roman commander knows the value of a screen of skirmishers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_African_Pike_Tooltip">These armoured pikemen form a powerful phalanx that can push back enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Noble_Infantry_Tooltip">These spearmen, drawn from the sons of the nobility, will stand and fight to the last.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Royal_Spartans_Tooltip">These men are Sparta's finest, strongest Spartans, and the toughest of hoplites.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Youths_Tooltip">Youth, inexperience, and ignorance of battle: all can armour the hearts of the young.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Praetorian_Cav_Tooltip">An elite heavy cavalry bodyguard, capable of a decisive charge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Sword_Followers_Tooltip">Where a lord commands, the sword is thrust.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_three">A large contingent of archers can make enemy crews' lives a misery.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Rhodian_Slingers_Tooltip">Few can match the deadly accuracy of the men of Rhodes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ibe_Slingers_Tooltip">A stone cast for Rome can be as deadly as any other.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ibe_Balearic_Slingers_Tooltip">If a target can be seen, the sling stone is already on its way.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ibe_Balearic_Slingers_Tooltip">Some sling stones, in the right hands, are worth their weight in gold.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gal_Light_Horse_Tooltip">A good Roman commander can use light cavalry who are useful in fight.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Bac_Light_Horse_Tooltip">The men are tough hill stock, and handy in a close-quarters fight.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Foot_Companions_Tooltip">These elite heavy pikemen, disciplined, well-armoured, and hard-faced, are a terror to face.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Onager_Tooltip">Few men willingly stand when an onager fires at them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Cantabrian_Cav_Tooltip">The skills of mounted archery should always be appreciated by a Roman commander. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_greek_seven">These massive warships strike fear into enemy hearts, and put iron into those of friends.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">Impaling enemies from a distance has a gory charm all of its own.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Light_Hoplites_Tooltip">Discipline is needed to carry a spear and bear a shield in the phalanx.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Thr_Peltasts_Tooltip">"Good skirmishers should always be on a general's ""shopping list""."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Gallic_Hunters_Tooltip">The skills of the hunt, hiding and a sudden strike, are the skills of a warrior.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Scutarii_Cav_Tooltip">These heavy cavalrymen are well able to handle themselves in the cut-and-thrust of melee.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Naked_Warriors_Tooltip">The blessing of the gods is armour enough for any warrior. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">Foreign ideas can be most useful, especially when impaling enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Onager_Tooltip">Walls are scant defence against the constant kicking of a wild ass!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Onager_Tooltip">While generals sneer at enemy onagers, their soldiers do not.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Sarmatian_Royal_Lancers_Tooltip">Bows and lances make these heavy cavalrymen a frightening and deadly force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Galatian_Spears_Tooltip">Armed with javelins and spears, these men are a formidable force in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">While impaling an enemy at huge distances may lack honour, it is extremely satisfying.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">Reach out and touch someone. With a massive bolt right through the sternum.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Tribes_People_Tooltip">A wise man fights the desert before he fights his fellow man.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_greek_two_halfer">Fast, relatively powerful pursuit ships, well able to hunt down pirates and other seagoing enemy scum.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Gallo_Infantry_Tooltip">For some men only the sword is manly enough.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Onager_Tooltip">Britons with an onager are rightly considered to be something of a danger to their enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_ballista_five">Ballista bolts or stones are a powerful tool for destroying an enemy's will to resist.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_four">Ramming attacks from these ships are capable of inflicting terrible damage to an enemy line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">An enemy impaled is no longer a threat to Dacian glory.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Onager_Tooltip">Really big rocks, thrown at the enemy, punctuate many a debating point in war.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Shield_Bearers_Tooltip">A powerful, reliable force of hoplites who can relied on in almost any situation.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Hellenic_Cataphracts_Tooltip">These incredibly heavy cavalry can turn the tide of battle with their thunderous charge!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">The inventive mind makes cruel machines very useful in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Onager_Tooltip">What use a helmet when an onager fires at you?</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Bri_Ambushers_Tooltip">Gold commands the sword's stroke and the javelin's strike.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Bri_Ambushers_Tooltip">Surprise is a sharper weapon than any sword or javelin.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Per_Hoplites_Tooltip">Beyond all brotherhood, the hoplite fights for his brothers in the phalanx.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Sword_Brothers_Tooltip">Those who carry the longsword choose their own brothers in death.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Onager_Tooltip">There is nothing quite like an onager for loosening an enemy's bowels.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Afr_Elephants_Tooltip">Only fools fail to fear elephants in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Onager_Tooltip">The crashing arrival of a large rock does much to humble haughty enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_War_Elephants_Tooltip">The hugely intimidating creatures are trained to charge and trample the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ind_War_Elephants_Tooltip">War elephants are a wave of flesh, unleashed against the unwary.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Numidian_Cav_Tooltip">Almost born in the saddle, these mounted skirmishers are a fast-moving threat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ara_Camel_Spear_Tooltip">Horses do not like the smell of camels: that is worth beyond money for a cunning general.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">The tribe may win little glory in its use, but a giant ballista wins many an argument.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Cel_Warriors_Tooltip">Hard fighting for gold earns a man gold, glory and prestige with his people. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gal_Warriors_Tooltip">A man who sells his sword should know how to use it well.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_five">From the decks of these ships archers can shoot down on many enemies, doing terrible killing work.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">What a ballista lacks in honour it makes up in killing power.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_egyptian_double_hft_eight">Size alone makes these ships imposing: more than suitable for any admiral.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Onager_Tooltip">Artillery puts respect into the hearts of enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Bowmen_Tooltip">Any lack of skill is hidden behind a typical Dacia belligerence.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Giant_Ballista_Tooltip">The comrades of men run through by ballistae bolts often run. Fast.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Spear_Warriors_Tooltip">A warrior grasps the spear firmly, so that it does not shake in his hand.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gal_Noble_Horse_Tooltip">Even a nobleman has his price, and will fight for gold.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Royal_Peltasts_Tooltip">The king's own skirmishers are an infantry force to be reckoned with.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Axemen_Tooltip">Well protected by scale armour, these axemen also carry javelins into battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Helot_Slingers_Tooltip">Even the most stupid, recalcitrant slave can be taught to use a sling.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_greek_fire_pot_two">Fire pots, hurled onto enemy decks, are a terrible threat to wooden ships.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Thr_Peltasts_Tooltip">Light infantrymen, able to move swiftly to counter the enemy, are a useful tool for a Roman general.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Levies_Tooltip">These axemen can announce themselves with a shower of javelins before closing for the kill.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Pike_Tooltip">Even the humblest peasant can be trained to carry a pike into battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Thessalian_Cav_Tooltip">These superb heavy horsemen can smash through most opposition on their first charge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Cel_Light_Horse_Tooltip">Good cavalry are always welcome, and worth the money paid to secure their services.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_six">These magnificent large ships are both intimidating and very dangerous to the foe.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Egy_Infantry_Tooltip">The sons of the desert can be of useful service to Rome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Per_Hoplites_Tooltip">Even the traditional enemies of hoplites copy a good thing when they see it.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Light_Peltasts_Tooltip">These skirmishers sensibly withdraw from threats while harrassing the enemy with javelins.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Late_Libyan_Hoplites_Tooltip">There is a discipline in the advance of a phalanx that eludes lesser men.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Kartli_Axemen_Tooltip">The axemen of Kartli are fierce fighters, eager to protect their homeland.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Cel_Warriors_Tooltip">A Celt may swing a longsword for Rome, and remain a Celt.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gal_Warriors_Tooltip">A Gaul may skillfully swing a longsword for Rome, and remain a Gaul.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Libyan_Javelin_Tooltip">Javelin-armed skirmishers harry an enemy before the main battle is joined.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Roman_Legionaries_Tooltip">Heavy infantry with strong attacks, good armour and exceptional morale.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Spear_Warriors_Tooltip">These spearmen have some training, and are a reasonably capable force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Cimmerian_Archers_Tooltip">Rome can always use tough, reliable and competent auxiliary troops.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Cimmerian_Archers_Tooltip">The Cimmerians have been prized as mercenaries for centuries with good reason.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Spears_Tooltip">Even the lowliest of Dacians can carry a spear into battle for his people.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Cimmerian_Heavy_Archers_Tooltip">These excellent archers can pose many problems to their enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Armoured_Spears_Tooltip">Well armoured, and hard-hearted, these Dacians are useful spearmen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Heavy_Infantry_Tooltip">These close-combat troops are entitled to a place of honour in any battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Slave_Slingers_Tooltip">With the right stone even the lowliest slave can bring down a warrior.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Bac_Light_Horse_Tooltip">The hills of Bactria breed tough men, such as these spear-armed mercenaries.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gal_Light_Horse_Tooltip">Useful cavalry, even when paid in gold, will always find a place in a battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Galatian_Sword_Tooltip">Once their javelins have been thrown, the Galatians can fight expertly in close combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Libyan_Peltasts_Tooltip">It takes skill to skirmish well, and fight hard.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_scorpio_three">The deadly accurate dart-throwers of these ships give enemies pause.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_persian_double_scorpio_five">Deadly accurate dart-throwers give these ships a significant crew-killing potential.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Syrian_Heavy_Archers_Tooltip">These scale-armoured bowmen can do terrible damage to the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Legatus_Tooltip">Romans should be led from the front.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Helot_Archers_Tooltip">A slave can pull a bowstring as well as any free man.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Night_Hunters_Tooltip">Men who can move in the shadows are always welcome in battle, except among foes!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Large_Onager_Tooltip">Carnage is only the start: wise targets remember urgent business elsewhere.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Thureos_Spears_Tooltip">Well able to pepper a foe with javelins, these warriors can fight hand-to-hand.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Thr_Cav_Tooltip">Those who fling javelins in the service of Rome do so with the blessings of Jupiter! </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Tarantine_Cav_Tooltip">These mercenary cavalrymen are rightly held in high regard for their skills.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Large_Onager_Tooltip">There are few arguments as potent as a rock crashing from the skies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Large_Onager_Tooltip">Artillery gives Ba'al Hammon's fists to the truly faithful.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Large_Onager_Tooltip">Wodanaz approves of squashing enemies with very heavy objects!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Hippeus_Lancers_Tooltip">These lancers have a strong charge, and can break enemies quickly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bac_Scale_Thorax_Hoplites_Tooltip">These scale-armoured pikemen are well protected, and have good skill-at-arms.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Wodanaz_Spears_Tooltip">Fighting for immortal honour, these warriors are inspired to great acts on the battlefield.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Citizen_Cav_Tooltip">A useful force of mounted mercenaries, able to hold their own in melee.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Equites_Tooltip">The cavalry elite of Roman society are among its most effective defenders.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Large_Shield_Warriors_Tooltip">A javelin to anger an enemy; a spear to kill him.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Periokoi_Pike_Tooltip">These pikemen are a useful, and cheap, addition to the army's ranks.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ill_Cav_Tooltip">Romans are infantrymen; it makes sense, then, to use whatever auxiliary cavalry can be found.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Chosen_Sword_Tooltip">These men fight with proven bravery and well-honed skill-at-arms.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_First_Cohort_Tooltip">Legionaries of the First Cohort are the best of their kind.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Camel_Archers_Tooltip">These camel riders are well suited, by inclination and training, to hit-and-run raiding tactics.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Leves_Tooltip">Even a poor man can throw a javelin with skill.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Agema_Spears_Tooltip">Guardsmen brings years of experience to the fight, along with tried and tested courage.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ibe_Cav_Tooltip">These auxiliaries are a flexible force of cavalry for any Roman army.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Persian_Cavalry_Tooltip">A good cavalry charge can break the most ardent of enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ara_Cav_Tooltip">Javelins and swords are eloquent in these raiders' hands.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Ptolemaic_Cav_Tooltip">A keen lance, under command of keen hand and eye, can do terrible work.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Noble_Spears_Tooltip">These nobles are as solid in defence as the mountains of their homelands.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Thorax_Hoplites_Tooltip">The phalanx is only as strong as the shield-arms of the warriors in it.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ara_Spr_Tooltip">Gold buys desert guile, and some familiarity with the spear.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Parthian_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">Leave a Parthian a bow and one eye, and he may yet conquer.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Spartan_Youths_Tooltip">Despite their youth, these men are a useful force in battle and skilled in war.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Heavy_Spears_Tooltip">A solid line of spears will keep enemies at a respectful distance.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Triarii_Tooltip">Wealth, experience and age make these battle-hardened veterans a fearsome force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Archers_Tooltip">Men who cannot shoot go hungry on the steppes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Parthian_Sword_Tooltip">Once their javelins have struck, these Parthians are able to finish off any survivors.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Hellenic_Royal_Guard_Tooltip">Only the very best men may carry a pike in the guards and protect the king.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Spear_Nobles_Tooltip">Nobility has a price, to be paid in blood, spear in hand, unflinching before the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Pontic_Peltasts_Tooltip">"No target pierced by a javelin feels merely ""harrassed""."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Sab_Cav_Tooltip">The desert breeds fierce fighters, and good horsemen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Nubian_Spear_Tooltip">The harshest landscapes breed the toughest of men. Nubians are no exception.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Spear_Tooltip">Spearmen are the backbone of an army; they keep cavalry at a respectful distance.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Sword_Masters_Tooltip">These experienced, high-status warriors make fearsome battlefield opponents.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Spear_Tooltip">Levies take up arms reluctantly, but they will fight for their homes and loved ones.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Spear_Tooltip">Angry Italians with spears should never be dismissed lightly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Num_Spear_Tooltip">No matter how reluctant, every spearman holds the line if he wants to live.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Spear_Tooltip">Cheap spearmen are not necessarily poor spearmen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Thureos_Spears_Tooltip">These well-trained warriors are a flexible force of skirmishing hoplites.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Libyan_Infantry_Tooltip">To take up arms for Carthage is to defend hearth, home and faith.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Chariot_Raiders_Tooltip">These light chariots turn battle into a hunt for human game.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Archers_Tooltip">Archers are ideal for harassing the enemy from afar, and goading them into foolish action.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Armour_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">Once their arrows are gone, these horse archers can cut their enemies into tiny pieces.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Libyan_Hoplites_Tooltip">There is honour and tradition in defending one's home as a hoplite.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Thorax_Sword_Tooltip">These well-protected warriors are a danger in melee and with their javelins.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Garrison_Spear_Tooltip">Any spearman should make a horseman behave with a little respect.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ita_Cav_Tooltip">Good melee cavalry can be a wise investment; many a battle is won by a well-placed spear.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Plebs_Tooltip">Rabble from the streets can be dangerous in large numbers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Scout_Riders_Tooltip">The cavalrymen can range across the field, and seek out enemy weaknesses.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Levy_Slingers_Tooltip">Even in the hands of levies, slings are dangerous weapons.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Num_Cav_Tooltip">These mounted skirmishers are horsemen almost without equal.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Per_Cav_Tooltip">A wise Roman commander recognises cavalry talent, and values it.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Eas_Javelinmen_Tooltip">These unarmoured skirmishers use javelins to harass and break up enemy formations.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Socii_Hastati_Tooltip">These troops throw spears at the enemy, and then close to settle matters with the sword.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Velites_Tooltip">These javelin-armed skirmishers are fast moving and lightly armoured.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Noble_Lancers_Tooltip">Keen lances are deadly in the hands of men bred to war.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Druidic_Nobles_Tooltip">Druids inspire by their magical presence, and are formidable warriors themselves.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Large_Onager_Tooltip">An onager lacks the subtlety of a falx, but it still hurts the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Eagle_Cohort_Tooltip">The eagle standard is the heart and soul of a legion.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Egy_Inf_Tooltip">Mercenaries used to hardship are always a sound investment.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Thr_Cav_Tooltip">Light cavalry who can defend themselves are always a sound investment.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Companion_Cav_Tooltip">These superb cavalrymen are an armoured fist to drive deep into an enemy's vitals.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bac_Hillmen_Tooltip">Hillmen are hardy and unforgiving, if a little ill-disciplined as soldiers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Citizen_Militia_Tooltip">These citizens-in-arms will do their best, but they need stiffening with trained warriors.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ama_Archers_Tooltip">There are legends about Amazonian prowess with the bow for very good reasons.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Hillmen_Tooltip">Unschooled in formal warfare, these hillmen are canny fighters if used correctly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Chosen_Spear_Tooltip">Chainmail does not chill a warrior's heart, or still his lust for battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Scout_Riders_Tooltip">These expert horsemen are a useful way of harrassing an enemy to despair and death.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Large_Onager_Tooltip">Subtlety is not an onager's strongest point. Destruction is.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Large_Onager_Tooltip">A large onager gives most warlords a warm feeling of superiority.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_egyptian_one_halfer">These swift, manouevrable light ships are a useful scouting and screening force for any admiral.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Citizen_Cav_Tooltip">These loyal auxuiliaries are a useful cavalry force to have under a general's hand.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Tribal_Garrison_Tooltip">Even the old and infirm will stand to defend what belongs to the people.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_General_Tooltip">Command must be exercised in person to be effective.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Socii_Extraordinarii_Tooltip">For close-quarter fighting, these men admit no equals: a boast, perhaps, but one born of pride.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ill_Cav_Tooltip">Handled properly, these mercenaries can do useful work in amongst the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Scythian_Royal_Horse_Tooltip">If a Scythian has a horse between his knees and a lance in his fist, he will prevail!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Legionary_Cav_Tooltip">Cavalry support is vital to all infantry work, even in the Legions.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Bri_Spear_Band_Tooltip">It is honourable to take Roman gold, and carry a spear into battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Num_Javelinmen_Tooltip">These skirmishers can harass an enemy battleline, or keep enemy skirmishers at bay.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Rorarii_Tooltip">The spear-armed Rorarii can quickly reach a crisis point in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Large_Onager_Tooltip">A large onager gives most men a sense of superiority.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Parthian_Foot_Archers_Tooltip">If a Parthian can see it, he will shoot at it.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ara_Cav_Tooltip">The desert does not allow fools or cowards to live for long.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ibe_Cav_Tooltip">The gold spent on these mounted mercenaries is a solid investment in a flexible fighting unit.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Archers_Tooltip">Killing enemies at a distance is always a welcome thing for a commander.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Pontic_Sword_Tooltip">A volley of javelins announces these men; their swords eloquently make a general's point.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Naked_Swords_Tooltip">A true warrior does not need armour. He is protected by the gods.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Noble_Riders_Tooltip">These proud horsemen will not flinch from a fight, perhaps a mixed blessing for a savvy commander.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Archers_Tooltip">All men serve the Pharaoh, to the limits of their ability, even humble bowmen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_placeholder">placeholder</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_War_Pig_Tooltip">War pigs are anti-elephant weapons, but are useful against other targets.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Lancers_Tooltip">These are hard men, almost-fearless shock cavalry, bred for war on the harsh steppes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Vet_Legionaries_Tooltip">All legionaries are effective fighters, veterans doubly so.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Cappadocian_Cav_Tooltip">These cavalry are very competent warriors, particularly in close combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Bri_Spear_Band_Tooltip">Britons are considered mad by some, but not when they take gold to fight.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Armour_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">A fleet horse archer is never happier than when he has a surfeit of targets.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Num_Javelinmen_Tooltip">These mercenaries are experts at skirmishing, showering the enemy with javelins.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Falxmen_Tooltip">Falxmen give all enemies pause: who wants to be cut in two with a single blow?</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_General_Tooltip">A great general knows when to lead from the front.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Eas_Javelinmen_Tooltip">These javelin-armed troops skirmish ahead of the main line, weakening the enemy's resolve.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Large_Onager_Tooltip">Enemies deserve the gift of large missiles crashing down on them!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Longbow_Hunters_Tooltip">A deer or a man: the target still needs killing.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Elite_Persian_Archers_Tooltip">The bow and the spear make the man who can use them doubly dangerous.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Painted_Riders_Tooltip">Tattoos and blue woad give these horsemen a menacing, otherworldly aspect.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Veteran_Riders_Tooltip">These horsemen have seen combat, and do not flinch in the face of danger.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Late_Hoplites_Tooltip">It is an honour for the sons of Carthage to fight in phalanx with their brothers-in-arms.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Large_Onager_Tooltip">There is little to be said against the idea of throwing heavy objects at enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Short_Swords_Tooltip">Brave, but unskilled, these men will fight and die for the tribe's honour.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Veteran_Spears_Tooltip">Battle hardens the sinews and the heart, and deafens the ear to the cries of cowards.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Tribal_Slingers_Tooltip">Even the smallest pebble is dangerous in the right hands.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Afr_Spr_Tooltip">A spearman at home in the desert has his uses.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Vigiles_Tooltip">These spear-armed garrison troops are also town watch, riot squad and firemen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">These fine mounted bowmen are excellent for harassing enemies. To death.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bac_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">A hard life in on Bactrian plains kills the weak before they ever see battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">These horse archers can pepper an enemy, and fight off unwanted attention in close combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Skirm_Tooltip">These skirmishers are used to plague an enemy line with repeated volleys of javelins.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Sword_Tooltip">Deadly falcata swords are powerful arguments in the hands of these men.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Sword_Tooltip">Never underestimate an Italian in battle: he will smile even as he guts you.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Skirm_Tooltip">Even the poorest of the tribe can fight for the tribe's honour and glory.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aet_Sword_Tooltip">The cunningly curved sword of these warriors does terrible damage in their hands.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Skirm_Tooltip">These mountain men are swift and nimble skirmishers, useful in any battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Skirm_Tooltip">Unencumbered by armour, these fast moving skirmishers use javelins to disrupt enemy units.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Galatian_Royal_Guard_Tooltip">Trained to fight in Celtic fashion, these mercenaries are a tough, reliable force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Noble_Swords_Tooltip">These nobles will go forwards without a second thought, to victory or death.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Farmers_Tooltip">The man who takes up arms to defend his family and land is not without honour.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Num_Cav_Tooltip">Numidians are expert mounted skirmishers, able to strike and withdraw quickly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Archers_Tooltip">Weight of numbers brings it own quality to arrow fire from eastern archers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Aet_Cav_Tooltip">These cavalrymen can shower an enemy with javelins then engage in melee.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Per_Cav_Tooltip">It is wise to hire men who can deliver a devastating charge to your enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Noble_Amazon_Riders_Tooltip">Scythian women are at least as deadly in battle as their menfolk.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Royal_Thorax_Sword_Tooltip">To fight in the Pharaoh's elite is an honourable calling.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Noble_Cav_Tooltip">The men are the social elite of Carthage, and capable of shattering enemy lines a powerful charge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Noble_Cav_Tooltip">Honour and skill at arms are valuable currencies in the desert.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Noble_Cav_Tooltip">These noblemen are excellent horsemen, hot-blooded, and unfazed by setbacks.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Citizen_Cav_Tooltip">The horse-owning rich have the same rights to defend their homes as lesser men in the phalanx.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Eas_Syrian_Archers_Tooltip">Good archers will prove their worth many times over, even in a single battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ger_Spear_Brothers_Tooltip">Germans are still fierce and formidable, even in Roman uniforms.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Agema_Cav_Tooltip">This elite heavy cavalry unit has the training and equipment to handle any battlefield encounter.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Cel_Naked_Swords_Tooltip">The savage gods of war should be used to Rome's advantage.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Praetorians_Tooltip">"The ""tent guards"" are a force of hand-picked heavy infantry."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Cataphracts_Tooltip">Nigh-invulnerable within their armour, these warriors are a fearsome sight.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Eas_Kartli_Axemen_Tooltip">Burying the axe in an enemy skull can be surprisingly good value for money.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Sar_Armour_Lancers_Tooltip">Mercenary cavalry, armed with lances, can deliver a terrible charge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Eas_Kartli_Axemen_Tooltip">Romans are not fools, and will not turn away good auxiliaries because they use axes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Numidian_Noble_Cav_Tooltip">Trained from infancy as cavalrymen, these warriors are a powerful tool for any general.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Mob_Tooltip">Mobs are like the sea: a terrible storm, or a suddenly turning tide. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Scy_Armour_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">There are few things more dangerous on the battlefield than a skilled horse archer.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Helot_Javelinmen_Tooltip">Even the meanest slave can throw a javelin at an enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_barbarian_raider_melee">Useful, handy ships, with crews large enough to board enemy vessels.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Dac_Spear_Horsemen_Tooltip">Dacians are not famed as cavalrymen, but they are an aggressive folk.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Light_Cav_Tooltip">A balanced army requires dashing cavalry as well as implacable infantrymen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Mob_Tooltip">Never dismiss the power of the mob: a few may die but the people live on!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Num_Legionaries_Tooltip">Equipped in Roman style, these men are a strong, flexible fighting force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Galatian_Noblemen_Tooltip">War is the test of a man; these spear-armed warriors are always ready for the test.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Cel_Short_Swords_Tooltip">Bravery in battle, rather than skill, sometimes gives worth to a man. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Eas_Hillmen_Tooltip">Resentment of others can make anyone fight hard, even for Rome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Bac_Hillmen_Tooltip">Armed with javelins and axes, these hardy hill people can trouble an enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ger_Scout_Riders_Tooltip">Good scouts are the eyes of their general.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Slave_Javelinmen_Tooltip">These men are a skirmishing resource to be spent or squandered as their commander wishes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Levy_Spear_Tooltip">Levies can fight and are relatively cheap to maintain, but lack skill and conviction.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Dac_Spear_Horsemen_Tooltip">While not renowned as horsemen, Dacians can still set spears and charge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Levy_Spear_Tooltip">Levies are plentiful, and can stand in battle when properly commanded.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ger_Longbow_Hunters_Tooltip">An arrow shot in Rome's service is always a good thing.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Sar_Lancers_Tooltip">Some warriors are born and die in the saddle. In between, they are mercenaries.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Elephants_Tooltip">These powerful beasts plough through enemy lines with terrifying force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ind_War_Elephants_Tooltip">Size really does matter; it is worth paying extra for big things.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Sab_Archers_Tooltip">An archer at home in desert sands is always useful.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Cav_Tooltip">Skilled in close combat, these cavalrymen are also well protected.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Tribesmen_Tooltip">Every Dacian fights for his chance in battle, no matter how slim.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Tribesmen_Tooltip">Even the least of men may hope for, and achieve, glory in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Tribesmen_Tooltip">Tribes are swift, deadly warriors with javelins and swords.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Tribesmen_Tooltip">While ill-disciplined, these men are ferocious fighters in search of honour.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Tribesmen_Tooltip">Mule-headed ignorance and stubbornness in the face of the enemy can be a useful thing.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Tribesmen_Tooltip">Bloody-mindedness in defence of tribe and family can be used in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Tribesmen_Tooltip">Everyone in the tribe fights. Everyone. Skill and courage will come to those who live.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Ambushers_Tooltip">Unexpected warriors, with javelins and swords, are useful to any warlord.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Cav_Tooltip">These cavalry will do good work at close quarters if handled correctly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Cel_Naked_Swords_Tooltip">The gods of war will bless mercenaries as long as they fight bravely.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Egy_Archers_Tooltip">Archers can strike down the enemies of Rome at a distance.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_barbarian_medium_raider_melee">Able to withstand rough seas, the ships' crews can board and take enemy vessels.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ger_Scout_Riders_Tooltip">A Roman army needs cunning troops to be its eyes and ears.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gal_Hunters_Tooltip">The skills of a hunter should be used in the service of Rome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Cav_Tooltip">Striking swiftly, like the wind, is the desert way.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Royal_Cav_Tooltip">These men may look old-fashioned but there is nothing old fashioned about their skill and courage.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ger_Spear_Brothers_Tooltip">Fighting for foreign gold does not make German warriors gentle or civilized.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Dac_Falxmen_Tooltip">Sensible Romans appreciate a falx being swung at their enemies!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Per_Archers_Tooltip">Deadly archers remain deadly, even when they wear another's colours.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Sar_Armour_Lancers_Tooltip">These armoured lancers can be the sharp point of a Roman general's bloody spear!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Hellenic_Royal_Cav_Tooltip">These cavalrymen know themselves to be heroes to a man, and always act appropriately.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Eas_Cappadocian_Cav_Tooltip">No ambitious Roman commander ignores a force of competent cavalrymen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Riders_Hunt_Tooltip">Germans on horses remain Germans: aggressive in battle, and true sons of the battle god!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Cel_Short_Swords_Tooltip">It is often enough to sell bravery and a taste for glory.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Mob_Tooltip">The common people, armed and defending what is theirs, can help in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Mob_Tooltip">The mob is easily roused, but fickle in its bravery and commitment to battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Balearic_Slingers_Tooltip">"""Which eye do you want put out?"""</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ibe_Cantabrian_Cav_Tooltip">These master skirmishers can harry an enemy unit to breaking point, and its death.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Royal_Cataphracts_Tooltip">Armoured like turtles, brave as lions, with lances as evil as wasps stings</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Cav_Tooltip">These cavalry are a useful force if they can come to grips with their enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Levy_Thuroes_Spears_Tooltip">A phalanx that can skirmish is a useful addition to a Roman general's bag of tricks.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Cretan_Archers_Tooltip">Give a Cretan a bow, and he is worth his weight in gold.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Agrianian_Axemen_Tooltip">A force of highly mobile axemen always gives a general a useful cutting edge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Dac_Spears_Tooltip">Spearmen, even ill-trained Dacians, are always needed in the battleline.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ita_Levy_Skirm_Tooltip">These levies are armed with javelins, and skirmish in front of a main battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Sacred_Band_Tooltip">The best and bravest of Carthage trained to fight as hoplites.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Vet_Shield_Warriors_Tooltip">Highly-experienced and respected fighters, veterans make ruthless opponents in one-on-one situations.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Periokoi_Peltasts_Tooltip">Peltasts are expert in the art of making an enemy lives miserable using javelins.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Dac_Bowmen_Tooltip">A little gold sometimes goes a long way when hiring Dacian archers. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Camel_Cataphracts_Tooltip">These camel-mounted lancers can break enemy lines, and disturb enemy cavalry with their stench!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Eas_Hillmen_Tooltip">Hillman cunning and brutality can be bought at very reasonable prices.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Mob_Tooltip">Armed with farm implements, the mob can distract and delay the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Bac_Hillmen_Tooltip">Armed with javelins and axes, these hillmen will earn their pay if properly used.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Thessalian_Cav_Tooltip">Give a Thessalian a lance and someone to charge, and await his victory</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Cav_Tooltip">These light cavalry are ideally suited to hit-and-run attacks, and the pursuit of the fleeing.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Thorax_Pike_Tooltip">A phalanx armed with long pikes presents a formidable threat to any battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Oathsworn_Tooltip">Great and terrible oaths should be kept, in blood and by the sword.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Bri_Scout_Riders_Tooltip">Light horsemen are always useful as a general's eyes and ears.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Cav_Tooltip">These spear-armed cavalrymen fight in close combat in service of the Pharaoh.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Savage_Dogs_Tooltip">Ferocious animals, trained to rip out men's throats to break any resistance.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Periokoi_Hoplites_Tooltip">A man will fight in defence of his home, even if he is not a citizen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_barbarian_medium_raider_ranged">Tough warships, constructed to take on the worst of seas, for harrying the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ger_Longbow_Hunters_Tooltip">Huntsmen will take men as prey, if the price is good enough.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Sar_Lancers_Tooltip">Enemy guts spitted by a lance are a good thing for any Roman commander.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Dac_Bowmen_Tooltip">Bowmen will always find a use, no matter their quality.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Club_Levy_Tooltip">Bludgeoning the foe to death is a remarkably effective argument in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aet_Cav_Tooltip">Armed with javelins, these Aethopian cavalrymen to unprepared opponents.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Thessalian_Cav_Tooltip">Heavy lancers should have a charm all of their own for a victory-hungry Roman leader.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_egyptian_eight">Anyone who does not quail at before an octeres deserves to fill the belly of a fish.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Polybolos_Tooltip">There is wicked cunning in a machine that can fire so many bolts so quickly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Levy_Skirm_Tooltip">The desert-canny fight only when they must.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Polybolos_Tooltip">The polybolos gives men the chance to match the gods in cruelty.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Polybolos_Tooltip">If firing one bolt at the enemy is good, many are excellent!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ind_Armour_Elephants_Tooltip">Clad in scale armour, these elephants are a terrifying, almost unstoppable force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Egy_Archers_Tooltip">A mercenary archer's wage is money well spent; he can kill enemies at a distance.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gal_Hunters_Tooltip">The hunting of other men often has the greatest of rewards.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Afr_Archers_Tooltip">Skilled archers from the desert rarely lack a master for long.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Cav_Tooltip">These horsemen are a versatile striking force when under the hand of a skilled commander.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ibe_Cantabrian_Cav_Tooltip">These mercenaries are masters of the art of mounted skirmishing, and a terror to enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Pontic_Royal_Cav_Tooltip">These heavy cavalry are an excellent tool for a commander, well able to break lesser opponents.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Bri_Scout_Riders_Tooltip">A general's eyes and ears are worth their weight in gold.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Cav_Tooltip">These excellent horsemen can punch through an enemy line, inflicting terrible casualties in the process.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Per_Archers_Tooltip">A purse of gold always improves a man's aim.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Dac_Falxmen_Tooltip">Men who carry the terrifying and cruel falx into battle are always a wise investment.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Guerilla_Warriors_Tooltip">These cunning fighters are masters of ambush tactics and unseen movement.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Skirm_Cav_Tooltip">Skirmishers who can ride out of danger are always a useful force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Skirm_Cav_Tooltip">These speedy, light cavalrymen can do good service in harrying the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Sarissa_Cav_Tooltip">Long spears give these cavalrymen a fearsome charge.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Eas_Cappadocian_Cav_Tooltip">A fine force of mercenary cavalry, well able to handle themselves in battle's pell-mell.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Dac_Spears_Tooltip">Within their limitations, a Roman commander can always find use for spearmen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Levy_Pike_Tooltip">It should be counted an honour to defend one's home and family with the pike.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Cretan_Archers_Tooltip">Give a Cretan a bow, and he will conquer in the name of Rome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Scut_Spear_Tooltip">These spearmen may lack the discipline of the phalanx, but they do not lack courage.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ibe_Sword_Tooltip">Javelins and swords make these Iberians a worthy addition to the Roman battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Cel_Skirm_Tooltip">Even the humblest skirmishers can serve Rome in need.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ibe_Sword_Tooltip">An Iberian passion for violence can be a sensible purchase if there's a battle to come.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Cel_Skirm_Tooltip">Some warriors fight not for pay but in the hope of bettering their lot.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Scorpion_Tooltip">Scorpions are cruel weapons, and delightful when turned on the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Slingers_Tooltip">Even the humblest of tribesmen can hurt the enemy with a sling stone.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Slingers_Tooltip">All Thracians are born warriors. Some are good shots too.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Sword_Band_Tooltip">To carry a sword is to be a warrior's warrior and brave among the brave.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Fire_Raiser_Tooltip">Fire is a terrible weapon, especially when properly applied to the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Thureos_Spears_Tooltip">A phalanx of skirmishing hoplites is good value for money, almost two units for one!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ill_Coastal_Levies_Tooltip">Sharp axes, driven into the right targets, really are worth the money.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Slingers_Tooltip">Even giants can be humbled by nimble slingers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Sar_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">Sarmatians in the service of Rome are good Sarmatians, and worthy of their salt.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Scy_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">Scythians who pull a bow for Rome and strike down her enemies are worthy warriors.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Par_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">No Roman commander worth his salt ignores the possibilties of horse archers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Sar_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">Sarmatians with bows: only a fool would not consider employing them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Scy_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">Few generals consider money spent on horse archers a wasteful expense.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Par_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">For the right money, a horse archer will put an arrow in the eye of choice.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Painted_Warriors_Tooltip">The painted bodies and uncanny rituals of these men un-man opponents before any blow is struck.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_greek_scorpio_hft_seven">The threatening towers on these powerful warships should serve as a warning to enemies!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Ballista_Tooltip">If a man can be seen, he can be hit. If hit, killed.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Ballista_Tooltip">Few men live to tell their children about the impact of a ballista bolt.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Ballista_Tooltip">What better way is there to strike down the enemies of Ba'al Hammon?</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Ballista_Tooltip">Even the war gods approve of machinery when it strikes down enemies!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Peltasts_Tooltip">The art of skirmishing has not be ignored by the warlike Thracians.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Massilian_Hoplites_Tooltip">The heritage of the citizen-soldier runs deep in all Greeks, no matter what their home.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Citizen_Hoplites_Tooltip">There is no prouder thing than to defend one's home city as a hoplite.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Bronze_Shield_Pike_Tooltip">In the hands of an expert, the sarissa pike is a deadly weapon.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ibe_Scutarii_Cav_Tooltip">These mounted mercenaries are a fine force for close-quarter combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Scorpion_Tooltip">These small ballistae fire bolts that can pass through a man.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Infantry_Tooltip">Egyptians, trained for close combat, are hardy and loyal in service to a true Pharaoh.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Scythed_Chariots_Tooltip">The terror of a thundering charge, with flashing blades, is often enough to un-man opponents.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Roman_Principes_Tooltip">Wealthy, older Roman citizens, the principes are a heavy infantry force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Warriors_Tooltip">There is a deep savagery in these warrior's hearts, a delight in battle for its own sake.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Scorpion_Tooltip">The scorpion has a vicious, long-range sting.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Infantry_Tooltip">Able soldiers, well schooled in war, and eager to serve Rome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Roman_Hastati_Tooltip">These young men are the armoured front line of a Roman legion.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_barbarian_heavy_raider">Strong warships, constucted to withstand the worst the sea can throw at them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ita_Socii_Equites_Extraordinarii_Tooltip">These heavy cavalry can give an excellent account of themselves in close combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_barbarian_raider_ranged">Handy ships, with a contingent of archers aboard to harry enemy crews.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Horse_Skirm_Tooltip">Born to ride, the Saka are notable mounted skirmishers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Bloodsworn_Tooltip">Driven by oaths, and seeking glory, these men are  terrible enemies to face.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ama_Warriors_Tooltip">These fierce warrior women are more than a match for most men in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Royal_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">There are few more terrifying sights in battle than Scythian archers, ready to shoot.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Noble_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">"A Scythian horse archer does not question the target, but he does ask ""Which eye?"""</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Saka_Noble_Armour_Lancers_Tooltip">Very little can withstand an attack by these heavily-armoured noblemen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Berserkers_Tooltip">Blood-mad, gripped by shield-biters' rage, and utterly uncaring of danger, these are terrifying warriors.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ibe_Scutarii_Cav_Tooltip">These heavy cavalrymen add a touch of Iberian fire to otherwise conservative Roman ranks.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Scorpion_Tooltip">Honest falx-work or scorpion bolt: it makes no difference as long as the enemy dies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Edetani_Noble_Cav_Tooltip">The courage and shock value of these riders is matched only by the quality of their mounts.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Slingers_Tooltip">The sling is an ancient weapon; age has not made it less deadly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Spear_Levy_Tooltip">A lack of experience does not mute the aggression of these spearman in the least.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ind_War_Elephant_Tooltip">Even the most exotic and temperamental of beasts can be made to serve the will of the Senate!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Praetorians_Guard_Tooltip">Hand-picked heavy infantry, well used to all kinds of combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Scorpion_Tooltip">Cruel bolts, fired over long distances, do much to weaken an enemy's resolve.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Scorpion_Tooltip">Impaling an enemy from a distance ends many a dispute.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ill_Coastal_Levies_Tooltip">Good axemen should always have a place in the armies of Rome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Silver_Shield_Pike_Tooltip">These Veteran pikemen are rarely matched in quality or courage on a battlefield.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bar_Screaming_Women_Ger_Tooltip">Should their menfolk not fight with enough vigour, these women will fight for them!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Noble_Spear_Tooltip">These heavily armoured warriors can always give a good account of themselves.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Noble_Sword_Tooltip">The sword settles many arguments in the desert.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Hoplites_Tooltip">"The sons of Carthage are men worthy of the name ""hoplite""."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Fire_Raiser_Tooltip">There is little wrong with burning away an enemy's defiance.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ita_Socii_Equites_Tooltip">Excellent horsemen and a valuable striking force to a bold commander.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Bri_Painted_Ones_Tooltip">Properly directed by civilized commanders, even the painted savage has his place in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Scutarii_Tooltip">Heavy infantry, armed with deadly falcata swords, are a handy force for any general.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Hoplites_Tooltip">Bravery and brotherhood march as one in the hoplite phalanx.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Afr_Garamantian_Warriors_Tooltip">These javelin-armed Garamantian auxiliaries are heirs to proud and fierce military tradition.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Fire_Raiser_Tooltip">Fire terrifies. Fire destroys. Fire wins battles.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Heavy_Horse_Tooltip">A charge from these heavy cavalry can break even resolute defenders.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Ballista_Tooltip">Ballista bolt or falx? Does it matter how an enemy dies?</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bac_Peltasts_Tooltip">A life in the hills gives a man all the fighting skills he will ever need.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Cel_Axe_Warriors_Tooltip">The right axes buried in the right skulls for the right price.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Silver_Shield_Sword_Tooltip">These veterans fight in the Roman style, and do so with fortitude.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Camel_Spear_Tooltip">Camels stink, scare horses with that stink, and make excellent mounts for aggressive cavalrymen.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Median_Cav_Tooltip">These fine cavalrymen are well able to handle themselves in the cut and thrust of melee.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Armour_Legionaries_Tooltip">Tough Roman legionaries, given improved armour for battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Par_Spear_Tooltip">A wise commander uses what his lord wants afford, regardless of quality.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Par_Spear_Tooltip">Spearmen do not need to be skilled or well paid to die for Rome. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ara_Slingers_Tooltip">Even the humblest nomad may hurl a stone at his enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Afr_Spear_Tooltip">The desert does not breed forgiving warriors.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ara_Spear_Tooltip">The desert kills the weak; it does not train the living to be soldiers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ita_Spear_Tooltip">A battle line of spearmen can be a very comforting way of spending money.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Young_Axes_Tooltip">Youthful courage and desire for glory make up for any shortcomings in axe-skill.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Persian_Hoplites_Tooltip">"An idea like hoplites is worth copying, even if Greek ""liberty"" weakens a man"</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_roman_transport">Trade is the lifeblood of an empire, and trading ships are very useful for carrying troops.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Ballista_Tooltip">Only a slack-jawed barbarian would not use such an efficient engine of death!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ibe_Ballista_Tooltip">There is nothing wrong with testing enemy courage by skewering a few of them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Ballista_Tooltip">A wise horse-general knows that there are other ways to kill the foe.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Peltasts_Tooltip">These javelin-armed light infantry are used to harass slower, heavier enemy units.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Militia_Hoplites_Tooltip">"Any honest citizen can take up the shield and answer to the name of ""hoplite""."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Chariots_Tooltip">War chariots, used with skill, can break ordered ranks of infantry.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Gladiators_Tooltip">Superbly trained heavy infantry with little fear of death.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Carroballista_Short_Tooltip">Mounted on small carts, these ballistae have firepower and mobility.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Num_Javelinmen_Tooltip">The light skirmishers harry enemy formations, and screen their own battle lines.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Spear_Band_Tooltip">Spears are simple weapons, but deadly in the right hands.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Spartan_Hoplites_Tooltip">These men know nothing but war, and others are right to fear them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Dac_Heavy_Skirm_Tooltip">These skirmishers can pepper the enemy with javelins, but should avoid close combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Ara_Camel_Archers_Tooltip">A useful force of archers, if only for their ability to upset ordinary cavalry horses!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Ara_Camel_Archers_Tooltip">If smell alone guaranteed worth in battle, camels would be used by every army!</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Slingers_Tooltip">"Witty slingers, and all Greeks have wit, often scratch ""OUCH!"" onto their shots."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ste_Armoured_Lancers_Tooltip">Steppe horsemen live and die by their skills with the lance.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Noble_Horse_Tooltip">These aristocrats can afford the best of armour and weaponry, making them a formidable force.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bri_Ballista_Tooltip">There is much to recommend a weapon that kills at such a splendid range.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Cel_Axe_Warriors_Tooltip">In the hands of a loyal auxiliaries, axes have a charm all of their own.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Hoplites_Tooltip">"Hoplites: no other word says ""Greeks at war"" in quite the same way."</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Javelinmen_Tooltip">Javelins at the ready, these African troops skirmish ahead of the main battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bac_Light_Horse_Tooltip">Hillmen expect little quarter, and offer none, in close combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Scorpion_Tooltip">A man pierced through is unlikely to dispute a battle's outcome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Bri_Painted_Ones_Tooltip">Savagery, when bought and paid for, is extremely useful on the battlefield.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Thr_Warriors_Tooltip">A Thracian likes to think of himself unequalled by other men. Perhaps he is right.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Afr_Scorpion_Tooltip">A machine that can fling huge bolts great distances has many uses.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Car_Scorpion_Tooltip">A steel-tipped bolt can deliver Ba'al Hammon's displeasure over great distances.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ger_Scorpion_Tooltip">It is better to kill enemies at a distance rather than within reach of their spears.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Afr_Garamantian_Warriors_Tooltip">Garamantian mercenaries are rightly regarded as highly skilled with the javelin and spear.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bac_Noble_Horse_Tooltip">Bactrians are born with a spear in one hand, and a shield in the other.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Noble_Horse_Archers_Tooltip">There is an art to using the bow from horseback, in battle or on the hunt.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Rom_Ballista_Tooltip">Ballistae can shoot with deadly accuracy over enemy-suprising distances.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Tarantine_Cav_Tooltip">Good, skilled horsemen will always find a place in the ranks of the Roman Army.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Tarantine_Cav_Tooltip">Tarentines are a byword for cavalry excellence, and a sound investment for a general's gold.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Bac_Royal_Guard_Tooltip">The phalanx of the royal guards is a capable force, not a court regiment. </string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Horse_Skirm_Tooltip">These horsemen are useful, swift-moving skirmishers, well able to harrass an enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Ballista_Tooltip">War is not always about glory. Sometimes it is simply about killing the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ill_Ballista_Tooltip">Enemies do not stand for long when bombarded by ballistae bolts.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_egyptian_onager_five">With deck-mounted artillery pieces, these ships can rain down destruction on the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Ama_Chariots_Tooltip">Amazonian chariot archers can strike quickly and withdraw before any response is possible.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Javelinmen_Tooltip">These skirmisher harass an enemy line with javelins, screening their comrades in the process.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Egy_Javelinmen_Tooltip">The javelin is a simple, deadly weapon, even in the hands of a peasant.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Aspis_Companion_Cav_Tooltip">The companions are an elite force, capable of great deeds if used properly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Light_Horse_Tooltip">The capable mounted skirmishers are a useful force for keeping an enemy at bay.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Cel_Slingers_Tooltip">These slingers, eager for glory in battle, are highly effective skirmishers.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Javelinmen_Tooltip">Lightly armed javelinmen, intended to harass and disrupt the enemy battle line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Mer_Gre_Vet_Hoplites_Tooltip">These armoured veterans are dangerous exponents of phalanx warfare.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Eas_Bithynian_Infantry_Tooltip">These light, skirmishing axemen pose a serious threat to any lumbering enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_short_texts_text_Gre_Thureos_Hoplites_Tooltip">Every man protects his neighbour, and fights for him, in the phalanx.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>