<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Mob_Long">Throughout history the mob has played its part in the rise and downfall of kings and politicians: a many-headed beast to be tamed or inflamed. The Greek democracies and the Roman Republic were shaped by the perceived will of the people. This was never more evident than when a mob took to the streets, seeking vengeance, to overthrow tyranny, or to protect themselves from aggressors. Ill-equipped, armed only with tools and weapons, whatever could be scavenged or was at hand, what they lacked in arms and skill was made up for in numbers and in anger. Against such violence, even armed troops could be overwhelmed in the confined space of a city. Mobs were no respectors of status: the great Epirot king Pyrrhus, who, having seized the throne of Macedon, and whilst attempting to put down unrest in their subject city of Argos, was knocked down by a roof tile thrown by an old woman in the mob at Argos. The king was momentarily stunned, and that gave an Argive soldier the chance to behead him on the spot.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Thr_Cav_Long">Homer, Greece’s greatest poet, praised the Thracians as “a race of horsemen”. The Thracians bred horses for racing and later improved the breed for warfare. Their horses were said to be larger and sturdier than those of the nomadic tribes to the north, and generally considered a match for most large Greek and Persian war horses. As cavalrymen, Thracians favoured speed and mobility above armour, making them well suited for tribal warfare of raids and skirmishing. When fighting as mercenaries and allies, they were the perfect swift skirmishers for harassing enemies, often to the point of defeat and death, pelting a foe with javelins as they rode around at high speed.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Sword_Masters_Long">While German tribes often fought in a more ordered, organised manner than the Celts, they sometimes looked to their neighbours for weapons and equipment. Sometimes this was taken in battle, sometimes in trade. Celtic armour found its way onto the backs of privileged German warriors, while double-edged longswords were another example of Celtic influence. A long, double-edged sword was a prestigious possession, so those who carried them were either of noble blood or were the veterans of a noble's following. By following a noble, his men were duty-bound to show dedication and valour. If the chieftain fell in combat, his men were expected to fight to the death. Any man who survived such a battle was disgraced, and men were known to hang themselves, unable to live with the shame and dishonour of outliving a battle-lord.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ara_Tribes_People_Long">The Arabian Peninsula was not a state, but a land occupied by inter-related tribes and powerful families. The nomadic Bedouin raised sheep and traded goods across the desert, while farmers were settled around the oases. The camel helped the nomadic tribes to grow in power, and the variety of tribes produced many different fighting styles but infantry remained important in Arab armies. Unarmoured slingers were fast and effective skirmishers, and Arabs also prided themselves on their close-combat skills. Traditionally, they fought as raiders looking for loot rather than conquest. Raids or “razzias” brought honour to victorious warriors, as well as livestock and goods for their tribes. Conflicts were usually small in scale and casualties were largely avoided as a fighting retreat in the face of great odds was not considered shameful. After the conquest of Egypt, Rome had to cross the Arabian Peninsula in order to secure the lucrative trade with India, but the Romans never fully conquered the desert or the desert peoples.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Bronze_Shield_Pike_Long">An elite phalanx of pikemen, the bronze shields were modelled on their hoplite forebears and, subsequently, the Alexandrian pike reforms. Their most distinctive feature, and the one which gave them their name, was their bronze shield, emblazoned with the name of their king. Although fighting in the style of Alexandrian phalangites, they probably wore a uniform of Persian origin. This would include a reinforced cuirass of scales or stiffened linen, bronze helm, and probably a patterned tunic and trousers. Their main weapon was the sarissa, a pike of up to 22 feet in length. As this required both hands, a neck strap in addition to a loop over their left arm would support their heavy bronze shields. In close order, phalanxes, such as the bronze shields, presented an impenetrable wall to the front, pushing back or pinning an enemy so that it could then be flanked and broken by cavalry.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Plebs_Long">Rome’s wisest rulers appeased the mob when they became unruly, but the cleverest leaders turned them against their rivals; the plebeians always had the power to make or break the mighty. Julius Caesar was particularly adept at manipulating the plebs, and his power remained even in death. At his funeral, the grieving crowd hurled their belongings onto his pyre: the fire raged out of control and damaged the Forum. Grief soon turned to anger and the mob attacked the houses of Brutus and Cassius, two of Caesar’s assassins. They had sensibly fled the city, so the plebs contented themselves with looting rather than lynchings.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Hellenic_Royal_Cav_Long">The Hellenic kings who succeeded Alexander recruited their royal cavalry guard in the image of Alexander’s famed Companion cavalry. Similarly equipped, they carried the Macedonian “xyston” lance, a two-handed thrusting spear of around 4 metres in length. They led their royal cavalry in the same heroic style as Alexander, setting an example at the head of the charge. Whilst besieging Sparta in 272 BC, Pyrrhus of Epirus learned of the death of his son. Channeling his grief and anger, he charged his cavalry headlong into a unit of elite Spartan infantry. Toppled from his horse, Pyrrhus fought hand-to-hand against the odds and survived to tell the tale. This approach to frontline combat meant he was held in great regard by his men, but eventually led to his death. Caught in melee in the narrow streets of Argos, where he had come to curb unrest, Pyrrhus was stunned by a tile thrown from a roof and then beheaded by an Argive soldier before he could recover.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Garamantian_Warriors_Long">The Garamantians were a Saharan people who created an empire based on the slave trade, and used a sophisticated network of irrigation tunnels for their water supplies. This vital water supported cattle and wheat farming, and this enabled the Garamantians to dominate much of Saharan and sub-Saharan Africa. At times, their expansion threatened Carthage and Ptolemaic Egypt, who also prized their fierce warriors as mercenaries. A reliance on slaves and freemen of low birth, much like the Spartans, enabled the Garamantians to develop a skilled military elite famed for their horsemanship and their four-horse chariots. Unfortunately, as the water ran out, so did the fortunes of the Garamantians. Unable to support their towns and territories, their military power dwindled. They could no longer get the slaves they needed to secure more water.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ita_Mob_Long">Throughout the civilized ancient world the mob, the people in arms, played its part in the rise and fall of despots, kings and politicians. The rulers of city-states and, most obviously, the Roman Republic had to be sensitive to the mood of the people. Joy from a military victory could soon turn to violence at perceived tyranny; riot was sometimes only a meal away. A public figure could go from hero to hunted man in a remarkably short time. Although ill-equipped and armed with whatever was to hand, a mob was on its home territory, the streets, and the potential harm it could do was enormous. The fate of Tiberius Gracchus shows how the mob could savage someone who had been their champion. He had been plebeian tribune yet, when the mob was persuaded that he sought to become ruler of Rome, he was hunted down and beaten to death. In defence of their city, the people of Argos helped kill King Pyrrhus of Epirus, stunning him with a thrown roof-tile so that he could be cut down by Argive soldiery.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Skirm_Long">The Romans called Iberian skirmishers “caetrati” after their “caetra”-style shields; there are no records of what, if anything, the Iberians fighting in this style called themselves. The caetra was a small, round, wooden buckler no more than 60 cm across. The central handgrip and protruding metal boss meant that it could be used both defensively for protection and offensively to punch enemies in close combat. An experienced skirmisher would, of course, try to stay out of hand-to-hand combat as much as possible, and rely on his javelins to kill the enemy from a safe distance. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Spartan_Pike_Long">When Cleomenes III succeeded his father, Leonidas II, as King of Sparta in 235 BC, he attempted to return Sparta to its former glory, reintroducing the traditional Spartan military system to bolster the city’s dwindling population, even raising some perioikoi to full citizenship. He also improved the weapons and battle tactics of his existing forces, equipping his hoplites with long sarissa pikes, replacing the shorter hoplite spears that had been used for the last 500 years. The Spartan army that took to the battlefield after his reforms was comprised largely of citizen recruits well-versed in the tactics that had dominated Greek warfare since the rise of Macedon 100 years before. Its Macdeonian-style phalanx was employed with some success, as Cleomenes’ forces initially countered the rising power of the Achaean League, but they were eventually defeated at Sellasia in 222BC. Cleomenes fled to Egypt where he was eventually forced into taking his own life after a failed coup to conquer Alexandria.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Spear_Levy_Long">"Spearmen were the lifeblood of German tribal forces. Brought up on the traditions of feasting and raiding, they craved the opportunity to prove themselves against a worthy enemy. Having scant regard for the dangers that lay ahead, whipped into frenzy by chant and song, and armed with bone-tipped spears and javelins, the ferocity of their initial attack was both feared and renowned. The ""furor teutonicas"", as it was labelled by the Romans, did not resemble the disorganised mass favoured by the Celts. Instead, the Germans attacked in ordered columns or in a wedge formation, known as the “boarhead.”"</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Syrian_Heavy_Archers_Long">Massed in large numbers, eastern archers can inflict heavy casualties, and the composite bows they carry afford them greater range, accuracy and power than many of their western counterparts. Constructed from a combination of wood, sinew and animal horn, the composite bow was far more effective than the traditional wooden or “self” bow. As its core offered greater flexibility, allowing the archer to draw its string back further and achieve a great range and power, the composite bow could find a target up to 35 metres away and pierce chainmail armour. Requiring great strength and stamina to use well, the composite bow demanded respect, care and attention. As military campaigns were often fought during the summer and autumn months, archers could rest their weapons during the winter - reconditioning the bodies before restringing and tensioning for future use.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Egy_Nubian_Spear_Long">Seen by some modern archaeologists as the cradle of civilisation itself, Nubia lay between Egypt and modern-day central Sudan. Although much of it was inhospitable desert, the tributaries of the Nile had fertile valley bottoms. As well as being a crucial water source, the Nile was the main trade route to Egypt for African ivory, animals, incense and other exotic riches. Being Egypt’s neighbour Nubia also became, at times, her greatest enemy. The population were often enslaved and used as soldiers. In 750BC, the Nubians managed to conquer Egypt and ruled for a hundred years, so the links and rivalry were deep. With their experience of the Nile, the Nubians were excellent sailors. The military consisted of mercenary armies from the various regions. Nubian archers even defeated the Romans, and their spearmen fought both against and alongside Ptolemaic armies. The greatest threat to Nubia came not from war, but from the humble camel. With its introduction in the 2nd Century AD, nomadic tribes greatly increased their power in the desert and lessened the importance of the Nile as a trade route. Subsequently Nubia declined.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Sarissa_Cav_Long">An early form of lance-like spear, most commonly associated with Hellenic cavalry, the xyston measured 3.5 to 4.5 metres in length. Consisting of an iron spear tip on a wooden shaft, the weight of the head was offset, like many Greek spears, by a bronze butt-spike. This may have helped with balance and, in the hands of a skilled rider, may have meant only one hand was required as seen in the famous Alexander Mosaic from Pompeii. As most bronze alloys are heavier than iron this may have been possible, as the xyston’s balance point was towards the butt-spike. However, whether such lances were as effective when used one-handed, both in terms of force and accuracy, is debatable.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Kartli_Axemen_Long">These fierce axemen came from the ancient Georgian kingdom of Kartli, a region that sat on the divide between east and west. The kingdom of Kartli remained mostly independent until its association with both Pontus and Armenia led it into direct conflict with Rome during Pompey’s eastern campaigns. They were then treated as a subject state, eventually becoming formally allied to Rome following the disputes between Emperor Hadrian and Pharasmanes, the king of Kartli. Kartli did supply axemen as both mercenaries and auxiliaries to the Romans. In battle these axemen used one-handed axes that could inflict horrible wounds, and carried round shields; they wore helmets, scale shirts and, later, chainmail. They were, by the standards of the day, rather well equipped.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_barbarian_heavy_raider">Most of the Northern European tribes were not naval powers but there were able seafarers to be found there. Shipbuilding techniques were well understood so, while the many vessels were small leather-skinned boats for inland and inshore use, bigger sea-going vessels were made. Shipwrights used heavy planking for the hulls, stitched together and then fastened to a wooden skeleton to create sturdy craft which were able to cope with Atlantic conditions. Julius Caesar was surprised at the quality of the enemy ships when his fleet clashed with the Veneti from modern-day Brittany. The Veneti vessels had flat bottoms so they could cope with shallows, but were also of heavy oak construction to cope with rough seas. This made them tough opposition for the Roman galleys, and capable of shrugging off a ramming attack. Caesar says the enemy ships were constructed of “...planks a foot in breadth, were fastened by iron spikes of the thickness of a man's thumb; the anchors were secured fast by iron chains instead of cables”. When the Romans were forced to board, they faced fearsome warriors used to close-quarter fighting at sea.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Fire_Raiser_Long">Employed against wooden gates, stockades and walls, the fire raiser is a means of setting fortifications alight with a cauldron of hot embers, sparks and flames. With an iron cauldron at the end of a long wooden beam, the fire raiser was a mobile, bellows-driven forge. Burning coals, sulphur and pitch were placed in the cauldron, which would be pushed against the defences and then fanned to create fierce, roaring flames. The bellows were connected by an iron tube inside beam to the cauldron; when pumped, the fire flared. Iron plating on the wooden beam protected it from the cauldron’s intense fire and heat; cartwheels gave some mobility. Somewhat ad-hoc in use and construction, fire raisers were used by the Thebans against the Athenians at the Siege of Delium, but the basic principles behind them were employed by many other cultures.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Massilian_Hoplites_Long">The oldest city in France, Marseille, started life as a colony of the Ionian city of Phocaea in around 600BC. Legend has it that Phocis married the daughter of the local Liguarian tribe of Segobringii, Nannus, and settled there, but in reality it was probably settled by Greek refugees from the Persian attack on Phocaea. Built on rocky terrain and chosen for its natural, deep harbour and easy access to the Rhone valley, Massilia became a popular trading port situated in the middle of the Mediterranean coast. Olives and grapes were introduced to Gaul for the first time and spread north. In turn, trade with the tribes of Gaul grew, resulting in some integration between the populations. The Celts exchanged animals, grain, tin, slaves and even amber for Greek luxury goods. In 125BC the Greeks turned to the Romans to protect them against the Ligurians. Rome saved Massilia and stayed to make a foothold in Gaul, although the Greeks managed to maintain autonomy. Foolishly in 49BC the city sided with Pompey against Julius Caesar in the Roman civil war. Caesar’s legions stormed the city, ransacked the Hellenic treasures and took its fleet. Following this, Massilia suffered as Caesar moved trade to Narbonne and Arles, later losing its independence as a self-governing city.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Chosen_Sword_Long">"The longsword was a weapon of high worth and status within the Celtic community. A warrior had to prove himself in battle many times before he could wield one in battle. The two-handed longsword was first developed during the 8th Century BC, but fell from favour before re-emerging around 450BC. It is possible that Celtic iron making was significantly behind that of the Romans: apparently, the Gallic longswords used at the disastrous Battle of Telamon in 225BC bent very easily and had to be straightened against the ground. On the other hand, since Celtic ironworking was several centuries old, some believe that Roman accounts of this practice mistook a ritual to ""decommission"" defeated, dishonoured or damaged weapons."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Horse_Archers_Long">With raiding as a way of life for many tribes, mounted archery was established early in eastern culture, producing some highly effective warriors. While foot archers could carry long, powerful bows, a mounted archer was a formidable fighter thanks to his composite bow. Constructed from layers of wood, sinew and animal horn, the composite bow was a much more powerful weapon than its size alone would suggest. In the hands of an expert an arrow on target was entirely capable of piercing chainmail armour. It did, however, require strength and care to use: in particular, it had to be kept away from damp. Military campaigns were usually fought during the summer and autumn, so bows were used during arid months. Archers could rest their weapons during the winter, taking good care of them before the next campaigning season.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Egy_Karian_Axemen_Long">These Greek soldiers from Karia in western Anatolia were known for their use of deadly one-handed, single-headed axes. Axes had long been used throughout Egyptian and Greek culture, from the slashing, pole-mounted examples of the former to the double-edged labrys, associated with Labraunda and held sacred by the Karian people. Acting as shock troops in Ptolemaic armies, the Karians used their axes to hack their way through armour. Even heavy or chain armour was no defence, as the concussive force of a weighted axe head could still crush bones and organs even if it failed to penetrate. Although effective, fighting in this way was both tiring and clumsy, and the initial benefit from a charge would soon wear off. Lightly armoured, with little more than shields and helmets, Karian axemen were best employed attacking the flanks of more heavily armoured foes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bri_Painted_Ones_Long">"The painted warriors of Britain were recognisable thanks to the blue designs adorning their skin and made famous by Julius Caesar’s ""De Bello Gallico"". Their bravery and savagery is evident from his commentaries. Fighting unarmoured, and sometimes naked in the style of the Gaulish Gaesatae or the northern Picts, the painted ones relied on their skills with the Celtic longsword, a weapon designed to slash and hack rather than stab, and their tall shields, which could also be used as a weapon in its own right. Their tattoos generally took the form of curlicue lines, dashes and circles, which mirrored abstracted animal and natural forms. Frightening to behold, these designs probably held religious significance, uniting the warriors with their gods, their lands and their tribes. Whether woad was the source of the blue dye or some mixture of copper and iron that Caesar referred to as, ‘vitrum’, is not entirely clear. Woad, however, does make a better candidate as it has slightly antiseptic properties."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Legionary_Cav_Long">"Developing throughout the Republic, from to the recruitment of allied horsemen from Iberia, Gaul, Numidia and Thrace, Roman legionary cavalry adapted to meet changing needs and resources. The cavalry of each legion originally included 300 Equites and 600-900 Socii, giving a typical consular army of two legions around 1,800-2,400 cavalry. During the Samnite, Pyrrhic, Punic and Jugurthine Wars, and with the demands of a growing empire, there was a gradual move away to using allied cavalry. 

As the equites became legionary officers and then the Socii became citizens, cavalry recruits from Italy became scarce: by the time of Caesar’s Gallic campaigns the legions relied almost exclusively on allied cavalry. Equipment changed little during this period. The spear and chainmail adopted by the equites, probably influenced by the Celts, came full-circle with the recruitment of later Gallic cavalry. Helmet and shield styles did change and the small round shield of the equites became the versatile thureos."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ara_Camel_Archers_Long">Camels have a number of advantages over horses: although notorious for their questionable temperament, they can be docile when handled correctly, and are less nervous than horses. As desert creatures camels also have greater stamina and can endure long periods without water. This offered a certain strategic flexibility to commanders, as long treks in arid conditions could be undertaken. When faced by conventional cavalry, the size and odour of camels caused horses to back away from fights. The invention of the north Arabian saddle in the 4th Century BC made effective control considerably easier; the steady, elevated position in the saddle enabled an archer to scan the battlefield and pick off targets with some ease.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Sword_Long">The Iberians were a warlike collection of tribes and peoples, and this ensured their independence from both Carthage and Rome for many years. They supplied mercenaries to both sides, and were widely respected for their tactical skills and courage. Their use of the deadly falcata sword added to their reputation too. The Romans called the distinctive Iberian sword type the “machaera Hispana” but these are now referred to as the “falcata”. These were extremely sharp, slashing, single-edged weapons with curved back edges; the term single-edged is also slightly misleading, as the point was sharpened on the back edge as well as the front. The balance of the blade was towards the broad tip, making a blow from one of these extremely powerful. In the hands of a master, a falcata could easily dismember an opponent. The skills of Iberian metal workers added to the blade’s deadliness; their steel was generally of very high quality. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ita_Sword_Long">At one point Rome was not the only power in Italy; there were others such as the Etruscans and Samnites. These various petty kingdoms, cities and tribes often fought each other, but also united against common external threats. It was as the Etruscans waned and Greek influence fell away that Rome steadily began to accumulate power and lands. After three wars against the Samnites, Rome finally became the dominant power in Italy, and extracted pledges of loyalty and military aid from the “Socii Latini”, the Latin allies. There were further rebellions against Rome’s dominance, and most significant was the Allied War of 91-88 BC when many of the Socii turned on Rome. This gave the Romans pause and the peace settlement after was surprisingly generous: it gave the Socii the right to become full Roman citizens, and this effectively united the whole of Italy under Roman rule with a stake in Rome’s survival for all.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Pontic_Sword_Long">Employing Celtic short swords or the xiphos, with its very similar blade-shape, these heavily armoured, elite swordsmen acted as frontline and shock infantry in the Pontic armies. Garbed in scale armour and carrying thureos shields, they were equipped with javelins in addition to their swords. When charging or receiving a charge, they would throw their javelins at close range, draw their swords and attack before their enemy had chance to recover. This has led to them being referred to as imitation legionaries and the suggestion that they copied the fighting style of the Roman legions. Over the course of the three Mithridatic Wars, waged between Pontus and Rome from 88 BC to 63 BC, there was certainly time to recruit and reorganise the Pontic army on the Roman model. However, such infantry may equally have developed under the influence of the Celtic Galatian settlers or the Hellenic thorakitai, a more heavily armoured form of thureophoroi. Whatever the case, Pontic swordsmen were well disciplined and equipped, and highly effective in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_roman_three">Of all the warships found in the ancient world, it is the trireme, or trieres, that remains the most famous and recognisable. Nearly all Hollywood “sword and sandal” movies will include a trireme somewhere. The vessel was entirely designed for war. Its name came from the three rows of oars carried on each side, stacked above each other in staggered columns to give the rowers some room to work. The top row of oars pivoted on a rowlock, or oarlock, mounted on an outrigger projecting from the hull. This allowed the top oars to pitch down at a sharper angle to reach the sea without getting tangled in the lower ones. The trireme was a greyhound of a ship, capable of high-speed dashes with a well-trained crew and, contrary to popular belief, not all rowers were slaves. Aboard Greek vessels they were citizens, and were given respect, not the lash. They were also largely fair-weather ships, and unsuited to rough seas such as the Atlantic; the lowest level of oars were, at most, less than half a metre above the waterline. That, however, did not stop the trireme being a superb weapon against other ships: a high-speed ramming attack could rip a hole in the side of almost any target. The type was also large enough to be used in other ways, which lead to it carrying archers and assorted light artillery pieces.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Silver_Shield_Pike_Long">During his final years on campaign, Alexander the Great renamed his elite hypaspist infantrymen argyraspides or “silver shields.” Following Alexander’s untimely death, his generals fought each other for territory and the enormous power that came with it. When the smoke cleared, the former “commander-in-chief of the camp”, Seleucus, controlled Babylon and several other eastern satrapies, proclaiming himself king in 306BC. His territory became known as the Seleucid Empire, and the silver shields formed the elite of its armies from the very beginning. Throughout most of their tenure they were equipped in the Macedonian fashion and trained for phalanx combat like their illustrious forebears. However, following their catastrophic defeat at Magnesia in 190BC by the Romans, the Seleucids began to re-model the silver shields on the impressive Roman legionaries who defeated them, certainly in equipment if not in tactics. It is thought that the 5000 men at the head of the Daphne Parade in 166BC were silver shields equipped in this way.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Citizen_Cav_Long">The early Greek cavalry took roughly the same form throughout the city-states, being comprised of citizens able to afford and maintain a horse. After the Greco-Persian Wars, city-states such as Athens founded more permanent cavalry funded by annual grants. Right through the Peloponnesian War however, this volunteer cavalry continued to be few in numbers, and was used principally to chase skirmishers and fleeing hoplites. It was not that cavalry were ineffectual in Greek warfare, as shown by the Theban victory at the Battle of Delium in 424BC, but until this time they had been underused and lacked the numbers to make a decisive impact. Often wearing a metal helm and a mailed cuirass reaching down to their knees, they were equipped with a long sword and a spear, usable as both a lance and a javelin. However, a lack of saddle and stirrups, unused by the Greeks of the time, made them relatively easy to knock from horseback.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Companion_Cav_Long">Macedonian companion cavalry, known in Greek as the hetairoi, were the foremost shock troops of their age. Originally formed from the Macedonian nobility, esteemed companions to their kings, these elite horsemen evolved under Philip II and Alexander the Great into a highly disciplined and formidable force with the adoption of the wedge formation that increased not only their manoeuvrability, but also their impact. Eventually their numbers were extended to include not just nobles, but in fact anyone who had been a friend to the king. Early Greek cavalry had been limited to skirmishing scouts and archers, as square formations of heavy cavalry up until this point were difficult to direct and wheel. However, the adoption of the wedge formation enabled the companions to exploit weak points or break the flanks of enemy infantry with precision. To achieve this they were armed with the xyston, a fearsome double-ended lance, designed to counter-balance itself and be reversible should one end break, plus a straight sword or curved kopis for close-quarters fighting. Armour took the form of a shaped bronze corselet, with optional greaves, and an open Boeotian helmet, which afforded some protection without hampering vision. The horse itself was unarmoured. The rider sat on a blanket, as neither saddle nor stirrups were used at this time.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Axe_Warriors_Long">Celtic warriors were ideally equipped to hack through even heavily armoured foes. Their axes took one of two forms: one-handed axes were typical, and the most practical, but two-handed axes were also used. In comparison to swords, axes were cheap to make, and were effective against chainmail, as a blow could still shatter bone and crush the organs beneath the armour. They could also be used to pull aside shields, or hack them apart. Like other Celtic warriors, the lightly-armoured, one-handed axemen relied on their own shields for defence. There was a long tradition, perhaps dating as far back as the Stone Age, of veneration for axes and hammers in Celtic cultures. Although both were associated with strength axes in particular were used as grave goods and were even depicted on coins celebrating victories in the Gallic Wars, 58-50 BC.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Night_Hunters_Long">The Germanic Harii tribe were a warrior cult, shrouded in mystery. Their night hunters were a terrifying prospect if met on the battlefield. Their bodies, shields and weapons were painted black for maximum shock value. The Roman historian, Tacitus, said this of the Harii: “…quite apart from their strength, which exceeds that of the other tribes I have just listed, they pander to their innate savagery by skill and timing: with black shields and painted bodies, they choose dark nights to fight, and by means of terror and shadow of a ghostly army they cause panic, since no enemy can bear a sight so unexpected and hellish; in every battle the eyes are the first to be conquered.”</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_greek_seven">"An arms race in warship size developed between the various nations around the Mediterranean. Size, in terms of the number of rowers, ships length and bulk and above all majesty of the vessel became as much a tool of statecraft as of warfare. A people who could afford such ships were almost certainly rich enough to withstand the strains of any war. A ""four"" or quadreme was still a handy warship, able to manouevre in battle. The same could not be said of some of the large polyremes, a word meaning many oars. Practical archaelogy shows that too many banks of oars simply don't work, so polyreme probably referred to the number of rowers: a septireme is likely to have had some seven rowers per bank of three oars, arranged in 3, 3, and 2 to an oar going up from the waterline. King Demetius of Macedon led his fleet at the battle of Salamis in 306 BC from the deck of a hepteres or ""seven"", but his ambitions didn't stop there. Neither did those of other kingdoms, and later lumbering warships including “elevens, “thirteens” and larger. As bigger ships to carry more rowers, such vessels could also carry big marine contingents, arrow towers and an array of useful artillery. "</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Aux_Socii_Hastati_Long">Although the early Socii troops varied greatly in armament and style, between the times of the Camillan and Polybian military reforms most Socii infantry adopted the equipment of the Roman hastati. Each carried a gladius and two pila, and either the hastati’s scutum or shields inspired by their Etruscan, Samnite or Greek ancestry. They also usually wore bronze helmets and breastplates. The Socii were drawn from the city-states and tribes of the Italian peninsula, and were expected to make up half of Rome’s military. In battle, they would normally be split into two forces under the command of the praefecti, and take position on the legions' flank. During the Allied Wars of 90-88BC, the Socii revolted against Rome not for independence, but to gain the right to be Roman citizens. Those that did not rebel were actually rewarded with citizenship but the people of the entire Italian peninsula eventually gained Roman citizenship at the end of hostilities.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Bithynian_Infantry_Long">"These fierce warriors hailed from northwest Asia Minor and, as their lands changed hands between Greek and Persian rulers, they were subject to many influences. In battle, they used the crescent-shaped ""pelte"" shields of the Thracians, but eastern axes instead of forward-curving swords or rhomphaia. This made them deadly against heavily-armoured foes as their axes could crush organs and break bones without necessarily penetrating armour. The Bithynians wore light armour for the most part, and also carried javelins, much like peltasts. Their style of fighting probably owed much to the mountainous and difficult terrain of Bithynia, as they were, in part, skirmishers and also similar to the thorakitai, or heavier warriors."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Cav_Long">The Iberians harboured a great deal of respect for horses, even worshipping them as divine creatures. In times of war the horse had previously played a minor role, but gradually progressed from a symbol of prestige and noble warrior’s ride to the battlefield, to becoming a major presence in the battle itself. Blessed with horses of great quality, Iberian cavalry grew to become one of the most potent weapons in the ancient world. Their horses were as fast and as nimble as the renowned Numidian steeds and, having been trained to cope with the rough terrain of the Peninsula, were hardy beasts also. The combination of fine mounts and dextrous riders enabled Iberian cavalry to earn a reputation that established them as mercenaries, sought after by both Carthage and Rome.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Scut_Spear_Long">Scutarii, or shield bearers, take their name from the Latin word scutum, or shield, although it is highly unlikely the Iberians used this title for themselves. Regardless, the scutarii carried the thureos, a large, oval, wooden shield that was perfectly suited for use in man-to-man combat. They wore little armour, and this gave them greater mobility than many of their opponents, particularly the armoured Roman legionaries. This mobility was used to charge forward and then feign retreat in the hope of getting the enemy to pursue and break their lines. Once an enemy unit took the bait, the retreat would end, and a genuine attack on now-out-of-position and unsupported foes would be staged: a simple tactic, perhaps, but still a deadly one when used well.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Ptolemaic_Cav_Long">Following the tradition of elite Hellenic shock cavalry, these horsemen employed heavy armour and fearsome xyston- or kontos-like lances. These were considerably longer than normal cavalry spears and balanced by a butt-spike. Using such weapons required Ptolemaic cavalry to forgo shields and to steer their mounts with their legs, in the same fashion as Saka and Sarmatian archers and later cataphracts. Unlike their eastern counterparts, Ptolemaic cavalry did not armour their horses in scale until around the 1st Century BC. They were heavily armoured themselves, initially wearing bronze cuirasses and helmets but later scale or chainmail armour. Recruited almost exclusively from the richest Greek colonists in Egypt their numbers were never great, but they provided a vital shock element alongside lighter Egyptian and mercenary cavalry.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Levy_Spear_Long">"Throughout the civilised world, levies formed the backbone of many armies. Called to service from among citizens or subjects, levies followed a long tradition that began, in Greece at least, with hoplite warfare between the city-states. Equipped with spears, these levied phalanxes could present a formidable wall of spear points to other infantry and cavalry. What levies lacked in skill and discipline when compared to professional soldiers and mercenaries, they made up for in numbers and the advantage their weaponry provided. These troops especially the citizen-levy of Greek city-states, were at first expected to provide their own arms and equipment. As time passed the citizen army developed into a more formalised body where which arms and equipment were provided. Often, however, personal loyalty to a general or king replaced any sense of civic duty, although ""civic duty"" might be grudging to say the least in men taken from their homes, families and livelihoods and thrust into battle."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Egy_Nubian_Bowmen_Long">Nubian archers from the ‘Land of the Bow’ were famed for their skills and used as mercenaries by the Ptolemaic dynasty. Archery was valued in Nubian society: their gods and rulers were often depicted with bows or archer’s thumb rings, and their warriors were buried with bows, quivers, arrows and rings. The rings allowed archers to fully draw their powerful bows, as the shaped metal ring guarded their fingers. Several types of bow were employed, including the longbow and composite bow. There were also many arrowheads, some of which were barbed to make them more difficult to remove from a wound. As unarmoured skirmishers, Nubian archers relied on their spear-armed comrades to keep the enemy at bay, whilst they made their shots count. Under the Kushite Queen Amanirenas, Nubian archers defeated a Roman force and, after five-years of war, a peace that favoured favouring the Kushites was agreed in 20BC.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Egy_Galatian_Royal_Guard_Long">Encouraged by Ptolemaic Pharaohs to settle in Egypt, Galatian mercenaries were employed in their armies and as royal guards. Celtic tribesmen, the Galatians migrated south into central Anatolia and eastern Phrygia following Brennus’ invasions of Macedon and Greece in 279BC. They had a fierce reputation and found employment as mercenaries throughout the Hellenic world. Held in high esteem throughout the period, they fought in the Celtic style, making use of swords, javelins and oval shields. Auxiliaries in the Egyptian army were not generally armoured, but the Galatians of the royal guard wore mail shirts by the time of the last Cleopatra; she was given 300 Galatian warriors in 48BC by Julius Caesar. Galatians were a practical solution to a manpower shortage faced by the Ptolemaic dynasty. The loyalty of mercenaries could easily be purchased with Egypt’s wealth, and they were far less likely to turn on their foreign masters than the Egyptians.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Hellenic_Royal_Guard_Long">Elite pikemen, the various Hellenic royal guards were modelled on a combination of their hoplite forebears and the Alexandrian pike reforms. Trading the traditional spear and hoplon for the longer sarissa and smaller shields mounted on their wrists, they were undoubtedly better equipped and to a more uniform standard than their counterparts, probably being comparable to the lochagos, or file commanders, of other phalanx armies. Kept and maintained at the king’s expense, royal guards were both highly drilled and disciplined. This close association with the king extended to their dwelling place, such units being garrisoned in or near the king’s palace or sleeping in the palace courtyards. Inspired by the elite units of Alexander, such as the hypaspists and silver shields, the concept of elite foot guards may have originated with the squires and armour bearers of the Companion cavalry.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Tarantine_Cav_Long">Taranto, in Magna Graecia, has a rich history. Founded in 706 BC as Taras, it began as the home of the Partheniae, Spartans exiled due to their impure bloodlines. Fortunately, the colony was able to breed superb warhorses, and so its warriors duly grew in reputation. Tarantine cavalry could be combined well with a slow-moving phalanx, providing a rapid and flexible defensive screen for the hoplites’ exposed flanks. Their suitability for such a role, in addition to a growing need for mercenaries in the armies of the Hellenistic world, saw that the Tarantines were much sought after. By the 3rd century BC there was some evidence to suggest that they no longer came exclusively from Taranto itself, the word “Tarantine” referring more to the unit’s tactics and weaponry rather than its geographic origins.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Num_Spear_Long">Drawn from two Berber tribes inhabiting the North African coast, the eastern Massyliis and the western Masaesylis, these spear-armed warriors would support the famed cavalry of Numidia in battle. Equipped with spears, small shields and cloth armour, they acted against opposing cavalry, enabling their horse riding counterparts to harry the enemy and safely retreat to cover. This was especially true of the bitter feuding and warfare between the Massyliis and Masaesylis themselves, which saw them taking and changing sides throughout the Punic Wars, until a united Numidia emerged following the Battle of Zama in 202 BC. With the fall of Carthage, Numidia was free to expand, and this ultimately led to the Jugurthine War of 112 – 105 BC, between Numidia’s king, Jugurtha, and Rome, which was only concluded when Jugurtha was betrayed by his father-in-law, Bocchus.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Num_Legionaries_Long">Numidians were renowned fighters and particularly superb cavalrymen. The Romans who first met with Hannibal’s Numidian light cavalry at Ticinus in 218BC, had no answer to their mobility. Keen to to break the stalemate in the Second Punic War and recruit Numidians into Roman forces, Scipio Africanus diplomatically wooed the Massyllii tribe. Their leader, Massinissa, withdrew support from Carthage, and there were mass desertions among the Carthaginians' army in Spain. As thanks, veteran Roman centurions trained Numidian infantry: drilled and equipped in Roman fashion, the Numidians fought at the decisive Battle of Zama.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Leves_Long">Under the early Roman army’s Camillan system, if you were poor or low born then you might well have found yourself in battle with little more than a spear in your hand. Typically the poorest members of a Roman legion, leves were attached to the hastati and faced the full enemy onslaught. They were used as a screen and to skirmish with the enemy’s front line. Un able to afford much armour, the leves used javelins in support of their richer compatriots. Historically, there were 300 leves alongside 900 hastati: 20 leves in front of each of the 60 maniples. They were replaced by velites, who were deployed across the three main lines of a maniple.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Azat_Knights_Long">Armenia has been ruled by many: the Persians, Macedonians, and Seluecids all played a part in forging the land and its people. The land-owning nobility, the Azat, were descended, so they claimed, from the Armenian gods and like the nobles of many lands, they fought as cavalry. They produced elite, heavily-armed and armoured cavalry that served as superb bodyguards. Historically, they carried lances, along with longswords, maces or axes, making them deadly in close-quarter combat. In 368AD, at the siege of Artogerassa by the Sassanids under Shapur II, they protected Pharantzem, King Arsaces II's wife. The Azat can be considered as forerunners of the chivalric knights of the Medieval age, obsessed with personal honour, loyalty, and their status.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Light_Horse_Long">The Celts held horses in high regard; they were prestige possessions, and revered for their strength and vitality. As a result Celtic cavalry, like that of many armies, was the preserve of the wealthy nobility. Developments in the saddle gave horsemen a firm seat without the need for stirrups: four pommels held the rider's thighs and this, in turn, allowed greater movement when using a sword or spear. With this improvement, cavalry tactics could emerge and two-man chariots declined . They were no longer the only fast-moving strike force. Some cavalrymen carried long swords and, in the same fashion as the traditional chariot riders, were given to dismounting and fighting on foot. Celtic horsemen became a much sought after mercenary force and, over the centuries, served in the Carthaginian, Egyptian and Roman armies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Thr_Royal_Cav">Prized for their strong and swift horses, archaic Thracian cavalry mostly consisted of skirmishers. Their weapons varied from tribe to tribe, but they typically used javelins and the kopis sword, although the eastern tribes were known for their skill with the composite bow. Thracians generally rode unarmoured, apart from the crescent shaped pelte shield. Mainly used while dismounted, the pelte was strapped to their backs whilst riding. What little heavy cavalry there was in Thrace took the form of the king’s bodyguard. All of this changed with the introduction of the saddle in the 4th the century BC. Probably adopted either from their Scythian neighbours or the invading Celts, the saddle led to Thracian cavalry becoming more heavily armoured, with riders wearing metal helmets and corselets, and using rounded shields. Their armament also changed, with the spear and sica being more commonly employed. A forward curving Thracian sword, the sica could easily slice off a limb.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Agema_Spears_Long">Composed of veterans, the agema, or guards, were elite units within Hellenic and Successor armies. They first appeared under Alexander the Great, where elitism was actively encouraged and rewarded, marking the move from citizen soldiers, loyal to the state, to professional armies, loyal to their general. Alexander’s agema probably developed from the ranks of his companions, but as his campaigns continued successfully more units of veterans naturally emerged. Known as hypaspists, they probably fought in the hoplite style, but used a smaller hoplon than their predecessors. Their role was to protect the vulnerable flanks of the pike phalanxes and support the cavalry. Such units could have long careers, the famed silver shields, for instance, fought as mercenaries first for Eumenes and then Antigonus after Alexander’s death, also being used as the blueprint for the later Seleucid silver shields. Highly valued for their experience, many silver shields continued fighting well into their sixties. Later agema diversified, and the term came to be used for many elite or veteran hypaspist, peltast or cavalry units during the period. These units often bore battle honours or nicknames celebrating their victories; at the Siege of Oaeneum in 169BC a vanguard of peltasts, the ‘nicatores’, or ‘conquerors’, stormed the walls.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Bloodsworn_Long">The desire for honour in battle within Germanic society was so strong that some men were not considered worthy of their tribe, or even their parents, until they had spilt the blood of an enemy. The young warriors of the Chatti tribe were unique in this respect, growing their hair and beards until they claimed their first kill in battle. As a result, unkempt facial hair was seen as the mark of men yet to prove their worth, or cowardice. It is said, however, that the bravest Chatti grew enamoured with their lengthy beards and, even when white with age, and having claimed many kills, wore them with defiance. Typically, these men often led the first charge during a battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Scout_Riders_Long">The lack of strong, fast mounts in northern Europe restricted the Germans’ ability to build cavalry forces. Horses were expensive to keep and, given the size and strength of the typical German tribesman, he was more suited to life as an infantryman. Even so, there were a number of tribes that became renowned for their expertise as horsemen; the Usipi and, in particular, the Tencteri tribes, who dwelt on the east of the river Rhine, possessed much-admired cavalrymen. The Tencteri had a strong tradition: their children were raised playing with horses, which were well-respected and treasured possessions. The horse was always inherited by the strongest, most warlike man within a family, helping to create a strong cavalry presence within the tribe. German light cavalry often attacked in a circular motion, throwing javelins before stabbing at close quarters with spears and wheeling to the right. By attacking in a circle, no single man ever led or brought up the rear and, as the attack rotated, each man in turn came into contact with the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Legatus">"Traditionally, the rank of legatus was given to Roman generals in command of a legion. Deputies to the commander-in-chief, these officers accompanied the dux or imperator on expeditions and were hand-picked from the senatorial class. They had great experience in the field and possessed exceptional military skill; they could even replace the commander if he was killed.  A consul would have several legati with him, often his friends and family. As aristocrats, legati would also take home a share of the spoils from any campaign. Pompey had fifteen legati accompany him on campaign in Asia Minor. During the Imperial era, the rank ""legatus legionis"" was given to legion commanders selected by the emperor, although with senatorial approval. A ""legatus propraetor"" was a senator or ex-consul acting as a regional governor, and could command several legions at once."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bar_Screaming_Women_Long_Bri">"Celtic women were passionate, unrestrained characters rather like their menfolk. Wearing brightly coloured cloth, jewellery that clattered and chimed as they walked, and sporting elaborately braided hair, all Celts were objects of interest to the Greeks and Romans. Unlike their ""civilized"" counterparts, Celtic women had power and responsibility within their societies, and they were not to be crossed. With a strong sense of personal honour, they would call down the gods' curses and swear vengeance on anyone who wronged them. Boudicca, the queen of the Iceni from eastern Britannia, is the prime example of a woman scorned: her righteous need for revenge following her daughters' rape by Roman troops brought about a revolt that threatened to drive the Romans out of Britain. She destroyed the Roman provincial capital at Camulodunum (Colchester), routed the legion sent to relieve it, and burned London. Roman authority was eventually re-established, but at terrible cost."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Gladiators_Long">Gladiators were usually slaves, condemned criminals or prisoners of war but others did enter the arena. Those with debts or a lust for glory could sell themselves as gladiators, and soldiers who had given ground might be sent to the arena. Their gladiators' trade was arduous and brutal, even before fighting in the games. The ludus, the training ground and home of gladiators, was run by a lanista, and within its walls his word was law. Trainees could, and would, be killed in practice or to encourage other gladiators. Outside, a lanista was the lowest of the low: some Roman cemeteries would not take the body of a lanista. Yet he also had a peculiar glamour as the man who owned and trained gladiators, the sports stars of the Roman world.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Persian_Light_Archers_Long">Very few Persians were professional soldiers and, apart from the earlier elite Achaemenid Immortals and some mercenary hoplites, none were formally trained or drilled. Instead, troops were levied by rich land owners as an obligation during times of war. Levied infantry included slingers, archers and javelin throwers, all wearing little armour but some had shields for protection. As might be expected due to the local terrain, cavalry was an important component in an eastern army, and several types were raised. Lighter cavalry wore iron or bronze scale armour over a tunic; these mounted warriors carried javelins and a sword but had no shield. Horse archers were used to wear down infantry with fast, ruthless attacks. Heavy cavalry included a royal bodyguard. The Parthians, and later the Sassanid Persians, developed all-over horse armour to protect their valued steeds as well as the fearsome cataphract warriors. These were as armoured as any late medieval knight.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Median_Cav_Long">Media, situated in the vulnerable centre of present day Iran, has often been a divided land. Since the time of the Persian empire, during Alexander’s conquests and under the Seleucids empire, Media was continually fought over. In 323BC Media was split into two parts by Alexander: the larger, southern, part went to Peithon, a Macedonian; the smaller northern section went to Atropates. Southern Media eventually became part of the Seleucid Empire and was heavily hellenized, while Atropatene, roughly modern-day Azerbaijan, remained defiantly Persian. Media was eventually conquered by Mithradates I in 141BC, who made it a satrapy once more but this time a Parthian satrapy. The land was renowned for breeding Nisean horses used as mounts in battle and for sacred rituals. The Medians were expert cavalrymen, identified by their distinctive tunics, later adopted by the Persians across their empire. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bac_Scale_Thorax_Hoplites_Long">"Scale armour was common throughout the cultures of the ancient world. As the name suggests, it looked like fish scales, and was made from overlapping rows of small scale-shaped plates, attached to one another or to a backing layer of leather or padding. Scale armour was flexible and relatively easy to produce. Depending on local resources, all kinds of scales were made, including bronze, iron, leather, hide and horn being the most common. Because it was made from smaller pieces woven together, scale armour could be easily repaired. Before the Marian reforms of 104BC, Republican Romans used the ""lorica squamata"", a shirt of metal scales sewn onto a fabric backing. Cavalry also made use of scale armour: Scythian, Sarmatian and Parthian cataphracts were covered from head to toe in scale armour, as were their mounts. "</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ara_Camel_Spear_Long">Camels, both dromedaries and Bactrians, were used by eastern empires of the ancient world. Their pungent natural odour disorientated and frightened horses, and made sure they were valued as light shock cavalry. Over time, their use spread west across northern Africa and, reputedly, there was a detachment in Emperor Claudius’ conquest of far Britannia. Like other light cavalry they carried spears, and sometimes javelins, to harass and chase off enemy light cavalry, infantry and skirmishers. Their real strength came from the qualities of their camels, which allowed them to patrol arid areas. Historically, the first recorded use of camels in battle was between Shalmaneser III of Assyria and the 12 Kings at Qarqar in 853BC. Widespread use does not seem to have begun until much later, as demonstrated by the hasty formation of camel corps by Cyrus the Great for the Battle of Thymbra in 547BC.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Pike_Long">A tightly formed phalanx of sarissa-armed infantry presented an almost impenetrable wall of spear points, especially to cavalry. The sarissa itself was a two-handed spear or pike, between 4-7m long, and was adopted by the armies of Philip II, Alexander the Great, and the Successors that followed them. With an iron tip and a bronze butt-spike, which provided balance and could be dug into the ground to bolster a defensive stance, it was an effective weapon for mass combat. When advancing in close order against the enemy, each man would occupy a square roughly 90cm to a side with the sarissas of the first five ranks projecting beyond the phalanx. On the defensive the phalance would close up, locking together with each man resting his shield on the man in front for greater stability. Such formations sacrificed manoeuvrability, leading to their main weakness on their flanks and rear. Philip II’s employment of the sarissa, and this new Macedonian-style phalanx, developed from earlier hoplite warfare. There is some debate as to whether his wounding by either an Illyrian or Thracian long spear, which killed his mount, may have influenced the sarrisa's introduction.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Car_Sacred_Band_Long">The Sacred Band were a phalanx of veteran spearmen, raised in Carthage, and trained and armoured in Greek hoplite fashion. They were unique in that they were drawn from the populace of the city itself, rather than being allies, levied subject peoples or mercenaries; these were the groups that normally made up Carthaginian armies. Chosen from the nobility and wealthy citizens, they were well trained and disciplined. Thanks to their social status they could afford the full panoply of hoplite armour: a bronze cuirass, greaves and helm, and a hoplon shield. In the case of the Sacred Band these were predominately white in colour. Armed with hoplite spears, tipped with an iron head and bronze butt-spike for balance, members of the Sacred Band also carried straight swords. Renowned for their valour, even in defeat, the Sacred Band was expected to fight to the last, and did so at the Battle of the Crimissus in 340BC. Their numbers never recovered and, in time, the pressure of Carthage’s wars with Rome meant that the Sacred Band was superseded by mercenary armies, paid for by Carthage's trading wealth. These armies still had small numbers of Carthaginian citizens and Liby-Phoenicians, but the Sacred Band of old was no more.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Large_Shield_Warriors_Long">"The thureos, a large oval-shaped shield, became common throughout the Hellenic world from the 3rd Century BC. Made from wood covered in hide, it differed from the earlier Greek hoplon in having a central handgrip, which was protected by a vertical spine running the length of the shield. This in turn could be further reinforced by the addition of a wide metal strip that protected the grip and the user’s hand. Inspired by the sub-rectangular and oval shields of the Celts, possibly through contact with the migrating Galatians, its usage seems to have spread through the Illyrian and Thracian tribes before it was adopted by the Greeks. Although large, the thureos was light in comparison to the traditional hoplon, and was adopted by heavily-armoured peltasts. Named after their shields, these ""thureophoroi"" could fight as common peltasts, skirmishing with javelins, but could also form up with their larger shields and longer spears in a similar fashion to a phalanx. The versatile and useful design of the thureos meant it was used by many armies, including the auxiliaries and cavalry of the later Roman legions."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Savage_Dogs_Long">Dogs have always been useful for guard, patrol and scout work. With skilled handlers they can also be used effectively on the battlefield. Attack dogs were specifically bred and would then be trained to ignore the noise and chaos of combat. Taught to attack on command, they were starved a little, and unleashed on enemies as a savage wave to break their formations. Faced with a pack of foaming, hungry dogs many men would naturally falter, and gaps in a battle line would open that could be exploited by melee troops.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ind_War_Elephants_Long">War elephants had to be trained like men and cavalry horses to endure the noise and chaos of battle. Indian war elephants were larger than their African counterparts and strong enough to carry a “howdah”, or small wooden tower, on their backs. The driver sat astride the beast’s neck while two men, armed with javelins, were in the howdah. The African elephants of the period were a smaller, third species found in northern Africa, and now extinct; they were not the large, intractable wild creatures from sub-Saharan Africa which are familiar to us. The Indian variety first came to the Middle East when Seleucus, one of Alexander the Great’s Successors, invaded India in 305 BC. As part of the peace treaty between the Seleucid dynasty and the Indian Mauryans, 500 war elephants came to the Seleucids. This corps remained an important part of the Seleucids’ army until their defeat by the Romans at Magnesia in 190 BC. The subsequent peace saw the forfeiture of all the elephants to the Romans, and the Seleucids were forbidden from breeding any more.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bar_Screaming_Women_Long_Ger">German women were a warlike lot, and accompanied their men into battle. They tended the wounded, brought supplies forward, and inspired courage in their menfolk: they were a constant reminder of what would be lost if the enemy prevailed. Although without formal positions in Germanic tribal politics, a woman could still inherit the influence of her husband or father, and this influence could be used to take terrible vengeance. Interestingly, the “weregild”, or blood-price paid to the wronged family, for the injury or death of a woman was twice that of a man of equal status. This is surely an indication that women had a high worth within the Germanic tribes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Hellenic_Cataphracts_Long">The Iranians and Persians pioneered armoured cavalry and the Seleucids were the first western, hellenized power to see their merit for battle. Antiochus III, 223-187BC, used cataphracts to great effect at Panium in 200BC. His Egyptian enemies, led by Skopas of Aetolia, placed cavalry on the army's flanks to shield the infantry in the centre. A single charge from Antiochus’ cataphracts entirely scattered the Egyptian horse, exposing the Egyptian infantry's flanks and rear. They were unable to defend themselves against the next mighty charge. The entire Egyptian army broke, and Skopas fled to Sidon. This retreat marked the end of Ptolemaic rule in Judea.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Berserkers_Long">Howling like animals and biting their shields, berserkers took on the appearance of wild animals, entering battle in an almost trance-like state. Worked into a rage before combat, possibly through the use of drugs, they had little protection but were utterly convinced of their invulnerability against fire, blade and indeed any blow that came their way. At the time, berserkers were thought to be shape-shifters that actually became the animals whose skins they wore. Other, more rational views suggested that they were simply carried along by a wave of group euphoria. However, their intended victims did not have the luxury of considering the opponent that stood before them; berserkers fought with a reckless fury, making them very uncompromising opponents to face, and to slay a berserker was thought a most impressive act of courage. One theory behind the appearance of bearskins in the Roman army was the premise that they were trophies, plucked from the corpses of German berserkers and worn by the Romans as symbols of bravery and prestige.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_egyptian_one_halfer">The “one-and-a-half” or “Hemiolia” was a light galley which was much favoured by pirates in the ancient world. It developed from the bireme, a ship that had two full decks of oars along its entire length. The hemiola reduced the number of oars on the upper level, leaving roughly half the number of oars and rowers in the midships section. The smaller number of rowers had little effect on overall speed because the laden weight of the vessel also dropped. Because it used both oars and sails, and the crew could rapidly change propulsion method, it was an ideal vessel for chasing down fat, wealthy merchant vessels. Boarding attacks were mounted from hemiolas; ramming was not a useful tactic as loot ended up with the fish rather than enriching the pirates! The speed and handiness of hemiolias made them useful as scouts, supply boats and vessels used to pick of damaged enemies at the edge of battles.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Aux_Socii_Extraordinarii_Long">These elite soldiers, chosen from amongst the Latin and Italian allies of Rome, were often given dangerous or vital duties to perform. Socii Extraordinarii were composed of roughly the best fifth of the allied infantry, and lead any column on the march, acted as scouts, and occasionally formed a rearguard. The Socii came from the city-states and tribes of the Italian peninsula, groups who were expected to match Rome’s military contribution on any campaign. Those liable for service included Romans that had given up citizenship to live in the colonies, Latin neighbours of Rome, and tribes such as the Etruscans and Samnites. In return for providing half of Rome’s military might, they did not have to pay tributes and received half of any spoils.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Aux_Gre_Rhodian_Slingers_Long">Perhaps not as famous as their counterparts from the Balearics, Rhodian slingers were famed for their skill. As Rhodes was protected by the sea, slingers could hire themselves out as mercenaries across the Mediterranean. They were deadly at 100 metres and could hit targets at 400 metres. Unencumbered by armour, they were highly mobile and could outpace or at least match the pace of most other infantry. Rhodian slingers sometimes made use of small shields with a single handgrip to protect them from any return fire. During the Greco-Persian Wars shaped shot gave the Greek including the Rhodians, an advantage over the Persians. This proved essential in covering the retreat of the Ten Thousand, after Cyrus the Younger’s death at the Battle of Cunaxa in 401BC. The Rhodian slingers were the only missile troops able to engage the enemy with some safety, as Cretan archers and Greek javelinmen had the same range as enemy missile troops.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Short_Swords_Long">These irregular, novice warriors were drawn from among the farmers, hunters and young men of the tribe. They carried Celtic shortswords, which were cutting and hacking blades, unlike the thrusting design of the Roman gladius. The shortsword developed from the earlier Celtic longsword, and was not as expensive to make. With little armour and only a simple shield these irregulars may have been lacking in equipment and skills, but they made up for it by their numbers. Some warriors would also carry javelins or heavy, weighted darts to throw in the last moments before charging into a melee. This gave them uses as both skirmishers and light infantry. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Horse_Skirm_Long">"Cavalry skirmishers relied on the speed of their mounts to close quickly with an enemy, attack, and then withdraw before any counterattack. This was the main role of cavalry in supporting hoplites, harassing enemy phalanxes and skirmishers and only pursuing foes already on the run. Most used javelins, and some attacked using the ""Cantabrian circle"", where riders would circle in front of an enemy, taking it in turns to throw their javelins before galloping to the rear again. A few skirmishing riders carried swords and small shields to use if forced into a melee. Thracian cavalrymen often strapped their crescent-shaped pelte shield to their backs, giving them a little protection when they withdrew, a habit that sensible neighbours would have copied."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_placeholder">placeholder</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Aet_Sword_Short_Long">Although some historians used Aethopia to refer to all of the sub-Saharan regions of Africa, it was commonly used in reference to regions to the south of Egypt that became the kingdom of Kush. Skilled swordsmen from this area, these warriors followed a long tradition of elite troops from the south that begun under the Egyptian and Nubian dynasties. Although they went into battle wearing only simple cloth armour, they did employ Greek thureos-like shields. These sported a central handgrip, and offered greater protection than the hide-bound wicker or wooden shields of the sub-Saharan tribes. They used a form of khopesh-like sword that would eventually evolve into the shotel used by the later warriors of Aksum. This had a forward curving, sickle-like blade designed to reach around an opponent’s shield, either to hook it away or pierce a man's vital organs.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Riders_Hunt_Long">While the Germans relied primarily on the strength of their infantry, some tribes built reputations as skilled horsemen. Notoriously aggressive in their cavalry tactics, they often seized the initiative when faced with greater numbers. Their confidence as riders was also unshakable; turning their back on new technologies and techniques, the Germans notably refused to use the four-horned saddle that had revolutionised the cavalry of their Celtic neighbours. Despite this disadvantage, the Germans were brave enough to face all comers, as Julius Caesar himself described: “In their eyes it is the height of effeminacy and shame to use a saddle, and they do not hesitate to engage the largest force of cavalry riding saddled horses, however small their own numbers may be.”</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Roman_Legionaries_Long">The military reforms of Gaius Marius in 104 BC transformed the Roman army into a professional fighting force. Recruits were no longer required to own land in order to be soldiers: Roman citizenship was enough. Without farms to return to, men were willing to make the army their career, fighting lengthy campaigns in return for the pay, glory and retirement benefits. The legions were equipped at the expense of the state, and each man carried a pilum, a gladius and a large “scutum” shield, emblazoned with their legion’s insignia. Under Marius, men were expected to carry their own equipment, removing the need for large baggage trains manned by non-combatants. Unfortunately, for the men this meant that they were carrying kit that weighed around 45 kilos, earning them the nickname “Marius mules”.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Levy_Freemen_Long">The Celtic client system meant that a “freeman” was given opportunities by the tribal hierarchy. He had to serve the noble classes, but he could also earn prestige in his own right. A freeman inevitably became the follower of an aristocrat, working on the land and raising livestock. However he also had the right to bear arms and fight alongside the nobles during times of war. In combat, a Celt could prove his worth, making a reputation for himself. This system caused an appetite for battle amongst the ambitious lower classes. This did not mean that their armies were ill-disciplined or haphazard: their cavalry would used “trimarcisia”, where each rider went into battle with a pair of freemen servants, ready to supply fresh mounts or replace a warrior who fell.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Numidian_Cav_Long">Numidian tribesmen were raised with horses from an early age, riding bareback without a bridle, and controlling their horses with a stick to tap the beasts between the ears. Numidan cavalry were a supremely agile force who skirmished with assured expertise, swinging around to escape as rapidly as they had arrived. The wore only tunics and carried javelins and small wicker shields. At Cannae, the highpoint of Carthaginian military success, Hannibal’s right wing had 3,500 Numidian cavalrymen. The Numidians attacked the Roman allied cavalry and chased them from the field, then returned to smash into the rear of the Roman lines. Arguably the elite of the Carthaginian army in the Second Punic War, the Numidians' defection before the Battle of Zama arguably led to Scipio’s victory over Hannibal.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bac_Royal_Guard_Long">The royal guard, an phalanx of elite spearmen who protected the kings of Bactria resulted from Alexandrian and eastern influences. They wore bronze armour and Phrygian helmets, but carried smaller shields than was typical among hoplites. They were armed with Greek-style short swords and spears rather than the longer sarissa used by many western states. A halfway point between the phalangite and hoplite-like hypaspists of Alexandrian and later Successor armies, the Bactrian royal guard were used to guard the flanks of sarissa-armed phalanxes. Such elite units were a deliberate echo of Alexander’s patronage and reforms, and marked the move from the citizen-soldier, loyal to the state, to the professional solider, loyal to his paymaster alone.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bri_Druidic_Nobles_Long">"Although the druids are shrouded in mystery, we know that they were a crucial part of Celtic society. They were responsible for the judicial system and religious life of many tribes. Holding a great deal of authority within a tribe, a druid’s judgement in the settling of disputes was widely respected. Druids were not required to fight, but their words instil vigour, vitality and invulnerability before a battle. Believing that the fate of men was directly connected to nature, druids appeased the gods and, according to the Romans, even turned to human sacrifice when necessary. Caesar spoke of ""divine worship, the due performance of sacrifices, private or public, and the interpretation of ritual questions."" Human sacrifices in Britain, usually foreign captives or criminals, were supposedly burnt alive in a giant wooden statue, the wicker man."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Thr_Nobles_Long">There were some forty tribes of Thracians who shared a common language and culture, inhabiting a vast area north of the Greek city-states. They were seen as war-loving, rebellious, rambunctious, bad enemies, and good allies in a fight. Many Greeks dreaded a time when they would be united under a single leader and sweep southwards. Such a turn of events never happened, but Thracians could be found across much of the Greek and Persian world fighting as mercenaries; they often specialised as skirmishers and light troops. At the Battle of Raphia in 217 BC there were Thracians in both opposing armies, ready to do bloody work. The forward curving rhomphaia with its razor-sharp blade and long handle could lop off limbs in the hands of a skilled user, and Thracians were certainly skilled. The most famous Thracian “general” of all never actually fought an action in Thrace or in command of a Thracian army; he was Spartacus, the commander of the last great slave rebellion against Rome in 73-71 BC.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Levy_Pike_Long">Throughout the civilised world, levies formed the backbone of armies. Drawn from the ordinary citizens or subjects, they were in a tradition that, in Greece at least, began with the hoplite warfare of the city-states. What levy pikemen lacked in fighting skills when compared to professionals and mercenaries, they made up for in numbers. Equipped with sarissas, or long pikes, these levy phalanxes were a formidable wall of spear points. Initially, the citizen-levies of Greek city-states were expected to provide their own arms and equipment. As time passed, however, the citizen army developed into a more organised body for which arms and equipment were provided by the state. At the same time, personal loyalty to an individual general or king replaced old-fashioned civic duty.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Ballista_Long">At close targets, a ballista could be aimed effectively but accuracy came at a cost in range; it could fire around 500 metres. The machine used two torsion springs with levers inserted into twisted ropes made from animal sinew, giving incredible power for its size. Firing either solid shot or bolts, it was equally effective against infantry or cavalry, but could also be deployed to destroy light fortifications during sieges. Originally developed by the Greeks around 400 BC, and based on the oversized Oxybeles composite bow, ballistae were widely used by many cultures of the period, including the Romans. Later Roman versions included adjustable caps that enabled crews to quickly alter the tension of each sinew bundle to provide balance and therefore improve accuracy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Evocati_Cohort_Long">After a roman legionary had finished his up to 25 years in the army, he could be asked back to join the Evocati, the ranks of “those who are called”. Usually affiliated to their old commander or re-enlisting at the bequest of a particular consul in times of need, veterans were afforded great respect and honour because of their previous service. As examples to the common soldier, they were often immediately promoted to centurion and given a pay rise. Crucially, veterans were exempt from the mundane and laborious tasks of legionary life such as digging latrines, building roads or making camp. During the civil war all sides called on old soldiers to swell their ranks and provide much needed experience.  Pompey persuading a large number of evocati to join him against Julius Caesar by promising them promotion and more money to return. The veteran Praetorians of the Evocati Augusti were held in especially high regard.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Thureos_Spears_Long">Light Greek infantry, the thureophoroi developed around the early 3rd century BC, and straddled the gap between the phalanx and the skirmishing peltasts. Named after the thureos, their large oval shields, they were more heavily armoured than the traditional Thracian and Greek peltast. Able to both skirmish and form up as a phalanx, they were used to guard the flanks and protect other light troops. Their shield, normally made from wood and covered with leather, had a central handgrip that was protected by a vertical spine and a metal boss-like strip, and may have been inspired by Celtic or Roman shields of the time. Like the longer sarissa, the spears used by the thureophoroi had a weighted butt-spike to provide balance, but this also allowed them to throw javelins, if so equipped, by jamming their spears into the ground. Able to fulfil a variety of roles, thureophoroi were common amongst both citizen and mercenary units of the Greek city-states until they were eclipsed by the Macedonian phalanxes of Phillip II and Alexander the Great.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Aux_Ita_Socii_Equites_Long">The Equites Extraordinarii were drawn from amongst the Socii, allied non-citizens who provided most of the early Republic's cavalry. Up to a third of allied cavalry would be selected to join the Equites Extraordinarii. As there were typically two or three times the number of Socii compared with Roman cavalry, a Consular army of two legions could have some 1,800 Socii cavalry, of which at least 600 would be considered part of the elite Equites Extraordinarii. By tradition, Roman cavalry was habitually deployed on the right flank, while the Equites Extraordinarii were sent to the left. This imbalance was famously exploited by Hannibal at the Battle of Cannae in 216BC, when the Carthaginian cavalry under Hasdrubal routed the Roman cavalry, while the Numidian light cavalry waylaid the allied Socii. Following the Marian reforms, and the Allied Wars of 90-88BC, the Socii and Equites Extraordinarii were reduced to nothing; as full Roman citizens they became part of the legions.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Onager_Long">Named after the wild ass with a dangerous kick, the onager catapult had a mighty kick all of its own, as crews quickly discovered. Although not accurate, it could hurl extremely heavy missiles over significant distances. Its throwing arm was pushed through a twisted bundle of animal sinew, held in a solid wooden frame. Pulled back, the tension in the sinew held an incredible amount of power until the arm snapped forwards and the deadly cargo was launched. The arm smacked into the frame, and it was this impact on every shot that made the entire machine lurch about unpredictably. An area-attack weapon, the onager was best suited to siege work, but it could be fired against tightly packed units of troops as well. The missiles launched could be as varied as rocks, clay pots filled with incendiary mixtures, and even dead bodies to spread disease and despair. Severed heads were gruesomely fired into beseiged towns from time to time, as a warning of what was to come. Easily constructed from timber, the onager was used throughout the ancient world.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Cimmerian_Heavy_Archers_Long">From the same root as the Thracian tribes, but ruled by a military elite of Iranian descent, the Cimmerians founded a kingdom of Greek colonies centred on Panticapaeum. Displaced from the steppes by their Scythian neighbours, some Cimmerians also migrated south of the Black Sea, settling in Cappadocia. Prosperous and wealthy traders, the Hellenistic world turned a blind eye to the Cimmerian tyrant kings, the import of vital wheat, fish and slaves outweighing Greek sensibilities. At their height, around 700BC, the Cimmerians had been mercenary allies of the Assyrians, and their armies had conquered Colchis, Iberia and Phrygia. With the migration of the Scythian tribes the fortunes of their empire dwindled, but their elite warriors continued to be valued as mercenaries. Their style of warfare was a mixture of Thracian, Iranian and Scythian influences, and principally focused on cavalry and chariots.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Noble_Blood_Cav_Long">Like the Companion cavalry of Macedon, these elite horsemen from the lands of Parthia and Pontus were recruited from among the nobility and social elite. Gradually they developed into a permanent and professional bodyguard force. Following both Hellenic and Persian traditions, they were armed with lances and armoured in a similar fashion to their Macedonian companions, but their mounts were armoured in eastern style. This gave their charges extra weight and meant that they were not only a counter to otehr cavalry forces, but could also be sent into the flanks of densely packed infantry. The eastern influence also meant that the nobles were quite at home using the bow, as they had spent their formative years hunting from horseback.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Helot_Javelinmen_Long">An unfree class of non-citizens within Sparta's zone of control, the helots were slaves in most respects. Agricultural labourers, they worked the rich valleys of Eurotas and Pamisos, on which Laconia and Messenia were situated, and were forced to give up half of their produce to the Spartan elite. In addition, helots would also be assigned to Spartan citizens as household servants. Sometimes pressed into service, helots would be employed as peltasts, and in some cases gained their freedom through such service. Following an earthquake in 464BC, which devastated Sparta and possibly claimed as many as 20,000 lives, the helots, mainly from Messenia, revolted alongside the periokoi of Aithaia and Thouria. Cruel and bitter treatment of the helots by their Spartan overlords intensified after this event, and may have led to the tradition of the autumnal krypteia. A declaration of war against the helots made by the ephors, during the krypteia members of the Spartan agoge could prove their skill as warriors. Armed only with a knife, they were expected to live off the land whilst sanctioned to spy on, steal from, and kill the helots. However, this worked both ways, as any young Spartan caught by the helots could be beaten to death for allowing his capture.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Peltasts_Long">These skirmishers were named for their small crescent-shaped leather or wicker shields or “peltai”. It was a common habit to name troops for their shield style in the Greek world. They wore little or no armour and carried three javelins. After harassing the enemy by flinging javelins, they would hastily retreat before any counter-charge or flanking move could be carried out. As armies developed and tactics became more complex, peltasts were expected to take part in hand-to-hand combat: with such expectation they were given stiffened linen cuirasses and short swords. They were still expected to use javelins, but could then join in the close fighting. Eventually, peltasts even exchanged their characteristic shield for the the heavier thureos. Their name and battlefield function remained unchanged.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Spartan_Youths_Long">Toughened by years of training within the agoge, Spartan youths were moulded into warriors from the age of seven, becoming paidiskoi, or Spartan reserves, in their later teenage years. Separated from their mothers, the first stage of their training was the paides, in which they lived communally in one of the Spartan syssitia mess halls. Here they trained and exercised together, learning from their elders, and were purposefully underfed to toughen and accustom them to hunger, and teach them resourcefulness. This extended to depriving them of clothing too, providing only their red cloak each year. This taught the boys to steal, for which they were severely punished if caught, but for being caught, not for stealing from the helot slave population. At eighteen, they became paidiskoi, joining the army as reservists for two years. Armed with the hoplite spear and hoplon, and armoured in cloth, they would support the older Spartan men in battle. A chosen few would also be inducted into the krypteia, a secret organisation that were expected to spy on, steal from and kill the helots. Seen as both a test of ability and a necessary means of keeping the helots submissive, a declaration of war against the helots was made each autumn, effectively legalising the krypteia’s activity.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Guerilla_Warriors_Long">"Rather than face an enemy in battle, where they would likely be outnumbered and defeated, guerrilla warriors carried out hit-and-run attacks, using high ground, sabotage, and ambush techniques to weaken enemy positions. Knowledge of the local terrain is essential in guerrilla warfare. Iberians were certainly well-suited to such tactics, having developed their skills through centuries of inter-tribal feuding. The Greek historian, Diodorus, said the following about Iberian guerrillas: “for those that are young and pressed with want, but yet are strong and courageous, get together upon the tops of the mountains, and furnish themselves with arms; and having made up a considerable body, make incursions into Iberia, and heap up riches by thieving and robbery; and this is their constant practice in despite of all hazard whatsoever; for being lightly armed, and nimble of foot, they are not easily surprised."""</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Onager_Long">One of the simplest forms of one-armed catapult, the onager relied on twisted skeins of animal sinew which provided the power to hurl either rocks or shot. Inaccurate but powerful, it was an effective siege machine against buildings and fortifications, but was of far less use on the battlefield unless firing into massed infantry ranks. First mentioned by Philon of Byzantium in his treatise on ‘Mechanics’, the onager made use of a sling-like cradle attached to a firing arm. This arm was inserted, twisted, and propelled rocks or shot through torsion. As the firing arm was released, the sling-like cradle would unhook, firing the projectile. A padded beam incorporated into the housing frame to restrain the arm. Larger machines could require as many as eight or ten crewmen, and the incredible recoil meant that they could not be easily or safely mounted on walls or towers. Quickly constructed wherever wood was readily available, onager soon became a staple of ancient siege warfare.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Car_Libyan_Javelin_Long">The javelin is among the oldest weapons in human hands. Ancient Greek akontistai, the javelin-armed psiloi, are among the best early examples of javelin-armed troops. Equipped with javelins and little else, they harried enemy javelinmen and peppered hoplite phalanxes, with their javelins before quickly retreating. This was the typical tactic of all unarmoured, javelin-armed troops, to engage at range and then fall back behind more heavily-armoured infantry, or continue attacks while trying to stay just out of reach of the enemy. Such harassment at range could be highly effective, in 391 BC, at the Battle of Lechaeum, a force of Spartans, lacking the support of skirmishers or cavalry, were severely punished by javelin-armed Athenians who refused to meet them at close quarters. Over time, shields became common, such as those used by Thracian and Greek peltasts or Roman velites, and in turn these were rendered obsolescent by the Hellenic thureophoroi and the Marian reforms of the Roman Legion. However, javelinmen and other irregulars continued to play a part in many armies throughout antiquity.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Youths_Long">The role of a skirmisher, lightly-armed and kept from melee combat, was not the part that young German tribesmen aspired to fulfil. Bursting with energy, they craved the glory of one-on-one combat. However, a fledgling tribesman first had to prove his worth before he earned the right to bear arms. If granted such an honour, he hungrily sought battle or risked growing idle. The strongest immediately joined a veteran warrior’s retinue, hoping to earn glory fighting alongside him. Typically, the young occupied themselves with inter-tribal warfare and raiding to prevent loss of fitness. Raiding other tribes was not recognised as a crime, but instead seen as necessary training for the young to nurture and maintain their appetite for battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Youths_Long">A Celtic tribesman reached manhood at 14 years of age and, depending on his status, he could carry arms from then on. Nobles could also recruit their own following, building both reputation and influence through their clients, but first proving your worth in battle was the start. Without bravery in a potential leader no freeman would follow. A man's future, if he lived, was therefore entirely dependent on his showing in battle, and this lead to bravery being a commonplace occurence. Like their elders, Celtic youths were not above goading their opponents with insults and taunts, and they used “carnyx” battle horns to instil fear in their foes. Inexperience, as with all young men, lead them to sometimes act rashly where a little caution might have served them better.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Cantabrian_Cav_Long">A specialist skirmish unit, the Cantabrians rode some of the finest mounts in the Iberian Peninsula. These speedy and dextrous cavalrymen were renowned for their tactical skill, introducing their own distinct attack formation that best exploited their speed and skirmishing. In a “Cantabrian circle”, the riders skilfully created a continually moving circle, making them difficult to target whilst ensuring a continuous shower of javelins rained down on the enemy. Incredibly effective at disrupting infantry lines, slow-moving heavy troops are their most obvious target. Enemies often broke ranks in an attempt to reduce casualties, but that played straight into the hands of the Iberian infantry. Having fallen victim to the Cantabrian circle on many occasions, the Romans later adopted it as a tactic for their own cavalry.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Warriors_Long">While Celts often lacked the formal organisations and tactics of their more “civilised” opponents, they did have extremely able metalworkers, and long experience as mercenaries. In battle, they were not outmatched on an individual level by Romans or Greeks. Celts often favoured the spear in battle. It is a simple weapon, and a typical Celtic warrior might carry several into a fight: lighter javelins to hurl at the enemy on the approach or charge, and sometimes an iron-tipped spear for close combat. Some spears were crafted with barbed tips to cause further damage as they were pulled from wounds. Spears were also convenient for displaying trophies, in the shape of rotting enemy heads. This bloody appearance by the Celts, and a ferocious appetite for battle, was often enough to un-man opponents. Celtic warriors would send a chorus of chants, taunts and insults aimed towards foes, and blow their unearthly-sounding “carnyx” battle horns. The whole display was intended to frighten foes, and put the warriors into the right frame of mind for battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ama_Warriors_Long">"Many myths surround the Amazons, a legendary tribe of hunters and warrior-women, such as the story of Queen Hippolyta's magical girdle that Hercules sought as one of his labours. A female-dominated society, descended from Ares, they were reputed to have lived in Pontus, on the shores of the Black Sea. According to Herodotus, they were killers of men and were a popular source of artistic and poetic inspiration in Greek culture. When necessary they intermingled with the all-male Gargareans, or enslaved what few men they needed in raids and battles. Depicted as superb archers, the Amazons also made use of the spear, axe and a crescent-shaped shield, being in many respects similar to the Goddesses Athena or Artemis. Historically, the ""Amazons"" may have had a basis in truth rather than myth, as archaeology suggests Sarmatian and Scythian women participated in battle, with the Scythians being renowned for their archery."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bri_Chariots_Long">A war chariot was constructed mainly of wicker with iron-rimmed wheels and was drawn by a pair of horses. The main body was suspended from the axle by a rope, giving a rudimentary suspension and allowing it to travel quickly over uneven terrain. Each chariot carried two men, a driver and a warrior.  The driver delivered the fighter into the action and then came back to make a pick-up; the warrior threw javelins and then leapt off to fight in close combat.  Julius Caesar provides the most famous description of chariot warfare as he faced British chariots during his invasion of Britain in 55BC: “…they display in battle the speed of horse, the firmness of infantry; and by daily practice and exercise attain to such expertness that they are accustomed, even on a declining and steep place, to check their horses at full speed, and manage to turn them in an instant and run along the pole, stand on the yoke, and thence betake themselves with the greatest celerity to their chariots again.”</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Agrianian_Axemen_Long">The Agrianes were a Paeonian tribe of fierce fighters. Known for their incredible dexterity and speed, they became an auxiliary infantry unit in the army of Alexander the Great. Carrying a clutch of javelins into battle, the Agrianes were able to move fast and strike hard. They wore little or no armour to hinder them and carried no shield. Alexander employed them time and time again as front line troops in many of his major battles, where they developed into an elite missile assault unit under the command of his general Attalus, proving especially effective in mountainous areas where agility was essential and the phalanx formation proved unwieldy. Carrying axes and knives that could also be used as climbing hooks, the Agrianes were exceptional not only at climbing and traversing difficult terrain, but also when assaulting manmade defences and walls. Fiercely loyal and extremely effective, they were also used to protect siege equipment before joining the crack hypastists for the assault. Alexander rewarded the Agrianes for their service with the right to govern their own lands. Later an elite force of Agrianes fought for Antiochus at Raphia in 217BC against Ptolemy IV.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Scorpion_Long">"The scorpion is a smaller form of the ballista, operating on the same principles of a torsion-powered bow. It was operated by one man, and was incredibly accurate at short ranges. It could be used as a sniper's weapon, but was often deployed for indirect battery fire where the high rate of fire could unleash a withering hail of bolts to completely pepper an area. Scorpions were popular with the Romans, where they were used to support the Legions. Batteries had sixty scorpions, each of which was capable of firing three or four shots per minute. 

Like its larger counterpart, the ballista, the Greeks originally developed the scorpion, but its deadly nature led to rapid adoption by many nations. In most designs, power came from two wooden levers inserted into twisted skeins of animal sinew which, when the arms was pulled back, provided incredible power."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Scorpion_Long">An ancestor of the medieval crossbow, this dart-firing ballista still required a sizable wooden stand and could not easily be moved by its single crewman. It was accurate at short ranges for sniping individuals, but could also be fired indirectly, with groups of several scorpions often deployed to form a battery in the field. Like the ballista, it was an improvement on the earlier gastraphetes, or belly-bow, and utilised either a composite bow or torsion springs to launch both flighted and flightless bolts. Incredibly powerful for its size, the scorpion required the crewman to ratchet back the drawstring with a windlass and lever. Even so, the rate of fire was high, and a skilled operator could loose three to four bolts a minute while firing indirectly. Easy to construct with the right raw materials, the required metal parts could be transported in the baggage so scorpions could be quickly assembled.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Slingers_Long">As far as the Celts were concerned, the best way to kill a man was in hand-to-hand combat. The Celts thought there was great value in personal bravery and there was no honour in killing from a distance. Even so, slingers, javelinmen and archers still had their place on the battlefield. It was often the only way that some Celts could go to war: Celtic warriors paid for their own equipment, so only the wealthy could afford, or had the right to carry, fine armour and weapons. Skirmishers were usually the poor: freemen who served as clients to the noble class. While they could never hope to achieve the same status as their noble masters they could still prove their worth in the cut and thrust of battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Slingers_Long">The German tribesman grew up throwing the stones found on the river beds of northern Europe, giving them a natural advantage when applying the skill to combat. Rocks and stones were in ready supply, so whilst spears may’ve needed repair after a battle, slingers were always well provisioned. Poor men of low status, both in society and, subsequently, in battle, slingers would typically take up position behind veteran warriors, protecting them from enemy attacks. In return, the veterans would use their shields to safeguard those behind them as they unleashed their rain of missiles. Slingshot could be an effective weapon against close enemy formations or cavalry.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Roman_Hastati_Long">"During the 4th Century BC the Romans abandoned the phalanx in favour of an army of hastati, principes and triarii. These were deployed in maniples: compact blocks of men, laid out in a checkerboard formation. This allowed flexibility moving across a battlefield, particularly when compared to a solid phalanx. 

Like most sophisticated city-states in the ancient world, Rome expected its men to fight, and supply their own war gear when they did so. A cynical observer might be tempted to note that the manipular legion also made sure that the hierarchy of Rome was preserved. The youngest and least wealthy became hastati, the first line of battle in a Roman legion. Behind them came the second line of principes, older and richer men, and finally the triarii, the third line of the most experienced warriors. “Going to the triarii” was a Roman saying in all kind of situations, implying that everything else had been tried and found wanting."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Car_Cav_Short_Long">Liby-Phoenicians are the closest Carthaginian society came to an indigenous population, and their numbers were limited following the catastrophic defeat of the Sacred Band in battle against Syracuse in 340BC. Afterwards, Carthage was unwilling to risk many of its own citizens again in a single struggle. This reluctance led to the greater use of mercenaries during the Punic Wars against Rome. However, some Carthaginians were in the field at Cannae, the greatest single Roman defeat of the period. Their trusted commander, Muttines, later betrayed the Sicilian stronghold of Acragas to the Romans following the Carthaginian senate's change of heart towards Hannibal towards the end of the Second Punic War. They withdrew support, fearing his ambitions more than they feared the Romans.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Car_Libyan_Hoplites_Long">Recruited from among descendants of Phoenician settlers and the native Lebu, Garamantian, and Beber peoples of the Sahara these troops were the largest non-mercenary Carthaginian contingent in the army. Colonising the African coast from around the 1st Millennium BC, the Phoenicians founded Carthage and others later known as Leptis Magna, and Sabratha. Important trading centres, they acted alongside Tingis, which was founded by the Carthaginians, and the Greek colony of Cyrene as gateways into Africa and the western Mediterranean. By the 5th century BC however, the three Libyan cities had passed under the control and protection of Carthage and its mercantile dominance. Mixing together a variety of eastern and Saharan customs, and influenced by contact with much of the Mediterranean through their trading network, the Liby-Phoenicians were varied in their style of dress and armament.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Aux_Infantry_Long">"Auxiliaries supplemented the legions of the late Republic and Principate and were recruited from non-citizens, usually provincial volunteers or from allied kingdoms. With the pressures of war requiring increasing numbers, especially in the aftermath of the Social War of 91-88BC, recruitment from Rome’s expanding provinces became a necessity. To limit the risk of rebellion, auxiliary units were recruited from a single province but always stationed far from home. Auxiliaries could be infantry, cavalry or specialists such as archers, and retained their own cultural identities and equipment. Being stationed in Roman provinces, under Roman rule, had an inevitable Romanising effect on auxiliaries, as did the rewards of service: land and citizenship. Some units eventually had ""civium Romanorum"" as a title, meaning they were Roman citizens. From as early as Caesar’s Gallic campaigns auxiliaries accounted for nearly all Roman cavalry, and during the 2nd Century AD, auxillary numbers actually exceeded those of the legions."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Egy_Infantry_Long">Native troops supported the Greek phalanxes of Ptolemaic Egypt. Brave and proud warriors, Egyptians fulfilled several roles, but were most commonly used as peltasts, skirmishers on the flanks of the phalanxes, or as non-phalanx infantry in difficult terrain. Although the Ptolemies adopted all the trappings of the Pharaohs and their religious infrastructure, there was still much unrest among the native population long after the succession. This was due mainly to the way the Greek overlords used the traditions of the Pharaohs to fill their coffers at the expensive of ordinary people. The core of Ptolemaic armies was always Greek until the Battle of Raphia in 217BC, when they faced such a large Seleucid force that Ptolemy IV was forced to muster some 30,000 native Egyptians for the first time. Need overcame suspicion of the disenchanted natives. The performance of the Egyptians in battle eventually led to a greater proportion of native troops in the Egyptian army and, in time, more diverse roles for those men as they gained the trust of their Greek commanders.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Thessalian_Cav_Long">Thessalian horses, Lacedaemonian women and the men who drink from the sacred Arethusa were, according to one oracle cited by Strabo, the three best things in all of Greece. Regardless of whether the last two parts ring true or not, Thessalian heavy cavalry were without doubt a highly disciplined, mobile and esteemed allied unit in Greek and Macedonian armies and were most famously employed by Alexander the Great during his Asian campaigns. Similar in many respects to the hetairoi, the Macedonian companion cavalry, both units used the xyston double-ended lance, but some evidence suggests that at times shorter spears and javelins may also have been used. Their mobility came from the rhombus formation they adopted, reputedly invented by Jason of Pherae, that enabled a unit to turn with cohesion, form up and charge on any of its four points. During Alexander’s campaigns, the contingent of Thessalian Cavalry accompanying him numbered roughly 2,000 men, 200 for every vote Thessaly had in the League of Corinth. They were commonly assigned the left flank, guarding it from enemy cavalry as the right flank spearheaded the attack.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Shield_Bearers_Long">Meaning shield bearer or shield carrier, the Macedonian hypaspist developed out of the foot squires of the Companion cavalry. Rising to prominence under Alexander the Great, these chosen foot soldiers were equipped more like their hoplite predecessors than the new sarissa-armed phalangite infantry of the Macedonian phalanx. Armoured in linothorax, a cuirass of linen reinforced with metal, and a helmet, greaves and the apsis shield, they were more heavily equipped than their phalangite counterparts. Even with the increased weight, the shield bearer’s armament of spears and short kopis swords made them more flexible in battle than the less manoeuvrable phalangite. Because of this they usually guarded the vulnerable flank of such sarissa-armed phalanxes and, as an elite body, held the place of honour on the army’s right flank between the phalangites and the Companion cavalry. Alexander’s hypaspists influenced the adoption of such units by many of his Successors, and their use continued within the Macedonian army for quite some time. Eventually the shield bearer role developed into a rank of lower staff officers spread throughout the army, reporting directly to the king.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Balearic_Slingers_Long">Raised from infancy to perfect their use of the sling, these famed warriors came from the Balearic Islands in the western Mediterranean. It is said that Balearic mothers did not allow their sons to eat until they had knocked their bread off a wall from a fair distance away. The slings they used were made from hair and animal sinew and, as adult warriors, each slinger carried three types for use at different ranges. Many slingers standing together produced a wave of shot that pierced armour and shattered bone, making them deadlier than even the very best archers. In fact, the Roman general Lucius Aemilius Paullus took a mortal wound to the head from slingshot during the opening minutes of the catastrophic Battle of Cannae. Not surprisingly, due to their geographical location, Balearic slingers were much sought after as mercenaries to fight both for and against Rome, and were reportedly paid in women rather than silver or gold!</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ste_Sarmatian_Royal_Lancers_Long">The Sarmatians were a western group of steppe peoples, and occupied the area north of the Black Sea, bordering Dacian and Germanic lands. They roamed this region as they pleased, and had a fierce reputation as cavalrymen almost without equal. They were feared by the Greeks, and often worked as mercenaries or allied themselves to the Dacians. The Sarmatians were always horse archers, but their cavalry gradually adopted heavier and heavier armour as the centuries passed, eventually wearing as much armour as the famed cataphracts of the east. Even the horses wore full suits of scale armour. The riders kept their fearsome bows, even as they became magnificent shock cavalry. With each man carrying a kontos, a long two-handed lance, they could smash through almost any enemy foolish enough to stand against them. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ste_Saka_Noble_Armour_Lancers_Long">The Saka, as they were called by the Persians, were a steppe people who lived and died by their horsemanship. As in all warrior societies, the heaviest armour was reserved for use by the nobility of the tribes, and Saka nobility could be deadly indeed. As a people, they showed little inclination to bow to any outsider. In 512 BC, King Darius the Great attempted to subdue the Saka, and marched into their steppe lands.  It did him little good. The tribes avoided open battle, and raided whenever and wherever they pleased. Alexander the Great, almost two centuries later, eventually lured the Saka into battle at Jaxartes in 329 BC. Even though Alexander won, he recognised that he could not tame them and released all his Saka prisoners in exchange for an oath to end their depredations. The Saka kept their word.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Wodanaz_Spears_Long">Wodanaz is, in many ways, the all-encompassing Germanic god. Worshipped throughout the tribes, known as Odin within Norse mythology and thought to be the equivalent of Mercury from the Roman pantheon, all-powerful Wodanaz inspired German warriors as the bringer of victory. It was he who stood in judgement over a conflict; he who would ultimately decide the victor. Any warrior who fell in battle automatically joined the war god’s own army. Wodanaz also carried a mighty spear, and those men with the strength and status to carry larger thrusting spears fought in his image. A German warrior would routinely call upon the gods in preparation for battle, his shield brought close to the mouth to amplify and deepen the sound, further intimidating the enemy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Galatian_Noblemen_Long">The fierce and proud Galatians dominated central Anatolia and eastern Phrygia. Having splintered from the migrating Celts following Brennus’ invasions of Macedon and Greece in 279BC, three tribes, the Tectosages, Tolistobogii and Trocmi, moved through Thrace and crossed the Bosporus into Asia Minor. They came as allies of Nicomedes of Bithynia and secured a victory for him in a dynastic struggle against his brother. After a brief and inconclusive war between Nicomedes and the Seleucid King, Antiochus, the Galatians settled down to stay. Their territory was split between the three tribes, each maintaining its own capital, but with a council at Drynemeton, a sacred grove of oaks near the Tectosages’ capital at Ancyra. Ruled by a military aristocracy, the Galatians left the indigenous Cappadocian people in control of their own towns and lands in return for tithes. Galatian mercenaries were highly prized and respected by Greek, Roman and Seleucid commanders. In fact, the personal bodyguard of the Ptolemies of Egypt consisted of Celtic mercenaries, and it is highly likely that these men came from Galatia.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Tribal_Slingers_Long">"Slingers were common in ancient armies. Slings are ancient weapons, dating back to Palaeolithic times. In comparison to bows, slings were easy to make and had a greater effective range. 

Constructed from braided flax, hemp or rushes, a sling has a cradle where the shot is placed. One end has a finger-loop, while the other has a knot or strip giving a firm handhold. The slinger sticks his middle finger through the loop and holds the knotted end with his thumb and forefinger. After whirling the shot in the sling it is released with a flick of the wrist. Quick to fire and reload, the sling was widely hated by those on the receiving end. 

Shot varied from stones collected in rivers, to shaped lumps of clay and lead; lead shot could fly over 400 metres. Such missiles were sometimes inscribed with comments such as “Catch!” or “Take that!” All shot was difficult to see in flight, and although they lacked the penetrating power of an arrow they could easily break bone or stave in armour at short ranges. Famously, the Roman Consul Paullus was killed by a slinger early in the disastrous Battle of Cannae. "</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Praetorian_Cav_Long">The word “praetorian” comes from the elite guards of the praetor, the commanding general. Founded in the sixth century BC, the cohors praetoria consisted of the hand-picked infantry or cavalry who guarded their general and his command tent. At first, they were recruited exclusively from among Roman citizens, but later other Latin peoples were allowed to join. The praetorians enjoyed prestigious status in the Roman army and, when Augustus came to power, they were the only soldiers allowed inside Rome. Augustus anticipated that they could be used politically as well as militarily, something of a gamble for the new emperor, as he was keen to assert the republican nature of his regime. Barracked just outside Rome, the praetorians were charged with keeping order during all public events. Later, as the Imperial bodyguard, they served in military campaigns only when the Emperor himself was present. This happened frequently as later emperors emerged from the ranks of the army during the 1st century AD.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Polybolos_Long">The polybolos was a repeating bolt thrower developed from the ballista and scorpion. A chain mechanism drew, loaded and released bolts from a gravity-fed magazine as quickly as a handle could be turned. Supposedly invented by Dionysius of Alexandria, the polybolos was quite a complex machine: as the operator turned a windlass handle, the bow was tensioned as a launching shuttle pulled back, an arrow dropped into place, and finally a catch was released to fire the machine. The process repeated as long as the operator worked. All he needed was a loader to keep the magazine filled. Efficient and deadly, the polybolos had the greatest rate of fire of all ancient war machines.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Lusitani_Nobles_Long">The Lusitani tribe were an Iberian tribe, renowned for producing light, skirmishing warriors. They, along with other Iberians, presented a distinct and unpleasant challenge to Roman arms; Lusitani were even present in Hannibal’s ranks at the Battle of Cannae in 216 BC. During the Roman incursions into Iberia between 155-139 BC the Lusitani resisted, particularly once they had been lied to by, and subsequently suffered a massacre ordered by, Servius Sulpicius Galba, the praetor of Rome’s Iberian forces. He had convinced the Lusitani to give up their arms, and then had them slaughtered by his legions. In seeking revenge the Lusitani fought a bitter guerrilla war against the invaders. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ill_Tribesmen_Long">Although called “Illyrians” by Greeks and Romans, these seafaring people from the Adriatic coast were actually not a single nation or tribe. The Greeks first had dealings with the Illyrian tribe in the Bronze Age, and the name was then applied to everyone in the area. The Illyrians were actually several petty, and no-so-petty, kingdoms and warred with each other when not fighting Greeks or their Macedonian neighbours. The Illyrians could not be lightly dismissed as barbarians: under powerful warlords such as Bardyllis, king of the Dardanians, they conquered Macedon and installed a puppet ruler in 393 BC. It was Phillip II and Alexander the Great who eventually ended Illyrian interference in their affairs. The Illyrians were also pirates, and terrorised the Adriatic for centuries; this was what eventually prompted their subjugation by the Romans. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Tribesmen_Long">Like many warriors, Iberian tribesmen were stubborn beyond all reason in defence of their gods, homes, lands and honour. Even when cornered, surrounded and beyond all hope, defeat was not an idea that could be entertained for a moment. In fact, rather than accept the shame of defeat they were known to kill themselves. Possibly they also hoped to deny the enemy the glory of having killed them. Some warriors went into battle carrying vials of quick-acting poison, carefully extracted from a variety of buttercup. All Strabo, the Greek historian described the poison as “…a herb that is nearly like parsley and painless…”, he was not being terribly accurate. Like all poisons, it hurt, and it caused the user’s face to contort into a horrid, sardonic grin before death came. This morbid, mocking expression unnerved enemies, even Romans, who were convinced that the smiling corpses were mocking their foes from the afterlife.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Scythed_Chariots_Long">Heavy scythed chariots developed during the Greco-Persian Wars as a response to armoured infantry and the phalanx. Although many cultures used them, the original idea was probably Persian or Indian. Others took up the idea, and Mithridates VI of Pontus had some success using scythed chariots against Bithynia during the River Amnias in 89BC, at the start of the First Mithridatic War. They relied on their momentum and axle-mounted blades to break enemy lines, creating weak points to be exploited by cavalry. Even if the chariot horses instinctively veered off at the last moment, the long axle blades would carve an opening. If any still stood, there was a good chance confusion and panic in the survivors would set in. Both the horses and drivers eventually had quite heavy armour, reminiscent of later cataphract cavalry. When fighting against scythed chariots, the simplest to do was open ranks and allow them to pass through, before quickly closing up again. However, the introduction of the long sarissa countered their effectiveness somewhat. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Archers_Long">"Eastern archers can inflict heavy casualties when they are used in large numbers, and their composite bows give them a good range, accuracy and penetrating power. The composite bow is, as the name suggests, made from many materials, and its layers of wood, sinew and animal horn make it a very effective energy-storing ""spring"". In the hands of a reasonable bowman, an arrow from a composite bow would go through chainmail at respectable ranges. It did not, however, take kindly to getting wet. The glues used in its construction soon broke down in damp conditions. In the deserts of the east this was hardly a problem, but it does explain why the composite bow was never adopted in Europe. "</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Garrison_Spear_Long">These spearmen were drawn from the subjects of the eastern regions. they were inexpensive, and simply equipped with a spear, wicker shield and cloth armour. Their shields were oval or rectangular in shape with a central handgrip. While uniformly equipped for the most part, their appearance varied greatly depending where they were recruited, and all kinds of Greek and Persian influences were manifest. In battle, spearmen guarded the flanks of phalanxes, or provided protection for skirmishers and archers. Although ill-equipped to face heavy enemies, their numbers and spears made them an effective counter to unarmoured cavalry. They were also a common type of mercenary and levied unit throughout Asia Minor and the Middle East.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Citizen_Hoplites_Long">Hoplites date back to the wars between the Greek city-states in the 8th and 7th Centuries BC. During the Greco-Persian Wars most hoplites wore a Corinthian-style bronze helm, and a cuirass of bronze or stiffened linen or canvas. They were armed with a short sword and an iron-tipped spear, with a bronze counterbalance butt-spike. They were named, though, after the round hoplon shield they carried. The hoplon-and-spear combination required them to fight as a phalanx, a block of spearmen some eight ranks deep. When closed up, each man would find shelter behind the shield of his neighbour, creating a wall of bristling spear-points. While all hoplites were originally citizen-soldiers, full-time mercenaries took over and became the standard fighting unit of the Greek world. Later, under Phillip II of Macedon and Alexander the Great, the shield became smaller, while the spear developed into the five-metre long sarissa pike. Many armies adopted the phalanx of hoplites as a tactical unit simply because it was very successful in battle.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bac_Hillmen_Long">The Bactrian plain is to the west of the Hindu Kush in what is now Afghanistan. Once part of the Seleucid Empire, around 255BC Bactria declared its independence under the leadership of King Diodotus I after Pharaoh Ptolemy II of Egypt had invaded Seleucid territory. A fertile and developed land, Bactria was prosperous and looked to expand its territory both east and west. The Bactrian kings Demetrius and Eucratides crossed the Hindu Kush and advanced into Asia from 180BC onwards, creating an Indo-Greek Kingdom. This influence resulted in the Bactrians using Indian war elephants in battle. However, the kingdom was fraught with tensions and inner conflicts; instability on its eastern borders and many attacks in the west by the Parthians, Sogdians, Arachotes and others finally destroyed independent Bactria.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Dac_Falxmen_Long">The exact origins of the Dacians are something of a mystery. Dacian lands were centred around the Carpathian Mountains but, unlike their Thracian neighbours, they seldom fought in the fights of others. The Dacians fought almost entirely on foot, and usually looked to their Sarmatian allies when serious cavalry were needed. Many Dacian infantry fought as peltasts, equipped with javelins, short swords and oval shields, but they also fielded archers. However, the Dacians were feared because of a weapon called the falx, which they used with deadly, limb-lopping skill. A two-handed sword with a forward-curving blade, a falx could cut a man in two from the top of his head to his breastbone. This weapon was so effective that the Romans improved their legionary armour to cope with it. The brow-ridge on later legionary helmets was there to stop a blow from a falx. Rome’s eventual victory in the Dacian Wars, in 101-102 and 105-106 AD, was celebrated by Trajan’s Column, finally dealt with the warlike Dacian tribes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Num_Noble_Infantry_Long">Numidia had a fierce warrior tradition, partly because the eastern Massyliis and western Masaesylis had a tradition of bitter feuding and internal warfare. They took, and changed, sides in the Punic Wars to suit their own agenda, and only emerged as a single state after the Battle of Zama in 202 BC. The fall of Carthage allowed the Numidians to expand their lands, and this led to the Jugurthine War of 112-105 BC against Rome. Numidia’s king, Jugurtha, was only defeated when he was betrayed by his father-in-law, Bocchus. While the Numidians were famed as cavalrymen, their infantry forces were also quite effective. The historian Suetonius mentions that there were “Numidian legions”, a term normally used in Roman writings for Roman troops, when passing comment on Julius Caesar’s speech about Juba’s march to aid Scipio before the Battle of Thapsus in 46 BC. This suggests that some Numidians were fighting in Roman style, and were possibly equipped in the same manner. The Numidians also adopted other tactics and war gear, such as the thureos-style shield and hoplite-like spears.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_General_Long">"Rome’s consuls were Republican politicians and generals in equal measure. Every year two consuls were elected by the Senate, each with the power to veto the other, a system designed to stop tyranny and the abuse of power. In civil matters the consuls led the Senate, alternating on a monthly basis. As far as the military was concerned, their powers outside the walls of Rome were absolute when each commanded an army. When a combined consular army was in the field, as at the Battle of Cannae in 216 BC, the consuls Lucius Paullus and Gaius Varro had to alternate command against Hannibal, with disastrous consequences. With absolute power came final responsibility and defeat was entirely the commanding consul’s fault. Punishment could be severe. During the Numantine War, of 154-152 BC, Gaius Mancinus’ apparent cowardice led to the capture of his legions. Although Tiberius Gracchus, then a military tribune, secured their release with treaty, the Senate refused to ratify it and sent Mancinus back to the enemy! Even when successful, a consul was accountable for his actions towards the provinces, allies and resources at his command. When Scipio returned from the Punic Wars, he was hailed as ""imperator"" and granted a triumph and given the honorific title ‘Africanus’, but he was still accused of squandering money by the Senate, at the urging of Cato."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_roman_two">"The waterline ram was first mounted on a vessel in around 850 BC. Warships and naval tactics were transformed. Ships were no longer platforms for infantry battles on the water; the ship itself became the weapon. Galleys changed as the new reality sank in. Ramming at speed would hole and sink an enemy, therefore slimmer, faster, handier ships were required. More speed on demand obviously required more oars a fast ship with a single row of oars ended up being stupidly, impractically long. The solution, then, was to put in a second set of oars above the first, but slightly offset to allow for rowers' benches. These biremes, a Latin word meaning ""two oars"", or dieres, the Greek equivalent, were no longer than previous designs but had twice the number of rowers. They were fast, manouevrable, and could carry a fighting contingent. Some nations also gave their bireme crews firepots; these clay pots filled with oil and pitch were hurled at enemy ships in the entirely reasonable hope of setting them ablaze."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Tribesmen_Long">In his heart of hearts, the German tribesman was a warrior and only a warrior. When a warrior was not fighting, he was seeking out another fight. Only in battle could a man earn glory wealth to improve his place within the tribe. This was not an easy life, and only the toughest lived an idle life away from the battlefield. Others had to work, to toil in the fields and forests, awaiting glory, won in formal battle or on a raid against the tribe's enemies.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Tribesmen_Long">Drawn from a vast area and numerous tribes, the warriors of sub-Saharan Africa were unsuprisingly diverse in appearance and culture. They all possessed long and rich warrior traditions, such as that of the Nubians and their descendants who ruled Kush, and Aksum. Despite tribal differences weapons and equipment differed only in detail: spears, javelins, bows and short swords were favoured. Relatively little armour was worn, but some tribes did employ wicker, wood or hide shields. Adornments and decorations varied greatly and some group sported warpaint. Ethiopians in Persian service were known for painting themselves chalk white on one side and vermillion on the other and using spears and bows of palmwood. Fighting as allies and mercenaries for Carthage, Persia, and the eastern Successors tribesmen tribes could be found throughout Africa and Asia Minor.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Car_Noble_Cav_Long">Carthaginian citizens were rarely called to military service because their armies were mostly legions of mercenaries and levied troops. Only men from the wealthiest and most powerful families, such as Hannibal Barca and his brothers, got the opportunity to serve. The army was, in many ways, their family’s private army rather than belonging to the Carthage. Modelled after Macedon’s revered companion cavalry, the noble horsemen of Carthage were a drilled and disciplined force that rode the finest African and Spanish horses. In the 3rd Century BC they were rightly considered to be amongst some of the finest heavy cavalry in the world.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Elephants_Long">The now-extinct African forest elephants were smaller than the Indian variety. At around 2-2.5m in height, they were an imposing beast capable of causing panic in enemies unused to facing them in battle. Having fought Syracusan elephants in Sicily in 278-6BC, the Carthaginians captured and tamed the local elephants rather than importing larger specimens from India. The Carthaginians did, however, hire Indian experts to form the most powerful elephant corps of the period. At Bagradas River in 255BC, the Carthaginian elephants caused many casualties, leaving the Romans fearful of battling the creatures for many years afterwards.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Camel_Cataphracts_Long">The camel is a curious thing in battle and, when clad in full armour, its strange looks are are much enhanced. Camels are also rather smelly, and this makes horses uneasy unless they are use to the odour. Perhaps not the fastest of creatures, the camel does not charge particularly quickly, but the extra height it gives to its rider makes a lance rather effective. The word “cataphract” derives from two Greek words, “kata”, completely, and “phraktos”, covered or protected. This neatly describes the all-over nature of the armour of both man and camel. Cataphracts were even adopted by the Romans, who used them in their eastern empire as auxiliaries. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Equites_Long">"Recruited from the gentry and lower aristocratic classes of Roman society, the equites were the cavalrymen of the royal and early Republican Roman armies. To be a member of the equestrian class meant that a man was rich enough to keep a horse, and provide his own armour, shield and spear. There were usually some 300 equites in each Republican legion, organised into 10 turmae of 30 horsemen each under the command of three decuriones. One of these men would be the praefectus, or commander, of each turmae. Mostly drawn from the young sons of elite society, these were men keen to show their courage. This was an important step in gaining a political office and prestige for their families. Mundane duties such as patrol or reconnaissance would be the work of the Equites Extraordinarii of the Socii, the Romans’ Italian allies. 

During the Samnite and Punic Wars, the equites’ ranks were opened to first class commoners. Although commoners received none of the equestrians' social and political powers, they replaced the aristocracy in the cavalry, while the equestrians became senior officers in the newer Marian legions."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Bri_Farmers_Long">Although farmers were lightly equipped as warriors, they came from a culture that had a long tradition of heroic warfare, raiding and skirmishing. Armed with spears and javelins, protected by cloth armour and Celtic, sub-rectangular La Tene shields, they made up for a lack of experience with numbers. Their weapons represented what was available to the common farmer, one who also fed his family by hunting. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Cel_Naked_Warriors_Long">A Celtic warrior, with battle-lust in his heart, was an intimidating sight. A warrior who went into battle naked, sure of the protection of his gods, only compounded the unease felt by a foe.  Fighting naked was not a particularly original idea or, indeed, all that silly. It was quite practical, because dirty cloth could be forced into wounds causing all kinds of fatal infections. The Romans assumed it granted greater mobility. Celtic warriors, such as the Gaesatae, embraced the idea of fighting naked with gusto: both the Britons and Gauls were convinced of their own battle prowess. They also had absolute faith in Camulus, the god of war. A blessed warrior simply didn't need clothes.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Longbow_Hunters_Long">The German warrior was exposed on an open, flat battlefield but, when fighting in hills and woodland, he had the advantage. Most were raised as hunters in dense forests, so became expert at stealthy manoeuvres and laying ambush. Whilst their battle tactics were proven, their longbows, often two metres in length and made of yew, lacked the power and accuracy of composite bows made in the east. Their ammunition was also somewhat lacking: limited iron supplies meant these men often fired bone-tipped arrows that struggled to pierce enemy armour. On the battlefield, archers lined up behind slingers, afforded some protection from the shields of the warriors in front of them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Rorarii_Long">“Rem ad Triarios redisse” or “going to the Triarii” was a Latin saying meaning to fight to the bitter end. The veteran triarii were the third line of battle behind the hastati and principes, and only fought when defeat looked likely. However, this saying excludes the supernumerary ranks of the rorarii, who stood even behind the triarii and were, when deployed, the very, very last line of defence. There is much debate over their actual role because historical detail is limited but the rorarii were light infantry armed with spears and shields. They are likely to have been a skirmisher reserve, missile support for the heavier infantry or perhaps rushed to fill any gaps that appeared in the line of triarii. It is thought the rorarii came from the poorest Romans, and were young men of little experience. They may even have been a last remnant of the old Roman phalanx-style army. During the Second Punic War, the rorarii were replaced by velites.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Cappadocian_Cav_Long">Cappadocian horsemen could be found in many armies of Asia Minor, but were most common in the forces of Pontus and Armenia. Although the riders had scale armour and open helmets, so as not to impair their vision, their horses were unarmoured, allowing them a good degree of speed and manouevrability. They were certainly faster across ground than the heavy cataphracts used by eastern armies. These horsemen were most often placed on the flanks of an army to counter any enemy infantry skirmishers or light horse. Charges into spear or pike-armed phalanxes would have been stupid, and fatal. At the Battle of Gaugamela in 331BC, Cappadocian cavalry overwhelmed Alexander’s Asian and Greek mercenary cavalry, only to be halted by the Thessalians.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Archers_Long">Although archery was not highly-thought of as a military skill in Greece, Crete produced truly excellent archers who were able to sell their services to the highest bidder as mercenaries. Firing bronze-tipped arrows from their heavy self bows, Cretan archers tended to carry shields, indicative of some additional prowess in melee, which must’ve made them an even more enticing proposition for a general hiring mercenaries for campaign. Their finest hours came when Alexander the Great hired Cretans directly into his army to support its unbeatable phalanx. Commanded by Clearchus, 500 Cretans accompanied the Macedonian phalanx into battle at Granicus, off-setting the Persian’s numerical superiority on the day and enabling Alexander’s subsequent victory. Whereas the Romans didn’t traditionally use archers in their forces, once they conquered Greece Cretan archers began to appear as auxiliary troops in their armies. Notably, they fought in Caesar’s campaign in Gaul against Vercingetorix, causing him to rally the best archers the tribes could provide to range against them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ste_Archers_Long">Far from being simple, ignorant barbarians the various tribes on the steppes had a rich and vigorous culture. They lived in an area stretching from the Caspian Sea to the northern shores of the Black Sea; the Greeks called them “Scythians”, the Persians “Saka”, while a western group became known as the Sarmatians. Wearing trousers marked them as barbarians as far as the Greeks were concerned, before their tall, pointed caps were even considered. Looks apart, they were all, however, exceptional horsemen, highly skilled with the composite-recurve “Scythian” bow, and deadly close-in fighters. The sagaris was a combined battle-axe and pick that could punch through most armour. Grave goods suggest that their women were as warlike as the men in some tribes, and probably fought in battle. This may well be the origin of the Greek myths of Amazon warrior women. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_greek_two_halfer">It is thought that the Rhodians, a significant naval power in the eastern Mediterranean, developed the “trihemiolia” or “two-and-a-half” as a vessel for pirate hunting. Given the Rhodes is an island entirely reliant on the sea and shipping this is a believable theory. Pirates used the hemiola, a handy little vessel developed from the dieres or bireme, a ship with two rows of oars; it makes sense that pirate hunters would think of taking a trieres, or trireme, with three rows of oars and modifying it in a similar fashion. A trihemiolia still had three rows of oars on each side, but the top row was reduced to only half the number of oars, positioned midships. The result was a faster, handier vessel that provided a height advantage over a hemiola for any archers on board. There was also a strategic benefit to the Rhodians, who could only draw on the manpower of one island: they could have six trieres warships with full complements of rowers, or seven trihemiolias for the same number of men. The useful design was soon adopted by other maritime powers around the Mediterranean.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Velites_Long">Recruited from among Rome's poor and those too young to fight in the ranks as hastati, the velites were the Roman army’s light infantry. They wore wolf skin head-dresses which are thought to have some totemic significance, although they would also scare enemies. At the Battle of Zama (202BC), when Scipio Africanus confronted the Carthaginian general, Hannibal, it was the velites who helped fend off the initial elephant charge. The velites harassed the elephants into a frenzy while the cavalry blew horns to disorient the beasts. Hannibal had hoped to break the Roman lines with his charge; instead many of the frightened elephants turned on his Carthaginians. The elephants who didn’t crash through the Carthaginians were carefully funnelled into gaps in the Roman lines.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_roman_four">There is a good deal of debate as to how large ancient warships worked; the principles are understood, but the details are not always so clear. A Roman “quadreme” or Greek “tetreres” would seem to have four rows of oars if the name is translated literally. However, it is unclear how four sets of oars each with one rower apiece could be used without them getting in a terrible tangle even with a magnificently trained crew, or how the top set of rowers would be able to handle the extremely long oars pitched at a steep angle and still produce any power. The chances are that the term “oar” had become synonymous with “rower” and that the lowest bank had more than one man per oar. The other option was to go back to a double row of oars, with two men apiece. Two banks of oars would also have made for a cheaper construction task for each ship. Either way, the result was a ship that could rival the lighter trireme in speed, yet had more deck space for a large fighting contingent or artillery pieces. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_roman_five">The “five”, called a quinquereme in Latin and a penteres in Greek, was a ship first used by the Syracusans against the Carthaginians sometime around 398 BC. Like other polyremes, a term meaning many-oared, the chances were that it did not have five banks of oars but that the word “oar” was used to mean “rower”. In such a case, the arrangement of rowers would be 2-2-1 going up from the waterline. It makes sense to keep as much weight as possible low in the vessel to help its stability; a high centre of gravity makes any ship liable to capsize if struck from the side. The quinquereme, then, would be a formidable vessel both in terms of appearance and combat value. With a large fighting contingent aboard and plenty of deck space, this heavy vessel could cope with most enemies and threats. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Car_General_Long">Carthage's generals, chosen from the ranks of the nobility, were elected to campaign against Carthage’s enemies. A tribunal of elders, the Hundred and Four, held both civic and military judicial responsibility, and could appoint and punish Carthage’s generals as required. Punishment could take many forms including penance or even crucifixion. Himilco, for example, abandoned his troops at the siege of Syracuse in 397BC. He visited every temple in Carthage dressed as a slave, and then starved himself to death as penance for his crime. Hasdrubal begged for mercy when Rome sacked Carthage in 146BC but his wife, unable to bear the shame, threw herself and their sons into the fires. By way of contrast, Hamilcar and Hannibal, his son, had success and were repeatedly appointed to command during the First and Second Punic Wars. Hannibal reformed the Hundred and Four into an elected body and, even following his voluntary exile to appease Rome in 195BC, continued to be feared by Rome until his death. The Carthaginians were also a little wary of his ambitions for power too.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_roman_six">As centuries passed, naval tactics and needs changed across the Mediterranean. There was a move towards larger ships, partly as an expression of national or dynastic power: the Ptolemaic rulers of Egypt were particularly fond of large ships to show their wealth and influence in a physical way. These “polyremes”, a term meaning many oared, were not suitable for ramming work in battle. In practice many of them had no more oars than smaller ships; what they had were more rowers per oar than smaller ships. A Roman hexareme or Greek hexeres would have a couple of banks of oars with three men per oar, and appear to be an over-sized version of a smaller ship. Even so, thanks to being tremendously heavy and strongly constructed, they were slow moving, and hardly capable of the quick turns needed to take advantage of enemy mistakes. Instead the large ships made use of their wide decks and plentiful carrying capacities and became fighting platforms for infantry and artillery. Boarding or long-range bombardment were the methods to be used to defeat the enemy; naval warfare had come full circle in terms of fighting methods, even if ships had grown significantly.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Eas_Hillmen_Long">Eastern hillmen tended to be light infantry skirmishers that excelled in mountainous and difficult terrain, as a result of defending their homelands against outsiders. Many hill tribes, including the Bithyni after whom Bithynia was named, were descended Thracian migrants who crossed the Bosporus into Asia Minor; each had a fierce attachment to their own lands and a suspicion of plains folk and outlanders. Equipped in much the same manner as peltasts, they carried spears, javelins and daggers and their only protection was a shield, made from wicker, wood or hide. As a fighting force, they were fast moving and extremely manoeuvrable and not above trickery and deceit.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_roman_transport">For most of history the only way to move cargoes and people over long distances at any kind of reasonable speed was by water; this remained true until the invention of the railway. Trading vessels carried goods around the Mediterranean, following the coastlines for the most part, and up navigable rivers. The pattern of Greek settlement and colonisation was almost entirely based on where Greek ships could reach. It was also considerably easier to move armies by sea than march them long distances. Trade ships were hired or requisitioned for such tasks, and this was an added incentive for generals to reach a quick conclusion to a campaign: war hurt trade, and use up ships needed for vital food supplies. </string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ger_Spear_Brothers_Long">"Hardened by years of both inter-tribal combat and contact with enemies further afield, the most talented German warriors thus earned high status within their tribes. Whilst iron supplies were scarce, men of such reputation and standing could equip themselves with lengthy spears, or ""framea"", tipped with narrow, sharp points of iron. Whereas the framea were used for fighting at close quarters, lighter javelins were also carried to be hurled from a distance prior to melee. The taller and stronger the man, the bigger the spear he could carry; this established status, not only within the tribe, but also when facing the enemy. Despite their proven ability, spear brothers relied only on their large shields for protection. Like others in the ancient world, the shield was a treasured possession for the German warrior; those who returned from battle without them were dishonoured. The very best shields were sealed with bronze and covered in leather, doubling as weapons if needs be."</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Afr_Chariot_Raiders_Long">Perhaps influenced by earlier Egyptian and Hittite examples, some kingdoms in Saharan Africa adopted the chariot by the 5th Century BC. Usage was most prevalent amongst the Garamantians, and Herodotus recorded them raiding their southern Ethiopian neighbours using four-horse chariots. Whether drawn by two or four horses, chariot were built for speed and manoeuvrability, rather than impact and protection. They consisted of little more than yoke and a platform with axle and wheels at the back and a waist-high screen. The driver and passengers wore cloth armour and used javelins, and in some cases bows. The emphasis on speed probably comes from the role chariots played in hunting being transferred to the battlefield, especially when raiding for slaves. Despite their weight, when many chariots were drawn up together, their impact against light or untrained infantry and cavalry could still be devastating!</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Spartan_Hoplites_Long">Conditioned from the age of seven for a life on campaign, and dedicated to full-time military training, the Spartans were exceptionally well drilled and masters of their weaponry and equipment. Anyone who lost their shield in battle was dishonoured: while cuirass and helmet were for protecting the individual, the shield was seen as protection for the entire phalanx. As such, the Spartans were a highly disciplined and co-ordinated force, largely superior to any other on the battlefield. It was the Spartans who led the defence of the Peloponnese against the Persians in 480BC and, after two full days of battle, fought the famous last stand at Thermopylae. 300 Spartans and their Greek allies blocked the tiny pass between the cliffs and the sea, forcing the Persians to attack their deadly phalanx head on. When a Greek traitor eventually caused the Spartan position to be outflanked, they fought to the very last man. The time spent defeating the Spartans was just enough for the remaining Greek allies to prepare a fleet to defeat the Persian navy decisively near the island of Salamis, ending the war.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Skirm_Cav_Long">Light Greek cavalry, these skirmishers used javelins to harry other cavalry and infantry, as well as to chase down skirmishers and fleeing troops. Recruited from amongst those citizens able to afford and stable a horse within the Greek city-states, they wore simple cloth armour and either rode bareback or used a saddlecloth-like blanket. Equipped with a supply of javelins and either a dagger or short sword, skirmish cavalry avoided direct confrontation, using their manoeuvrability to prevent heavier cavalry and infantry getting to grips with them. This limited their effectiveness in early Greek warfare to chasing off psiloi and running down fleeing hoplites, but as more cavalry and lighter types of infantry began to develop their usefulness increased. Often deployed to support the weaker left flank in battle, their role became one of misdirection and waylaying, while the traditionally stronger right flank would break the opposing line.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Periokoi_Spears_Long">The ‘dwellers around’, the periokoi were a free, but non-citizen class of Sparta. As the Spartans themselves could pursue no profession other than that of the warrior, the periokoi fulfilled the roles of artisans and merchants in the Lacedaemonian state, eventually taking on the roles in the Spartan army considered unsuitable for true citizens, such as skirmishing and cavalry. Living along the coast and in the many hill towns surrounding the fertile valleys of Eurotas and Pamisos, they acted as a barrier between the Spartan citizens and the rest of Greece. A barrier that also kept in the helots, the Spartans' slaves that farmed the valleys below the city. Like other Greeks, the Periokoi were expected to purchase and maintain their own arms and armour, each town contributing to the Spartan war machine when required. Even though they were allowed their own laws and customs, as non-citizens periokoi could not influence or vote on Spartan foreign or military policy.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ste_Tribesmen_Long">These nomadic tribesmen come from the vast steppes to the north of the Black and Caspian Seas, and were known variously as Scythians or Saka, and later the western Sarmatians. Light infantry, they were often armed with javelins or medium length spears and used shields covered in animal hide. Such shields could also be scaled with either horn or metal. This type of armour also extended to their clothing at times, with scaled versions of their tunics becoming widespread, especially amongst the nobility. These men also made extensive use of daggers, straight swords and the fearsome sagaris, a one-handed battle-axe, with both a bladed or hammer-like head and a pick-like point on the reverse for punching through armour. Complimenting their foot archers and horsemen, the role of such men was simply to protect the former from the latter. Far from barbarians, steppe culture, although nomadic, was a rich and diverse one.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Aux_Afr_Spr_Long">The warriors of the Sabaean region were light infantry, cavalry and archers as mercenaries and auxiliaries for the Roman Empire. Dressed desert fashion, they were entirely familiar with and comfortable in arid places. This was secondary however, to their reputation as mostly reliable fighters, of far more worth than ordinary citizens or levies. This was due to the independence that the Sabaean kingdom maintained from the 8th Century BC to 275AD. This record was based on military might as well as diplomacy and the spice trade including frankincense and myrrh. Never conquered by Rome, Sabaean warriors still found work as mercenaries and auxiliaries in Roman service.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_War_Pig_Long">In battle, pigs were exploited for the panic they caused in elephants. Of the various methods developed to contend with them (skirmishers, fire arrows, ground traps, specialist troops and special formations), the pig was by far the most ingenious method of countering elephants. Elephants simply cannot cope with the high-pitched squeals of a pig. The Romans were quick to realise this and, by covering pigs in thick tar and setting fire to them, made them all the more disturbing. At the Battle of Beneventum in 274 BC, the Romans used pigs against King Pyrrhus of Epirus. The burning pigs ran between the legs of the panicked elephants, who turned in flight and routed through their own army, giving the Romans a momentous, almost effortless, victory.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ste_Lancers_Long">Developed from the cavalry skills of their ancestors, the steppe lancers of the Scythian, or Saka, tribes and the Sarmatians were a type of heavy cavalry comparable to their Hellenic counterparts. They wore scale armour to protect themselves and their mounts, and used a long lance known as a kontos. This enabled them to deliver devastating charges in a fashion comparable to the Alexandrian Companion cavalry. The scale armour was made from horn, or later metal, and allowed the wearers to run down their western counterparts. They were still vulnerable to dense pike or spear-armed formations. Archery provided a solution: sustained volleys from skirmishing foot and horse archers were used to thin and spread out the enemy. At the Battle of Carrhae in 53 BC, the tighly-packed Roman infantry were forced to spread out by Parthian archers, which enabled their cataphracts to charge and break an overconfident Roman force four times their number.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ibe_Painted_Warriors_Long">The Arevaci were a Celtiberian tribe of warriors and horsemen. As a group, the Celtiberians were regarded by their contemporaries as odd to the point of being quite intimidating, if not downright scary. Even among their many bizarre little ways, it was the custom of washing their bodies, hair and teeth in urine that made others think them deranged. The Celtiberians seem to have been convinced of urine’s healing properties. They also went into battle painted orange. The dye paste they used was thought to toughen the skin, but the morale impact on enemies must have been considerable. Other Celts tattooed and painted themselves for battle. Some Britons dyed themselves blue by using an extract of woad; this must have been something of a trial for everyone else, as processing woad to make dye produces a magnificently disgusting smell as well as rich blue colour.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Gre_Foot_Companions_Long">Historically, the Macedonian phalanx innovated the use of the fearsome sarissa: a pike of up to 21 feet in length. First introduced to the army by Alexander the Great’s father, Phillip II, the sarissa was cumbersome but created an almost impregnable phalanx formation. Presenting a wall of pikes from five files of men, it protected more of the front ranks and created a much bigger killing zone than the traditional hoplite phalanx. Defensively, the Macedonian phalanx could not only withstand and repel any cavalry or infantry charge to the front, it could also deflect incoming arrows, as the back rows kept their pikes vertical until needed. Arrows were caught up in the raised pikes and fell harmlessly to the ground, where they could be repurposed by the deadly Cretan archers fielded to support the pikes. Thusly, the Macedonian attack, whilst slow-moving, could also be unstoppable: if coordinated and disciplined, it simply steamrollered its enemies from the field. Following his untimely death, the diadochi - Alexander's successors - continued to use and further refine pike phalanx combat.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Mer_Ger_Scout_Riders_Long">German cavalry were much sought after mercenaries, including by the Romans after the defeat of the Belgic alliance in 57BC. During their attacks into Gaul, the disciplined Nervii cavalry managed to cross the Rhine in a single day, ambushing and defeating the Menapii. Caesar was greatly impressed by their bravery and fighting abilities. He faced the Germans himself at Sabis, and was almost defeated before managing to encircle and destroy them. The remaining Nervii joined the rebellion against Quintus Tullius Cicero, besieging his winter camp until relieved Caesar broke the siege. They Nervii were eventually overwhelmed, but Caesar did recruit a band of German horsemen into his army for his war against the Gauls.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Ind_Armour_Elephants_Long">War elephants were not battle-winning weapons on their own. They needed to be used properly, and given the right support if they were to break an enemy line and the enemy’s will to fight on. They would often be accompanied into battle with a screen of friendly skirmishers. It was their job to keep the elephants from being harassed by the enemy’s light troops, allowing the elephants to attack unmolested. The sheer size of an elephant was enough to instil terror, before its tusks impaled men, or it hurled enemies away or trampled them to death. Even in the best conditions, elephants could be unpredictable: they could react with anger if their handlers were killed or wounded, but they could also turn on the same men when they had reached breaking point. Sent forwards at the right moment, though, and they could sweep all before them.</string>
<string name="unit_description_historical_texts_text_Rom_Vigiles_Long">Vigiles were stationed around Rome and were responsible for dealing with any unrest that occurred after dark. Keeping the peace was just one part of their work as they also acted as Rome’s fire department. They were equipped with pumps to douse small fires, but a blaze could spread quickly through tight-packed streets, so often buildings were torn down to make fire breaks. Vigiles did this with impressive speed, and men were specially trained to remove roofs and knock down walls. In extreme cases they used onagers to knock down buildings in a matter of seconds.</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>