<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resource>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_8">"Consul Laenas died of his wounds on the third night after battle. His body, washed and anointed, has been sent to Rome, attended by his surviving guardsmen. He died a true Roman.

It took two days to clear the last of the bodies from the streets, so great was the slaughter. The citizens of Capua have opened their houses and shared what little grain remains. Our Lucanian allies have returned to their homeland to the south, the Samnite threat as great to them as it is to us. Our debt to them is immeasurable.
What fate has befallen Consul Rutilus we cannot know. For now we sit and wait for the enemy to attack once more. I fear that Capua cannot sustain another assault."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_0">"a.d. Nonae April, the year of the consulship of Sp. Nautius Rutilus and M. Popillius Laenas.

The war with Samnium continues into another year. Three weeks have passed since a consular army marched from Rome passing the outpost that I, Gaius Fulvius Silanus, command.
Grave news has been received from the front, for this army has met with heavy defeat. Consul Rutilus is taken hostage and Consul Laenas has retreated to Capua, which now faces a Samnite siege. An urgent call to respond to Laenas's plight has been sounded."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_30">The Invasion of Samnium</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_33">The Battle of Malventum</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_39">The Battle of Buxentum</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_25">The Battle of Salernum</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_21">The Aftermath of Vesuvius</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_17">The Battle of Vesuvius</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_50">The Battle of Aternum</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_51">The Battle of Bovianum</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_45">The Battle of Lucera</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_39">"The engineers have spent weeks constructing seagoing vessels along the shore in Campania, with yet more being commandeered locally. Many Lucanian exiles have volunteered their services, including some with knowledge of the coastline, so the advantage will surely be ours once battle is joined.
We put to sea yesterday after the wind turned, having been unfavourable to our cause for many days. Contact has been made with several coastal settlements near to our target. Rejoicing in our arrival, the villagers report that the enemy have mounted few defences facing the water. Nevertheless I have ordered us to anchor and rest, so we may enter battle tomorrow at full strength."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_33">"I am well, and so is the army. For a week now we have climbed through open farming country into more mountaineous, pastoral lands. The villages we find are already deserted, the natives having retreating with their livestock. Supply is not a problem however, as our baggage train carries a grain surplus and our riders ensure the road back to Campania remains clear.
We are coming upon Malventum and will be in sight of the town within a day. A hunting party from this ancient city has been contacted and put to flight, doing little more than throwing missiles and insults. The defenders know that we come."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_30">"The population of Salernum came out of their houses and cheered our troops after the resolution of battle. So heady was the strength of feeling against the enemy that the remaining Samnite settlers were compelled to seal themselves in the town hall for fear of their safety. Amid the excitement, a fire took hold in which a number of the Samnites perished; the remainder being pulled from the building and beaten by the townsfolk.
I have been recalled once more to the capital. Salernum's capture has opened up routes to the sea and into the hinterlands for Rome. I will stress the importance of retaining this vital intersection to the Senate."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_25">"I have observed a spring in the step of every soldier since our enemy was driven from Roman soil. Yet the Samnites, a people native  to the mountains, still occupy lands on the coast that were once allied to Rome. We must now march to reclaim them.
My guard and I passed through Capua five days ago. Repairs to the city are still ongoing, but great cheer was roused from the populace by our arrival and we were greeted by a feast. A shrine was erected to the fallen city defenders before our departure the next day.
The Samnites seem content to sit in the town and let us advance. Perhaps they lack inspiration, perhaps they plan a ruse. We will find out soon enough."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_21">"I may be a low-ranking commander, but the force and fury with which the Samnite army was vanquished at Vesuvius was a shock and delight to me. There is more vigour and cheer about the camp than ever before. You can see it in the eyes of every man: they know they have the beating of any Samnite army.
I must leave them now, for I have been summoned to Rome. It has been a busy few weeks and it somehow sits wrong to leave the front line. The immediate threat is quelled, however. Roman lands should be safe for now."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_17">"I have been appointed Propraetor for the coming battle. It is a great honour, no Silanus has ever served the Republic as high. My focus remains devoted to the task at hand.
The army has made camp at the foot of the great mountain Vesuvius. The priests have been conducting prayers to ensure the favour of Jupiter and divine the health of Consul Rutilus. From these heights we can guard the pass into the Campanian plain.
A foraging party has already skirmished with scouts from the Samnite army. Our camp has not been found, but the enemy will reach us soon."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_50">"We lay siege to the Gallic stronghold at Aternum. It is clear their troops lack confidence in their ability to face us. On successive nights we have caught bands of deserters attempting to escape through the hills surrounding the town. A few were interrogated, the bodies of the rest left out in view of the defenders.
A day has passed since a Gallic representation came to seek terms. Their party refused to disarm in my presence, however, and were barred from approaching. Weapons were drawn in the confusion and a son of the chieftain was slain, along with two others of their party.
I tire of the distraction these Gauls present from our campaign against the Samnite capital. They shall be driven from Aternum in Rutilus' name, and never again will Italy be stained by their presence."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_51">"The army has arrived at the gate of the enemy capital, Bovianum, the seat of all Samnite power. Both sides know that its fall would mean nothing less than Samnium's total subjection to Rome, and the end of the war. Despite their fatigued state the men strain at the leash, urging rash attacks on the city's formidable walls. I will have them torn down, but at a time of my choosing.
The defenders taunt us from the walls as to the fate of Rutilus. One party threw down a javelin on which a head was impaled. This was quickly retrieved, although those who know the consul say that it is not him. Hope remains that he can be found and that Rome can unite behind a common leader once more.
This will be my final entry before the assault. My veterans assemble in battle formation and await my command. The resistance will be desperate, but with divine favour I am confident we shall win a glorious victory. For Rutilus! For Rome!"</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_main_text_45">"The army is far from home and we are compelled to live off the land as best we can. Our foraging parties are raiding local townships but news of our arrival precedes us. The enemy slash their crops and move their grain away by wagon. Our soldiers intercepted one convoy and such was their strength of feeling at the shortage of supplies that the wagon drivers were cut down to the last man. Word has been sent to local communities that such will be the price of their defiance of Rome.
For three days now a sickness has spread through the camp, striking down dozens of men, including a legatus. Nevertheless we come across Lucera, sat on the plains of the Dauni. Our attack will be swift, all the better to reinvigorate the army."</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_0">The Siege of Capua</string>
<string name="prologue_loading_screens_title_8">The Defence of Campania</string>
<string name="nothing_nothing">nothing_nothing</string>
</resource>